<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
 
<<<<<<< ab5e6c99ebf65ed6cd1cf3f50b0789a835f1269f
 <title>a b/og</title>
 <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com"/>
 <updated>2016-07-05T14:13:36+01:00</updated>
 <id>http://richardlitt.github.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Richard Littauer</name>
   <email>richard@burntfen.com</email>
=======
 <title>Litt Up</title>
 <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com"/>
 <updated>2012-04-08T22:37:34+02:00</updated>
 <id>http://richardlitt.github.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Richard Littauer</name>
   <email>richard.littauer@gmail.com</email>
>>>>>>> New
 </author>

 
 <entry>
<<<<<<< ab5e6c99ebf65ed6cd1cf3f50b0789a835f1269f
   <title>Books I read in 2015</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-12-29/books-i-read-in-2015"/>
   <updated>2015-12-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-12-29/books-i-read-in-2015</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I read a lot of this books. This year was no exception. Not including a few books which I gave away and can’t remember reading, and a few books that I read on my computer (mostly code books), here is my list of books I read this year, in alphabetical order by first author. I love talking about books; if you’ve read any of these, &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#114;&amp;#105;&amp;#099;&amp;#104;&amp;#097;&amp;#114;&amp;#100;&amp;#064;&amp;#098;&amp;#117;&amp;#114;&amp;#110;&amp;#116;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#110;&amp;#046;&amp;#099;&amp;#111;&amp;#109;&quot;&gt;drop me a line&lt;/a&gt; and let’s chat! I’ve bolded the ones I found particularly good.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The most influential books I read this year were: &lt;em&gt;My Struggle&lt;/em&gt; by Karl-Ove Knausgård, and &lt;em&gt;Of Walking in Ice&lt;/em&gt; by Werner Herzog. They’ve redefined what I thought was possible with writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amanda Palmer - The Art of Asking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Amy Tan - World on Fire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Andy Weir - The Martian&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill Waterson - Calvin and Hobbes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill Waterson - Scientific Progress Goes Boink!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill Waterson - Something Under the Bed is Drooling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill Waterson - Weirdos from Another Planet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill Waterson - Yukon Ho!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brandon Sanderson - Mistborn&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brandon Sanderson - The Hero of Ages&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Brandon Sanderson - The Well of Ascension&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brandon Sanderson - The Way of Kings&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Brandon Sanderson - Words of Radiance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;David Deida - The Way of the Superior Man&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Troupes - Parsimony&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Troupes - Renaming of the Birds&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;David Troupes - The Simple Men&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Democracy, A Very Short Introduction&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Donald Hall - Essays After Eighty&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Douglas Adams - The Hitchhikers Guide to the Galaxy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elie Wiesel - Night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elizabeth Speare - The Sign of the Beaver&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frank Herbert - Dune Messiah&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gary Snyder - The Back Country&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gary Snyder - This Present Moment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gary Synder - Riprap &amp;amp; Cold Mountain Poems&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Gene Wolfe - A Cabin on the Coast&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - The Ziggurat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Haruki Murakami - What I Talk About When I Talk About Running&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hermann Hesse - Siddhartha&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;James C. Richards - Better is Better&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;James D. Watson - Avoid Boring People&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Josh Waitzkin - The Art of Learning&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JRR Tolkien - The Book of Lost Tales 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JRR Tolkien - The Book of Lost Tales 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;JRR Tolkien - The Fall of Arthur&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JRR Tolkien - The Hobbit&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;JRR Tolkien - The Lord of the Rings&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karl Ove Knausgård - My Struggle, vol. 1&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Karl Ove Knausgård - My Struggle, vol. 2&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Karuho Shiina - Kimi no todoke&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ken Follett - The Pillars of the Earth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Kenji Yoshino - A Thousand Times More Fair&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leo Babauta - Zen to Done&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Leo Tolstoy - What Men Live By&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mark Salzman - Iron and Silk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Matthew Inman - How to Tell If Your Cat Is Plotting to Kill You&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neil Gaimain - American Gods&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Neil Gaiman - The Ocean at the End of the Lane&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pablo Neruda - The Sea and the Bells&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Pablo Neruda - Twenty Love Poems and a Song of Despair&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Rothfuss - The Name of the Wind&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Patrick Rothfuss - The Wise Man’s Fear&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ray Bradbury - Fahrenheit 451&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Raymond Fiest - Magician: Apprentice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rebecca West - The Return of the Soldier&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Robert Pirsig - Zen and the Art of Motorcycle Maintenance&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robin Hobb - Assassin’s Apprentice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robin Hobb - Assassin’s Quest&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robin Hobb - Royal Assassin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robin Sloan - Mr Penumbras 24 Hour Bookshop&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ryan North - Poor Yorick&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ryan North - To Be or Not To Be&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seth Grahame-Smith - Abraham Lincoln: Vampire Hunter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Seth Grahame-Smith - Pride, Prejudice, and Zombies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Terry Pratchett - Making Money&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Thomas Aquinas - On Being and Essence&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;To-ru Zekuu - Shiki Tsukai&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Ursula le Guin - Searoad&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Various - As You Were, Punx Comics&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Walter Isaacson - Benjamin Franklin&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Werner Herzog - Of Walking in Ice&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;WB Yeats - The Tower&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;William Carlos Williams - Selected Poems&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The user has sobered up</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-11-29/the-user-has-sobered-up"/>
   <updated>2015-11-29T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-11-29/the-user-has-sobered-up</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tuid-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;Cover&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Roughly six months ago, I had a fun idea for a website that I fully expected would be a joke, that I would share with a few of my friends, and that would promptly be forgotten by the Internet. I had just joined &lt;a href=&quot;http://hackerparadise.org/&quot;&gt;Hacker Paradise&lt;/a&gt; in Bali. I needed a project for a hackathon during my first week there, so I decided to build out my idea. I made a basic website, didn’t think too much about the style or the wording, and launched it that afternoon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea was simple: I would get drunk, and review your website in the process. I would look for bugs, dark UX patterns, poor copy, and evaluate the site as a whole. The domain name said it all: &lt;a href=&quot;http://theuserisdrunk.com/&quot;&gt;TheUserIsDrunk.com&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The site went wildly viral. Within an hour, I was at the top of Hacker News. I had just under 100,000 hits on the first day. Within a week, I had around 300k hits. I was interviewed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.fastcodesign.com/3044455/reviewing-ux-designs-while-drunk-makes-way-more-sense-than-you-think&quot;&gt;FastCo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://tech.co/heres-why-its-important-to-design-like-the-user-is-drunk-2015-03&quot;&gt;Tech.co&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://gizmodo.com/i-paid-a-ux-expert-100-to-get-drunk-and-evaluate-gizmo-1693902126&quot;&gt;Gizmodo&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://vwo.com/blog/drunk-review-worlds-easiest-ab-testing-tool/&quot;&gt;VWO&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://blog.hubspot.com/marketing/hubspot-website-review-userisdrunk&quot;&gt;Hubspot&lt;/a&gt;. And, almost immediately, the orders started coming in. I raised my price from $50 to $500, sure that at some point, people would stop buying. They didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I am announcing that I am closing it to open orders.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post, I’d like to share my process and my favorite parts of the entire experience; what drinking professionally is like; serious questions I have about privilege; why I feel it is time for me to close the site; and what’s next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;evaluating-ux-while-drunk&quot;&gt;Evaluating UX While Drunk&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The User Is Drunk provided a service that wasn’t actually as straightforward as it seems. I wasn’t really a “user”, a naïve person you’d pay on fiverr.com or a friend you’d ask to check out your beta site. I’m a full-stack developer with experience evaluating UX/UI for websites, mostly ones I was building as part of teams in New York and San Francisco. The site could easily have been marketed as “The independent UX reviewer is drunk,” with the following line saying: “I’ll get drunk and give you advice that I could have given you sober about your UX, pretending I am a normal user, but I’ll mess some stuff up.” The service could have also been touted as “Richard will get drunk and try to have as good a time as possible while straddling the line between comedian commentator and astute observer.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to be clear, “The User Is Drunk” wasn’t an entirely novel idea. There was another guy who had come up with the same idea before: &lt;a href=&quot;http://willdayble.com/&quot;&gt;Will Dayble&lt;/a&gt;. I had doubtlessly heard of the phrase from him, although I didn’t know the provenance of the idea at the time and thought it was just a standard idea used in the industry. That probably says more about my absentmindedness than about the state of UX as an evolving discipline. There’s a few reasons why drunk users are interesting, from a UX perspective. I could list them all here, but Austin Knight of Hubspot wrote an &lt;a href=&quot;http://austinknight.com/writing/ux-insights-from-a-drunk-guy/&quot;&gt;absolutely fantastic article&lt;/a&gt; about drunk user testing, based on my service, that says it much more eloquently than I ever could.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My process reviewing sites went something like this. I would have a few drinks, always with friends. At some point during the evening, I would wander away for twenty minutes and launch up my computer. I would generally spend around ten minutes on a site — sometimes, I spent as long as twenty minutes, sometimes as short as five. I used a Trello board to organize everything. I used &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screenmailer.com/&quot;&gt;ScreenMailer&lt;/a&gt; to take videos, although for some special instances I used QuickTime to record mobile reviews. Afterwards, I would give the video to a writer friend of mine, &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidfolgeryoung.com/&quot;&gt;David Young&lt;/a&gt;, who would type up my rants in a nicely formatted PDF (originally designed by &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/u/5da5f67aece&quot;&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt;) that I would then send to the customer. David was an absolute champ, and every dollar I spent on his copy editing was 100% worth it. He’s listened to hours of me talking incoherently, and somehow made sense of it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the end, what I would send to the client was a PDF with a list of things I had noticed in the site — bugs, dark patterns, bad copy, etc. — and a list of things that they could instantly do to improve their site. I also attached a screenshot of the video and a link to the video of me going over their site. If they liked it and said yes, I would put a link to their video on my website. At the moment, there are 36 videos up. I probably reviewed somewhere around 50 different sites, all told. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The actual videos were the main deliverable. Sometimes, they were really useful to the client. I identified bugs, found parts of their website they didn’t know existed, and pointed out where copy could be better. I got great feedback, and occasionally I would get repeated clients. Sometimes, the videos were useful for other reasons — for instance, they wanted exposure. I’m fairly certain Mathbreakers.com had no idea how much traffic they would get from my site as my first client (tons). For a lot of buyers, the entire point was just to see what I would make of their site, because they thought I was a pretty funny guy when I was drunk. And, sometimes, my reviews were completely useless to everyone involved. I’ll talk more about that later. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;what-drinking-professionally&quot;&gt;What Drinking Professionally&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Means Living in Bali and Thailand, getting drunk wasn’t expensive, difficult, or out of the ordinary. I was traveling with 30~ friends, and on any given night some of them were up for hanging out. Many even seemed to enjoy watching me go away for ten minutes in the middle of a beer to record myself stumbling my way through someone’s website. I made a deal with my friends, as I didn’t want to drink alone: if I was reviewing a site, I would buy everyone drinks. All that I asked of them was that they, you know, hang out with me. Most of them thought this was hilarious, and were more than happy to oblige. There was always someone up for a drink. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I first posted the site on Hacker News, one comment, quickly upvoted, was this: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Alcoholism is sad. :(&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The comment was later deleted after a barrage of HN commenters stated this wasn’t alcoholism, let the kid have a good time (something I’m not sure I agree with). I wish the commenter had left it up. Although it may seem strange, it was this comment that, for the first time, made me take a step back and think honestly about what I was doing. Remember, I hadn’t thought that the idea would go viral, at all. I did it as a joke. Now, all of the sudden, I was &lt;em&gt;contractually&lt;/em&gt; obliged to drink. And I was known for it. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I quickly did a few things. First, I added a huge disclaimer to the website. Then, I made it clear that I would be responsible about drinking times, and I gave no assurances to any customers that I would do their reviews by X date. A few people did email me asking when their review was coming; in those cases, I would generally just move them up in the queue. This took a lot of pressure off of me to drink. Still, for the first month or so, I was essentially drinking every few days. I would suggest that absolutely no one do this, for any reason. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m naturally a lightweight. At the beginning of this venture, I would get drunk on two beers. I’m not even joking. My friends suggested at times that I just pretend I was drunk. I never did, because it didn’t take much for me to become inebriated and stay that way, and because it felt disingenuous. I had routines to ensure that I was still at peak performance the next day, because I hate hangovers and I like working. My main routine involved big breakfasts of greasy, non-sugary Indonesian food, lots of coffee, and long distance running. If you ever suspect you may be hung-over the next day, I highly suggest running five miles before dawn on only a few hours sleep. You’ll sweat out the alcohol, stay fit, and the pain of the first few miles will rapidly give way to a fantastic, natural endorphin high. Make sure you stay hydrated. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(I don’t want to get too sidetracked, but running is the best. I can’t possibly explain how beautiful it is to run through Indonesian rice paddies in tropical heat, or on Thai beaches before dawn with shrimp boats and lightning storms on the horizon and ghost crabs flirting with the waves next to you. Drinking is pathetic in comparison, but running doesn’t pay my bills.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a couple of months, my tolerance level rose through the roof, and my routines were less effective. I dealt with this by only “working” once a week, if that, and I stopped drinking casually. Luckily, my price level was high enough that by this point I was mostly out of clients. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In July, I moved to Boston. This was my first time living in my native New England in ten years, and my social group was radically different — mostly, I was hanging out with my cousins, not digital nomads. Since I was spending more time with my family, this also meant I was much less likely to get drunk often. Pretty soon, I found that I had difficulties finding anyone who wanted to have a few drinks on any given night, which meant I had to plan events as far as a few weeks away. This was a lot better for me physically, but made the entire thing much less of a side project and much more of a job. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If drinking is your job,  you swiftly realize how miserable drinking is. For one: alcohol is a depressant, and always trying to stay in a good mood is tiring. Sometimes my comments on people’s websites weren’t intellectually useful or comedic, often because I wasn’t in a good place that night. On one occasion, I think I sang for a couple of minutes in the middle of the review. I’m not proud of that. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alcohol is also expensive, in terms of both time and money. For me, this was especially pertinent. Sometimes I would review the wrong site, and I had to do a site over. Most of the time, my clients thought this was hilarious, especially after I sent an email saying that was part of the problem of streamlining my process. How do you make a drunk person more efficient, anyway? Sometimes they didn’t find it all that funny — I was, after all, paid to provide a valuable service. The amount of time I spent on a site also varied, as it depended upon my ability to find things to comment on — this wasn’t always easy — and how tired and / or bored I was. If I could stand here and honestly tell you that I found a way to standardize how drunk I was or what mood I was in, I’d be either a liar or not a human (approach with caution). I didn’t. That’s part of what drinking means. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alcohol obscures judgment. Sometimes my comments were idiotic. Sometimes I think I was downright mean as a reviewer. I’ve since dedicated a lot of time towards reading articles and learning how to give constructive and not destructive criticism. This is very hard, and I hope I’ve gotten better at it. Alcohol can also, besides obvious liver damage, lead to dangerous situations. Thankfully, I don’t think anyone was ever physically hurt by The User (as my friends called me sometimes), but there were a few bicycle rides I probably wouldn’t do again if asked. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;checking-my-privilege&quot;&gt;Checking My Privilege&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things I noticed early on when tweeting about The User Is Drunk was that very few of my good friends were interested, and very few members of the Javascript community I consider myself a part of talked to me about it. Instead, there was this big area of silence. Initially, I figured this was because The User wasn’t dealing with javascript, node, or similar coding things. A good deal of thought later, I realized I was guilty of something else: flaunting my privilege. Very few people called me out on it; I wish more people had. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Imagine if I weren’t a white heterosexual-looking cis-male. Would The User Is Drunk have gotten anywhere near the amount of press it got if I were an African-American man? If I were a woman? What if I was both? What if I was from Indonesia, like the majority of people I saw daily when this started, and not an educated, upper-middle-class kid from Connecticut? &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These sentences are questions because I don’t have answers to them. I do know that I  would not have gotten the same amount of press, at all, if I was a member of a minority; if it had, I think the comment sections would have been filled with slander and ignorant statements. We’ve all seen these, so I don’t need to give you some potential examples here. My being a white dude made it that much easier for people to share and laugh about my website. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the months went on, I found myself asking more questions. For instance, what if it was more obvious that I am not heterosexual, but openly queer? Does my sexuality even matter here? Does the fact that I founded this while backpacking around Southeast Asia flaunt how mobile and independent I am, and how I am a product of a capitalist, warmongering, and colonial empire (looking at you, America)? Am I complicit in that legacy?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The worst question, that came soon and which I mentioned above, was this one: what if I was actually an alcoholic? I started to wonder if I was being ableist by doing something that many people cannot — drinking excessively. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am one of those strange kids who remembers the first time I had a drink. It was at 3:33pm on my birthday, 18 years exactly since I was born, because I wanted to only drink when it was legal to do so. I had a Guiness, hated it, got drunk for the first time that night, and hated that too. I can count the amount of times I got drunk my first year of university (7), I think largely because drinking had a huge stigma for me because of how sheltered I was raised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(Note: I do not think that I am an alcoholic, and I am more than happy to sit down and talk seriously with you about this if you feel I need to. Please get in touch. I’m listening.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Raising these questions amongst my friends, many of them tell me that I am “being too hard on myself”, or “thinking too much.” But by not answering these questions on my website, by not drawing attention to them, I was enforcing the status quo of “It’s OK to drink and laugh about drinking, as long as you’re a white bro.” I also bought into drinking culture, and in particular, drinking tech culture, as a thing that is OK. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; ok. Being able to enjoy alcohol with your coworkers or community isn’t a given, it’s a privilege, and not everyone is afforded it, subscribes to it, likes it, or has the option. I know people who didn’t mesh well with a team because they didn’t drink, and I know people who felt excluded at tech conferences because they didn’t drink. I know young people who can’t enjoy conferences because there’s alcohol there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know people who struggle with drinking. Alcoholism is real, and it is ugly, pernicious, and brutal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to sideline my privilege. I added a few lines to my website. I told myself, “Sure — but you are, in fact, a healthy, able, twenty-six year old tech male who can do this. So why don’t you? Have some fun. Live your life. Recognize who you are, but don’t apologize for it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m still debating whether that was the right thing to do. I have friends who are firmly in the “No, it wasn’t OK” category, and friends who definitively aren’t. Disagreements make us human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m raising these questions here because I think they are important to talk about, to mention, not because I have answers, and not because I feel like raising these questions alone will absolve me of any guilt or damage I may have caused. The only thing I can do is recognize my privilege and check it. I dropped that ball in some ways here. I wish I was alone in this. I’m not. As a culture, tech is extraordinarily bad at not dropping that ball. The only thing we can do to get better, as a culture, is to recognize and check our privileges. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of you might know that I launched &lt;a href=&quot;http://theuserismymom.com/&quot;&gt;TheUserIsMyMom.com&lt;/a&gt; shortly afterwards, with my friend Scotty Allen and his mom, Pam. While not a great commercial success, The User Is My Mom also got significant amounts of traffic, and was seen on Motherboard, Wired, and CNBC. There are very similar questions we could raise about whether it is ableist or sexist. In both cases, I personally would emphatically say no, because Pam wanted to do it herself, and that’s her choice. But the way we phrased it might have been better, and I’m not sure that riding on the controversy wave, as I certainly did, is the best move. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-best-parts&quot;&gt;The Best Parts&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The last few minutes of reading have probably not been fun reading (they weren’t fun to write). I don’t want to give the wrong impression about it was like doing The User Is Drunk, on a daily level. For the most part, it was a very enjoyable experience. I had a great time. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the coolest bits was that I would meet people, someone would bring up TheUserIsDrunk.com, and I’d hear a lot of “Oh, that was you!?” This happens pretty regularly, and is, in a “yeah, that was me, no big deal” kind of way, pretty damn satisfying. I’d also see references around the web now and then, like this quote at the top of Designer News:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/dn-news.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;DN News&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My favorite review I did, hands down, was &lt;a href=&quot;http://jeffreypicard.com&quot;&gt;jeffreypicard.com&lt;/a&gt;. Jeff is my favorite person. His website had no CSS, and he paid because he wanted to see what I would do. I laughed so hard. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screenmailer.com/v/sXyhHiYTcauAQqI&quot;&gt;Here is my review&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other notable highlights include &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screenmailer.com/v/aqUEFaIwIjbFGME&quot;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt; for meh.com, where I bought a dog toy for a dog I don’t have; &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screenmailer.com/v/MacCNd8UnNtlqx4&quot;&gt;my review&lt;/a&gt; of weeklyfilet.com, where I liked the product so much that I mentioned that David Bauer and I should be friends (we since are on Facebook and Twitter, much to my amusement); and my review of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.screenmailer.com/v/tmtT6Yyf7UagZ7w&quot;&gt;drsquatch.com&lt;/a&gt;, which was memorable mainly because their site is great, and because their product is great. They sent me some soap that smells absolutely amazing — like, seriously, stop what you’re doing and go buy their soap. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also had an absolutely great time with BREWPUBLIK, my sponsors. BREWPUBLIK is an awesome company in North Carolina that delivers hand-picked brews to your door. I went down and visited them a bit ago, and they’re a great team and they work so hard. I really can’t praise them enough (they’re not paying me to say this here, either). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;why-i-am-closing-it&quot;&gt;Why I Am Closing It&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I covered most of the reasons I am shutting down The User Is Drunk above, but I wanted to recap a few of them here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s not that it isn’t profitable, or can’t be made profitable, or that it can’t scale. I’ve thought about all of these things, and there’s definitely a sustainable business model to be made out of drunk reviews. The User Is Drunk also helped me get out of immediate credit card debt, something I am incredibly happy about, and for the first time in my life, I have savings. That’s really cool. So, finances and declining demand for drunk reviews isn’t why I am writing this post. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mainly, I don’t want to drink professionally any more. I’m not in the same community I was in when I started, and I don’t like asking my friends to drink with me while I have financial benefit in mind. Call me crazy, and several of my friends have (especially those who say, “Just split the profits with us. We’re cool with that.” Of course you are, you nincompoops.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also would like to be able to say that I gave value to every single person I worked with. I don’t think this is true, and I don’t think it would be true going forward. I don’t want to just give people a product — I want to make everyone I know be AWESOME. All of the time. That’s what I want to be like as a person. The User Is Drunk was a fun experiment, but I don’t think it was an entirely successful one; there were times I let clients down, times that I never got a return email after sending the video, and some bridges I feel I may have burned. I hate burning bridges, and I hate letting people down in any way. Since I can’t standardize how I drink and how much value I give to people while drunk, I am going to try my hand at something else. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whats-next&quot;&gt;What’s Next&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now that I no longer do drunk reviews regularly, as of writing this post, I am going to try and focus on giving better sober ones. If you need any UX/UI appraisals, do let me know. I’m available for hire. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You may have noticed, above, that I said “regularly” and “closing it to open orders”. What this means is that if you &lt;em&gt;really&lt;/em&gt; want to have a drunk Richard video —email me. I won’t do sites for any paying customer anymore, but if I like your site, and I think I can honestly help you out and help make your website AWESOME — well, maybe I’ll see if I can give you some comments after the occasional night out. This should help me quality control both my life and my product better, which will make me — and you — happier. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For now, I am going to focus more on open-source projects. I’m still working on &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BeagleLab/beagle/&quot;&gt;Beagle&lt;/a&gt;, a Chrome extension PDF and HTML annotator I’ve been building with the MIT Media Lab to help make science better. I also want to work more on &lt;a href=&quot;https://ipfs.io/&quot;&gt;IPFS.io&lt;/a&gt;, the distributed web that I think may seriously change how we use the Internet. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also want to write better fantasy literature, climb bigger mountains, see more art, run a marathon, volunteer to help more people, and enjoy both what a late night with a book feels like, and what the early morning looks like with a clear mind. If you’re interested in following me on this journey, and learning about what projects I have and what I’m thinking about — I’ve got a new tiny letter here: &lt;a href=&quot;https://tinyletter.com/richlitt&quot;&gt;https://tinyletter.com/richlitt&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s to the future. Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to amend a commit on a GitHub Pull Request</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-10-30/how-to-amend-a-commit-on-a-github-pull-request"/>
   <updated>2015-10-30T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-10-30/how-to-amend-a-commit-on-a-github-pull-request</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;so-you-need-to-change-your-commit&quot;&gt;So you need to change your commit&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are your options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add another commit on this branch and then push to this branch.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Manually fix your changes, amend, and force push.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Add another commit, and then squash commits.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interactively checkout the previous commit, remove lines that aren’t wanted, stage, amend, and force push.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Interactively rebase.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Close this PR, commit again on a new branch, open another PR.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wait for someone else to do this for you, and then have them credit you.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make sure you’re on your branch, and currently pointing to the commit that was used to make this PR.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-1-add-another-commit-and-push-to-your-pr-branch&quot;&gt;Option 1: Add another commit and push to your PR branch&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is normally the thing to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ echo &#39;these are some edits&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; your_file.md  
$ git commit -m &#39;Edits are the best&#39;  
$ git push origin HEAD  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this does is provide you with a very clear history of what was committed where, and anyone can see this in the PR and in the future history of the project if it is merged in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, for things like spelling edits, line removals, or general small nitpicky things that the maintainers want you to do, having an extra commit may not be the best option. Some repositories like to have a very clear history, where each commit shows something meaningful that happened. A second commit removing a space, added by accident in the previous commit, isn’t really useful for anyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;(On a side note: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push&lt;/code&gt; is enough if you’re on newer git versions and the remote matches local. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push origin HEAD&lt;/code&gt; is just longhand for pushing to whatever branch you’re currently on. If you’re using a different naming scheme for &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;origin&lt;/code&gt; and &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;upstream&lt;/code&gt;, you will need to update that accordingly, of course.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-2-manually-add-changes-amend-and-force-push&quot;&gt;Option 2: Manually add changes, amend, and force push&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where force pushing comes in. While most git guides tell you that “Force pushing is the worst thing in the world, and it makes you a Sith Lord if you use them, and we will find you and hunt you down”, really, it makes sense in situations where a commit on a non-merged PR should be changed. No one is going to be touching that PR, so you don’t have to worry about dirtying past history. The only person likely to be touching that branch will be you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A lot of people complain that then the comments made by the maintainers will be lost. Technically, they are saved on GitHub in outdated diffs, if anyone wants to see them, although they won’t be in the git history itself (which makes them less accessible and useful). But, more relevantly, they often aren’t that important. Is it important that a maintainer told you to remove a trailing space? I don’t think so. Most maintainers I know would agree with me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, you can manually change your file.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ vi your_file.md  
# Do the edits you need to, here, and then type `:wq`.  
# There&#39;s no reason you can&#39;t use your usual editor to edit the file.  
$ git add -A  
$ git commit --amend  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You see that we added the edits to git’s staging area, with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git add -A&lt;/code&gt;. (If you ever want to know what a git command flag means, type the equivalent of &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;man git-add&lt;/code&gt;. The git manuals aren’t really all that bad.) Then, we typed &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit --amend&lt;/code&gt;. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--amend&lt;/code&gt; is your friend - it lets you change a commit by adding to it, editing the commit message, or even doing things like changing who made the commit and when it was committed. This only changes things locally, which means you have to be careful about pushing elsewhere or expecting anyone else to have your changes. But don’t worry - git will warn you if you try to run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push origin HEAD&lt;/code&gt; at any point, as it knows that the commit has been changed, and you should know what you’re doing before pushing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--amend&lt;/code&gt; opens up the interactive commit message environment you are used to from &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit&lt;/code&gt;. Change the message as you see fit; you’ll see your edits are now actually part of the commit, too. When you save (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;:wq&lt;/code&gt; again), it will register that a new commit has been logged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now comes the part you normally shouldn’t do, but since the maintainers have asked you, and since you know it is to your own branch, and since you’re not too worried about being a Sith lord: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git push -f origin HEAD&lt;/code&gt;. This will tell git to not care that this is a different commit. Git will overwrite the remote commit with your commit, and now you’ll see that the PR has also automatically been updated on GitHub. The old comments telling you to change stuff are now in an outdated diff, the code shows the most recent version, and you’re ready to merge. Everyone wins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-3-committing-and-squashing&quot;&gt;Option 3: Committing and squashing&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option you can do, which is a bit more standard and which you may be used to, is to edit your file, and then make a new commit. You can even make as many commits as you like, really. However - like we said earlier, some maintainers want a clean history. You can clean up your history by squashing commits, and then force pushing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ echo &#39;1&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; your_file.md  
$ git add -A &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit -m &#39;init&#39;  
$ echo &#39;2&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; your_file.md  
$ git add -A &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit -m &#39;1&#39;  
$ echo &#39;3&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; your_file.md  
$ git add -A &amp;amp;&amp;amp; git commit -m &#39;2&#39;  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What you’ve just done here is made three commits, with three changes. But say you only want the initial commit to be logged, but you want all of the changes in the subsequent two? So, you want one commit for this final file:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ cat your_file.md  
1  
2  
3  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is easy. What you need to do is to find the SHA for the commit you want. Type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git log&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git log  
commit a64e0ba789c7d6a38190a87cf073de83f9e74e65  
Author: Richard Littauer &amp;lt;richard.littauer@gmail.com&amp;gt;  
Date:   Fri Oct 30 13:01:26 2015 -0400  
  
    2  
  
commit b55c3647991830ba50c12b3755ab00c8c537caab    
Author: Richard Littauer &amp;lt;richard.littauer@gmail.com&amp;gt;  
Date:   Fri Oct 30 13:01:24 2015 -0400  
  
    1  
  
commit 7bedf0d423deb3e7e81fc3ba980a92252b684a83  
Author: Richard Littauer &amp;lt;richard.littauer@gmail.com&amp;gt;  
Date:   Fri Oct 30 13:01:24 2015 -0400  
  
    init  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copy the final commit SHA. As with all git SHAs, you can actually just copy the first 6 letters. Then, type this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git squash 7bedf0  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this will do is squash your commits down to the commit &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;7bedf0&lt;/code&gt;, but keep all of the subsequent changes (in the staging area). Let’s take a look:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git log  
commit 7bedf0d423deb3e7e81fc3ba980a92252b684a83  
Author: Richard Littauer &amp;lt;richard.littauer@gmail.com&amp;gt;  
Date:   Fri Oct 30 13:01:24 2015 -0400  
  
    init  
$ cat your_file.md   
1  
2  
3  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sweet! You now have one commit, but &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;your_file.md&lt;/code&gt; looks like you want it to. However, if we run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git diff --cached&lt;/code&gt;, we can see the staged edits:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git diff --cached  
diff --git a/your_file.md b/your_file.md  
index d00491f..01e79c3 100644  
--- a/your_file.md  
+++ b/your_file.md  
@@ -1 +1,3 @@  
 1  
+2  
+3  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looks like the changes in the second two commits are staged, but not committed. Well, now we just do &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit --amend&lt;/code&gt;, save, and then force push. Easy as pie.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But what if you don’t want to edit your file manually, like we did in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;vi your_file.md&lt;/code&gt;? Say there are a lot of small changes you have to make, or it’s just tedious work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-4-interactively-checkout-and-amend&quot;&gt;Option 4: Interactively checkout and amend&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, here you can do some cool stuff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout -p HEAD~1  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What this does is to compare your current commit (your &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HEAD&lt;/code&gt;) to your last commit (&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;HEAD~1&lt;/code&gt;). It diffs the two commits, and adds the previous commits lines which are different, removing lines from your current commit. This is like applying the inverse of your current commit. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-p&lt;/code&gt; means patch, and it interactively selects hunks from the diff. This is useful, because it means you can choose which lines you want to keep, and which you don’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When you type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git checkout -p HEAD~1&lt;/code&gt;, it will give you an option for each hunk in the file. This looks like this: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Apply this hunk to index and worktree [y,n,q,a,d,/,e,?]?&lt;/code&gt;. I would suggest pressing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;e&lt;/code&gt;, which opens up your editor. There, it gives you these options:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;  8 # To remove &#39;-&#39; lines, make them &#39; &#39; lines (context).  
  9 # To remove &#39;+&#39; lines, delete them.  
 10 # Lines starting with # will be removed.  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you would like a line to stay in your commit, replace the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-&lt;/code&gt; in front of it with a space. If you would like a line that was deleted to be removed, simply delete it (in vi, you can do this by typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;dd&lt;/code&gt; while on that line). This might take a bit of mental work to get used to, as removing a line while checking out a previous commit is the same as effectively keeping the line in the current commit. If you ever have any difficulty, you can restart the process by doing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git reset --hard&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once you have removed the lines which you wanted to - say, for instance, lines which where you had accidentally changed a word - add the new changes to the staging area by typing &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git add -A&lt;/code&gt;. Then, commit them using the amend function we mentioned prior, and finally, force push them. It might be smart to look at the commit diff from the previous commit before force pushing: do this by diffing the two commits with &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git diff HEAD~1..&lt;/code&gt;. Then:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt; $ git add -A  
 $ git commit --amend  
 $ git push -f origin HEAD  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you don’t want the commit command to open up the editor because you’re not changing anything, you can also use &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git commit --amend --no-edit&lt;/code&gt;, but that’s a bit more dangerous.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-5-interactively-rebase&quot;&gt;Option 5: Interactively Rebase&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another option is to interactively rebase. Normally, you’ll want to do this if the branch you forked off of has changed, and you’re being asked to update your commit, especially if there are changes. Rebasing is a bit more complicated, and I think you’d appreciate graphs for this, so take a look at &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.atlassian.com/git/tutorials/rewriting-history/git-rebase-i&quot;&gt;this short post&lt;/a&gt; on it. A good way to think of rebasing is as a merge and a squash, rolled into one, while also using the hunk methods we saw in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;git checkout -p&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you have conflicts, this might get a bit hairy. That’s OK though! Everything will eventually be alright. I’m not going to go into how to do this here, because I think the post above does it very clearly. Feel free to message me if you would like me to fill this out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-6-open-a-new-pr&quot;&gt;Option 6: Open a new PR&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is frowned upon by most maintainers, because it creates more work for the maintainer, and quickly leads to a lot of random PRs being opened for what might have been a very simple problem. This is also work for you. You need to delete your old branch, close the PR, edit your commit manually in whatever way you see fit, and then push to a new branch, and reopen the PR. That’s a lot of effort.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;This should be your last resort&lt;/strong&gt; - only do this if the maintainer of the repository says it is OK. An example of where this might happen is if the PR has moved away significantly from the original solution it provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;option-7-wait-for-someone-else-to-help&quot;&gt;Option 7: Wait for someone else to help&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, for some fixes, maintainers can help you, too. This often happens when a maintainer wants to close a PR, but there’s a small thing that needs to be changed, and the original filer of the PR has moved to Ethiopia. What a maintainer can do in these situations is this: they checkout your branch, and pull down your changes onto your local machine. Then, they manually edit the file, and edit your commit message, amending it, before merging it into their up-to-date main branch and pushing. This will make the PR look like it has a conflict, but your code and your attribution will still be in the git history for that repository. Sometimes, people do this and then let you know in the PR comment thread by saying &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Landed in &amp;lt;commit_sha&amp;gt;&lt;/code&gt;, where the commit_sha is the merge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git checkout -b your-username-master master  
$ git pull https://github.com/your-username/repo.git master  
$ echo &#39;This PR needs this line&#39; &amp;gt;&amp;gt; your_file.md  
$ git commit --amend --no-edit  
$ git checkout master  
$ git merge your-username-master  
$ git push origin master  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing maintainers can do is to actually add content in a new commit, and then make it look like you made it. They can do this by using this command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;$ git commit --amend --author \&quot;Your Name &amp;lt;your_email@email_provider.com&amp;gt;\&quot;  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Don’t worry - it’ll say on GitHub and in the commit, when they push, that they pushed a commit that you made, so in a sense, you are dual attributors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you got this far, though, it’s likely they didn’t need to do that, and that you were able to fix your PR yourself. I hope so!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let me know if any of this is confusing. I’m happy to edit it and make things more clear, or to fix the inevitable errors I made describing this process.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>How to create a literary press</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-10-15/how-to-create-a-literary-press"/>
   <updated>2015-10-15T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-10-15/how-to-create-a-literary-press</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I just published an article on Medium, &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@richlitt/how-to-start-a-literary-press-2ecdf0c92b6b&quot;&gt;How To Start A Literary Press&lt;/a&gt;, about my experience setting up &lt;a href=&quot;http://wordhoardpress.com&quot;&gt;Word Hoard Press&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I like Medium’s formatting better than this, my own blog, so go read it there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Follow &lt;a href=&quot;http://twitter.com/wordhoardpress&quot;&gt;@WordHoardPress&lt;/a&gt;, too!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On not doing a project</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-05-31/on-not-doing-a-project"/>
   <updated>2015-05-31T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-05-31/on-not-doing-a-project</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been thinking about building a site for coworking for many years. I’m not alone in this; there are many communities and websites building sites for digital nomads and itinerant workers in various cities, such as &lt;a href=&quot;https://workfrom.co/&quot;&gt;Work From&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://digitalnomadslife.com/&quot;&gt;Digital Nomads Life&lt;/a&gt;. More recently, after having visited half a dozen coworking spaces in South East Asia, I’ve been considering building a site for coworking spaces in particular: not for cafes, or restaurants, or libraries that are good for working in, but for coworking spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coworking spaces offer more than cafes. They often have more reliable internet, better facilities, and most importantly, they have other people you can interact with. I’m not just talking about mixers after work; just talking around the coffee pot on a break can be a useful experience, especially for solo nomads who need more interaction with their peers than they get in their work, especially if you &lt;a href=&quot;http://hoppycow.com/2014/12/13/working-remotely-for-extroverts/&quot;&gt;are an extrovert&lt;/a&gt;. A site dedicated towards finding the best and most productive places could potentially be a useful list for people not sure of where to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue, and the reason I am going to not make this project, is that there isn’t enough value in such a list. People normally don’t choose their locations based on the coworking spots (although I do, but I suspect I’m alone in that). They choose based on where they want to go. Once they are there, they scope out the best places to work. Trying to direct people towards certain coworking spots goes against this grain.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The other problem is that people don’t tend to google to find good spaces. They use Yelp, or Trip Advisor, or they go on NomadList or Hashtag Nomads and search there. They ask their friends and nomads who have been around longer. This is easier, more effective, and provides more relevant feedback for any given parameter. I don’t see how a website would make this any easier.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some pain points aren’t actually pain points. I constantly think that this might be one for me - it isn’t. I would like to know where the best coworking spots are in the world, but I’m not desperate about it and I’m not concerned about being able to find them. The pain is just a momentary wish that I knew more than I do, which is easily fixed by five minutes of googling. Finally, curating a website of coworking spots doesn’t really interest me. I’d like to go to those places, but taking photos, getting reviews, testing the internet; I’m not sure if I have the time or interest to do all of these things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why am I writing this? Well, one of the hallmarks of success is being able to choose projects wisely. This means rejecting projects that are suboptimal. I’ve thought about this one for a long time, dedicating many hours to it, and the above is my rationale for saying no. So this is my goodbye to that project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;See you at the coworking space, where I’ll be working on something else.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hosting NodeSchool in Bali and Chiang Mai</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-05-03/hosting-nodeschool-in-bali-and-chiang-mai"/>
   <updated>2015-05-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-05-03/hosting-nodeschool-in-bali-and-chiang-mai</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I co-organized the first NodeSchool event in Bali, and organized the first event in Chiang Mai. Here’s a write up of how they went.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;what-is-nodeschool&quot;&gt;What is NodeSchool?&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://nodeschool.io/&quot;&gt;NodeSchool&lt;/a&gt; is an open source community who build tutorials to help people learn how to use Node.js and javascript. NodeSchool chapters are groups of people in various cities who throw events where local coders come together to do the tutorials at once. It’s like a conference, but no one is talking, people are actually coding, and there’s a lot less pressure to be a good coder and much more pressure to hang out and have fun learning something new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I helped organize a NodeSchool in San Francisco in March, and mentored a workshop that was basically a one-off NodeSchool event as part of NodeSummit there. When I left San Francisco to go travel around South East Asia for a while, I figured I’d see if anyone was up for throwing some more NodeSchools where I was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bali&quot;&gt;Bali&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at the &lt;a href=&quot;http://nodeschool.io/chapters.html&quot;&gt;NodeSchool chapters&lt;/a&gt;, and no one had ever thrown any events in Bali before. In Bali, a website had been started by a guy called Eric, but there weren’t any specific plans or date. I messaged him on the GitHub repository for Bali, and we decided to have one.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>100 Days of Code</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-04-30/100-days-of-code"/>
   <updated>2015-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-04-30/100-days-of-code</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve published an article on my 100 days of coding streak.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@richlitt/100-days-of-code-5e9a4dc6d56b&quot;&gt;Article on Medium&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Removing local npm modules from your development workflow</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-04-26/removing-local-modules-from-your-dev-workflow"/>
   <updated>2015-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-04-26/removing-local-modules-from-your-dev-workflow</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;While building &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BeagleLab/beagle&quot;&gt;beagle&lt;/a&gt;, I’ve tried to modularize as much as possible. Beagle is a Chrome extension, using browserify and React, that injects a sidebar into any page or PDF on the web. We also rerender PDFs using &lt;a href=&quot;https://mozilla.github.io/pdf.js/&quot;&gt;PDF.js&lt;/a&gt;, and add in the sidebar to the native PDF.js viewer. Beagle is an annotation tool; one of the goals of the product is to be able to eventually build a web portal for anyone to see annotations without having downloaded the Chrome extension, which would mean loading PDFs on our own website. Because of this, I knew fairly early on that some of the styles would be specific to the Chrome extension, and some specific to the website. So, I decided to make a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beagle-style&lt;/code&gt; module, to factor out the styles for the extension. I also factored out the code that deals with the PDFjs api into a module, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beagle-pdf&lt;/code&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a smart move at the time, but it has become increasingly clear that there must be a better way. What this did was require every developer working on the platform to symlink two other git repositories into their &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; folder. I made a shell script to help do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;script src=&quot;https://gist.github.com/RichardLitt/d668e99f9566dcf386fb.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sure, this is one way to do it. But this means requiring every developer to run this symlink, which is a major barrier to installaton and debugging for people who aren’t interested in the entire app, but just want to test it. Further, this goes against the idea of modularity. If I have to have two connected modules, at all times, and they can’t be unplugged - than why am I making two modules at all?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first inkling that I could change this came when I considered &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beagle-pdf&lt;/code&gt;. That module is basically a wrapper around PDF.js, so that I have specific methods I can call that do things with the PDF.js api such as highlight text. At the moment, that module is stable, and works pretty well independantly of the Beagle core. As this is the case, there’s no reason to not publish it and remove the dev environment. If I want to change it live, I can edit the module installed in &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;node_modules&lt;/code&gt; directly, and copy those changes over to another repository, commit, push, and publish them. That’s one removed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beagle-style&lt;/code&gt; is a bit more complex - these styles are hypothetically modular so that the sidebar can be separated from the future web instance. But I’m using React - which means that each component can actually have it’s own styles injected in the React component itself, without having to use an external CSS file. This makes my life a lot easier, too, as I don’t need to require and inject entire CSS files. Further, the web instance shouldn’t look different than the Sidebar, and if it is different, the CSS should reflect that directly where it happens - in the component.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we can take that out too. For now, I’ve published the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;beagle-style&lt;/code&gt; module, but I expect to complete remove it of all of its CSS at some point soon as I work the CSS into the React components. What this means is that now users can clone my repository and just run &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;npm install&lt;/code&gt; and everything works. This is a much easier workflow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And now that that barrier is lowered, hopefully it will be easier for other devs to work on the project. When in doubt, refactor, minimize, and remove barriers to entry.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Build smaller, help more</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-04-14/build-smaller-help-more"/>
   <updated>2015-04-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-04-14/build-smaller-help-more</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;This post was also published &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/@richlitt/build-smaller-help-more-7101d9933b4f&quot;&gt;on Medium&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I left San Francisco, I saw some graffiti in the Mission which said ‘There are no local tech workers.’ As a web developer, I resonated with that; I often feel disconnected from my community, as I build things for a global audience. I’m also a digital nomad. I haven’t lived anywhere longer than a year for the past decade. It’s hard to feel connected when I don’t have a home to go back to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last week, while traveling in Bali, I realized being disconnected is a conscious choice, and I can change it. I didn’t realize this in the middle of a massage, or from a wise old man, or from acting out &lt;em&gt;Eat Pray Love&lt;/em&gt;. The epiphany occurred in my ride to the airport, with my taxi driver, Nyoman.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;does-it-scale&quot;&gt;Does it scale?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before I go deeper, I’d like to give you some more background. My friends and I have a problem: we like thinking of ideas for projects. We build up entire business plans over lunch that would require all of us to quit our jobs and spend a year or more working on them if we were honest about making them work. We’re constantly evaluating the annual revenue for local businesses based on the amount of customers we can count in a few minutes. We think of a dozen different ideas that could lead to viable streams of income, and discard the majority of them for not being long term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There’s a few questions we ask ourselves: What’s the market value? How much could you offload onto a virtual assistant? What are the competitors?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does it scale?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These questions make a lot of sense, if you’re in the San Francisco tech scene. As I’ve been finding out, their relevance is less clear elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;there-are-no-local-tech-workers&quot;&gt;There are no local tech workers&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I recently left San Francisco for the greener rice pastures of South East Asia. I’d never been before, and my work allows me to be wherever I want as long as there is an internet connection. Technically my client is in Massachusetts, but I was living in California before I realized I didn’t need to pay that much rent. So I moved.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not alone in being able to do this. The internet is distributed, and web developers generally work on projects which are location independent. This separates us from our communities; from the people we buy groceries from, from our youth groups, in some cases, like mine, from our friends, who live all over the world because they go where the jobs are. My community isn’t grounded anywhere, except maybe in a Slack channel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After a few weeks in Bali, my first destination, I started wondering if the recent rise in digital nomads and remote workers (and, to some extent, expats) is actually a symptom of an unhealthy society. Here I was, with tech money, coming and staying for a month at a hotel for almost nothing, eating out every meal. I learned a few words in Bahasa, but my only real interaction was people in the service industry - with the people at the laundromat, the cafe, and the co-working space. With my taxi drivers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;nyoman-ardika&quot;&gt;Nyoman Ardika&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was thinking about these themes one morning especially. I was heading to the airport for a weekend trip to Hong Kong to see an old friend and business partner of mine. The hotel arranged a taxi for me, and I sat in the front and started talking to the driver. That’s not uncommon here; it’s more normal to sit and chat to your driver than to sit in the back in silence. This is how I met Nyoman. After asking for basic phrases in the local language and just chatting, I asked him how long he had been driving, and he told me a bit about his life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nyoman is Balinese, and had been driving a taxi for around twenty years. Sixteen of those he had been an employee, getting paid less because he didn’t have his own car - generally, drivers get around 15-25% of the money they earn, while the rest goes to the company who provide their cars. Nyoman had saved up for years to buy his van, but he only owned half of it, and still had four years left on his payment plan. He worked every day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I must be hard,” he said. His son was in college learning to be an artist (craftsmen make good money in Bali), and his daughter would probably go to college soon. His wife and he played instruments and danced some nights with their friends, which he enjoyed. But driving past marshes, I mentioned that I heard there used to be good crab fishing there before the sewage plant was put in. I asked if he ever fished. “I don’t have the time. I must work every day. Even when I do not have a ride, I must wait.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I asked him if he had a website. “No. I have a phone, and my son can use the internet, but I don’t have a website. I don’t know how to use it.” I asked if he had an email. “Yes, Yahoo.” I asked if he thought about using any apps, like Trip Advisor, or offering repeat rides or so on. He became silent for a bit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think about how to make more money and change my business all day. I don’t know how. I don’t know what to do.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I stared at the ocean to our left for a few seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I could make you a website.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;build-more-small-things&quot;&gt;Build More Small Things&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I did: &lt;a href=&quot;http://inyoman.com&quot;&gt;inyoman.com&lt;/a&gt;. I don’t know if a website will help him out. Building websites is what I do - it’s an easy way for me to help without having to spend weeks of my time doing research on how to game the taxi industry. And what I do know is that since making it, I have been able to share it with twenty or thirty friends of mine in Bali, and he has gotten more rides because of it. I know that he will probably get one or two rides more from it, and that, if it is linked enough, he may actually rise in the rankings on Google and may be able to build a bigger business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing is, the website I made took the equivalent of an afternoon. There’s no tangible benefit for me in making it. It is for one guy,. It won’t scale. I’m not even unique: a friend of mine &lt;a href=&quot;http://juliasaiwayan.com&quot;&gt;made one&lt;/a&gt; for his taxi driver, a year before I did. Another American I know who has lived here for twenty years suggested that I build out a platform for taxi drivers to all build their own websites. But I’m not interested in a service like that - I think that the problems I’m working on are more economically viable for me in the long run, and more interesting from a developmental perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But for Nyoman, it may have gathered him an extra month’s pay. He works every day, but only gets around 18 rides a month. He showed me his ledger. He doesn’t earn much. A few extra rides may make a huge difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not every project needs to be built into a business plan. Not every product needs to be scalable. Not every product needs to be built for everyone anywhere in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And if I can make one man’s life a little easier by using one throwaway afternoon of mine, shouldn’t I do that?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On emotionally investing in a finite number of infinite possibilities</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-03-05/on-emotionally-investing-in-a-finite-number-of-infinite-possibilities"/>
   <updated>2015-03-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-03-05/on-emotionally-investing-in-a-finite-number-of-infinite-possibilities</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;There are an infinite amount of places this sentence can go. In closed systems, that space can be severely limited; to the point where a language comprised of one non-duplicatable value would only have a single possible state. Recently, I’ve been asking myself often what determines our intuition about bounded states that occur in, for lack of a better word, ‘real life’. I didn’t attend Philosophy 101 in college; I may not be using the right vocabulary throughout this, and I’d ask you to bear with me if that is the case.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For instance, I am currently in a cafe. I could walk outside of the door and do an infinite amount of things. However, when asked what I am going to do later, the answers will be highly bounded - I am going to go eat, or go home, or maybe if I’m feeling particularly crazy I’ll go to another cafe. The odds that I will walk out of this cafe, throw my backpack into opposing traffic, and begin swimming towards Alcatraz while screaming about the giant platypus in the sky are very, very low (I hope). But that’s a possibility. We all know about this - it’s something that we’re taught early on, in the same breath as ‘creativity’ and ‘living outside of your comfort zone’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, we don’t generally talk about other applications of questioning the bounds of possible paths or areas within the decision space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend Simon tweeted recently that he didn’t know “how I feel about these 2k person slacks that are starting to crop up.” I responded, casually - do you have to feel a certain way about them?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know intuitively what Simon meant - he was airing that he may have some unfinished thoughts surrounding a relatively new phenomenon online, and what it portends for the future of the internet (and for our jobs and lives, as online-living and -working people). I was trying to respond to his feeling about it - though. Why would he feel anything about the phenomenon, at all? This swiftly got interesting when he responded:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Simon: I’m not apathetic about most things I’m involved with?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Me: Sure you are. You’re being really selective of the fields of interaction you’re choosing to notice.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think about it. In the multiverse (a word I really don’t like but am going to use anyway), there are an infinite amount of things one chooses to take notice of. This doesn’t necessarily have to be about the multiverse - in the universe, there are an infinite amount of ways I could carve up reality into segments that involve interaction with me (there are probably a finite amount of segments that I would find semantically different, though). I could choose to interact with my coke bottle next to me at this cafe, or with the label, or with the Cousteau-like nautical light in the corner. Until I looked at the lamp just now, I had no preconceived statements I could make about my value judgements of it. But now I do. And I could repeat this process, infinitely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Choosing which objects to conceivably identify as worthy of emotional weight is a thing I can do. And it’s a thing you can do. It’s a way of dealing with limitless possibilities, and it is, in a sense, controllable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That may be what I was trying to say. I didn’t communicate the above thoughts as clearly as I could have. This may be, even, where I wanted this post to end up. I won’t know until I consider alternatives, and I am going to choose a path that involves me not following this line of thought presently. You don’t have to stop - the comment section is right beneath this final sentence.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>It's OK, Richard.</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-02-14/its-ok-richard"/>
   <updated>2015-02-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-02-14/its-ok-richard</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;It’s ok.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Richard, it’s OK.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’d rather sit in a cafe and solve interesting problems, working with brilliant people making the world a better place, you can do that. You don’t have to go to a cafe on the other side of the city because you said you wanted to go to a cafe on the other side of the city earlier in the day. You don’t even have to go outside. If you want to work, work.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>practice</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-01-08/practice"/>
   <updated>2015-01-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-01-08/practice</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“Practice makes the master.” - Patrick Rothfuss, &lt;em&gt;The Name of the Wind&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Skills are hard work. They take a lot of effort, and they take a lot of time. If you really want to be good at something, you have to do it every day - otherwise, your skills begin to rust.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve tried a lot of task management systems. None of them were very good at repeated tasks - probably because no one wants to feel like Sisyphus every day, seeing tasks they just accomplished the night before in their to do list. I don’t like feeling like Sisyphus, either, but there are tasks I do want to do daily. I’ve found the way to stress less about them is to take them outside of my to do list, and to have them in a list of their own, somewhere that reminds me what I need to do.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best place for me is my window: I sit daily and look outside at Protrero Hill, and writing on the window makes sense. So, I got a glass pen and wrote the four things I try to do every day on it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Code&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Journal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Exercise&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Meditate&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The issue is that I don’t &lt;em&gt;always&lt;/em&gt; sit at my window. But I am always on my laptop. So, I decided to use an old friend of mine,  &lt;a href=&quot;http://projects.tynsoe.org/en/geektool/&quot;&gt;GeekTool&lt;/a&gt;, to put the four items on my desktop. I made a node module that prints out whatever I haven’t done today into the terminal, and I mirror that on the desktop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the process of building this small thing, I learned a lot. For instance, how to use the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;bin&lt;/code&gt; field in npm’s &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;package.json&lt;/code&gt; file. Having an executable module without having to make an alias is amazing (You may recall I used aliases when I made &lt;a href=&quot;github.com/RichardLitt/journall&quot;&gt;journall&lt;/a&gt;. I also learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/rvagg/node-levelup&quot;&gt;levelup&lt;/a&gt;, which is great - this was the first time I actually used a proper database for some small project, and I like it much more than my old .csv file methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I also got it working with &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.alfredapp.com/&quot;&gt;Alfred&lt;/a&gt;, which I’ve used 33,000 times in the past 18 months (I highly suggest it). I made a workflow that allows me to send arguments to my node module directly from Alfred, which took a lot more tinkering than I thought, mostly because Alfred doesn’t offer node as an option and I had to jerry rig bash to make it work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the bash file I’m using:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;c&quot;&gt;#!/bin/bash &lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;task&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;s2&quot;&gt;&quot;{query}&quot;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;[[&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$task&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;o&quot;&gt;]]&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;then&lt;/span&gt;
  /usr/local/bin/node /usr/local/lib/node_modules/practice/bin/index.js &lt;span class=&quot;nv&quot;&gt;$task&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;
  /usr/local/bin/node /usr/local/lib/node_modules/practice/bin/index.js
&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;fi&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So far, the whole set up is working pretty well. I like having a clean desktop, so I work hard each day to do my four things, and then my desktop is clean again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And the best part is I am getting better at journaling, coding, meditating, and exercising. Here’s to the New Year, eh?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Books from 2014</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-01-04/books-from-2014"/>
   <updated>2015-01-04T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2015-01-04/books-from-2014</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;books-from-last-year&quot;&gt;Books from last year&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I read a lot. This year was no exception. I failed to keep a list, and I moved from New York to San Francisco in June. I’m not sure what I read in paperback before I moved, so this list isn’t complete. I’ve also given away some books, and I don’t remember some of those.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;As You Were: A Punk Comix Anthology&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Surprisingly had one of my favourite strips of all time, about a man missing a Mountain Goats concert&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tim Atkins - &lt;strong&gt;Horace&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Really quite atrocious&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robert Bringhurst - &lt;strong&gt;A Story As Sharp As A Knife&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Incredible work about Haida mythtellers. I wish it was longer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bruce Chatwin - &lt;strong&gt;What Am I Doing Here&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Still the best storyteller I’ve read&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anderson Cooper - &lt;strong&gt;Dispatches from the Edge&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ken Follett - &lt;strong&gt;The Pillars of the Earth&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Amazingly long book about building a cathedral. I wouldn’t suggest reading this on your phone.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Allen Ginsberg - &lt;strong&gt;Howl and other poems&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;He wrote other poems, too!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Green - &lt;strong&gt;Looking for Alaska&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Frank Herbert - &lt;strong&gt;Dune&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Best book ever&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Franz Kafka - &lt;strong&gt;The Metamorphosis, in the penal colony, and other stories&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A Hunger Artist was a fantastic story&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jack Kerouac - &lt;strong&gt;The Dharma Bums&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;A must read&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Daniel Keyes - &lt;strong&gt;Flowers for Algernon&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Made me cry&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Martin Luther King Jr. - &lt;strong&gt;Where Do We Go From Here: Chaos or Community&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Fantastic and still very pertinent read&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CS Lewis - &lt;strong&gt;The Great Divorce&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Worst book ever&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;CS Lewis - &lt;strong&gt;Prince Caspian&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;So, apparently, Lewis was incredibly sexist&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lois Lowry - &lt;strong&gt;The Giver&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Alice Miller - &lt;strong&gt;The Drama of the Gifted Child&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;No comment&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Yukio Mishima - &lt;strong&gt;The Sound of Waves&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;My favorite Japanese author. Astoundingly good&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;John Myers Myers - &lt;strong&gt;Silverlock&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Someone published this?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ryan North - &lt;strong&gt;B to the F: The Novelization of the Feature Film: Ryan North reviews George Gipe’s insane novelization of the major motion picture&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;If you want to laugh, this was the funniest book I have ever read&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sean Patrick - &lt;strong&gt;Nikola Tesla&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Don’t download free books from iTunes people&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Penny Arcade - &lt;strong&gt;Epic Legends of the Magic Sword Kings&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Did not age well&lt;/em&gt;\&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rogers, Sharp, Preece - &lt;strong&gt;Interaction Design&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This was a very good introduction to design and UI and I actually thoroughly enjoyed it&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gary Snyder - &lt;strong&gt;Turtle Island&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gary Snyder - &lt;strong&gt;The Real Work&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This was incredibly, equally as good as my favourite book of his,&lt;/em&gt; The Practice of the Wild&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gary Snyder - &lt;strong&gt;The Back Country&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;You know, I don’t think I like Snyder’s poetry all that much&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elizabeth George Speare - &lt;strong&gt;The Sign of the Beaver&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Reading young adult books in old age is amusing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Neal Stephenson - &lt;strong&gt;Snow Crash&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;Amusing&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Jonathan Swift - &lt;strong&gt;Gulliver’s Travels&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This wasn’t worth the read, but there were some fun moments&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;David Troupes - &lt;strong&gt;The Fountain&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;David Troupes - &lt;strong&gt;Parsimony&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - &lt;strong&gt;There Are Doors&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I gave up on this book the first time I’ve read it; I read it twice this year. It’s an incredible fantasy set in 1920s SF or so.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - &lt;strong&gt;The Book of the New Sun (Tetrology)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - &lt;strong&gt;The Urth of the New Sun&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;This is the addendum to the Book of the New Sun, my favorite series&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - &lt;strong&gt;The Wizard&lt;/strong&gt; &lt;em&gt;I read the Wizard and the Knight at least once a year&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - &lt;strong&gt;The Knight&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Gene Wolfe - &lt;strong&gt;The Ziggurat&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Robert Zelazny - &lt;strong&gt;Doorways in the Sand&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Randomly picking a GitHub Issue</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-12-26/14-56-randomly-picking-a-github-issue"/>
   <updated>2014-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-12-26/14-56-randomly-picking-a-github-issue</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I sometimes have an issue choosing what GitHub issue to tackle next. Who doesn’t? Here’s my solution to fixing that problem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, install &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/stephencelis/ghi&quot;&gt;ghi&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ghi&lt;/code&gt; is a command line client for GitHub issues. &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;brew install ghi&lt;/code&gt; will do it. Try it out in your repo dir by running &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;ghi&lt;/code&gt; - look, all of your open issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next, if you’re using OSX, the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt; command is sadly defficient. It doesn’t allow &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;--random-sort&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;-R&lt;/code&gt;, and I don’t know why. To fix this, install GNU coreutils: &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;brew install coreutils&lt;/code&gt;. This will install Linux &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;sort&lt;/code&gt;, with the prefix &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;g&lt;/code&gt;. Now, to randomly choose an issue, just run:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;ghi | gsort -R | head -n 1
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fun times!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Trello and To Do Lists</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-12-25/16-47-trello-and-to-do-lists"/>
   <updated>2014-12-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-12-25/16-47-trello-and-to-do-lists</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h1 id=&quot;december-25th&quot;&gt;2014 December 25th&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trello isn’t working for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have an Agile board for my life, which I have been using regularly for around six months. I have these lists:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Bwat&lt;/strong&gt;. This is borrowed from Paul Farmer, who I read about in the amazing book &lt;em&gt;Mountains Beyond Mountains&lt;/em&gt;. Basically, he would tick off a box (called &lt;em&gt;bwat&lt;/em&gt; in Haitian Creole) whenever he did something. I like this idea, and it reminds me to try and do actually meaningful things (because all of Paul Farmer’s work is, and mine so often isn’t).&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Today&lt;/strong&gt;. This is supposedly what I plan to do that day, but often it is instead simply a list of small tasks that I want to do. It is almost never a list of things I need to do that day, and it never approaches the scope of things I want to do. Instead, it is normally two or three hours worth of random things, after which I do the actual work after those are done. This isn’t efficient. I try and put an amount in that I can do in a day, but most days I forget. The worst part is that I end up with tons of little boxes saying ‘Read Hacker News’, or some other newsletter, which swiftly leads to fatigue as reading a lot of small articles becomes exhausting.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Later&lt;/strong&gt;. This is more often than not blocked items, or things I want to do tomorrow - right now, there are four of those: &lt;em&gt;code&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;exercise&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;journal&lt;/em&gt;, and &lt;em&gt;inbox zero&lt;/em&gt;. Since I do these daily, I constantly move them between Today and Later, and just create a new ticket each day for each after I complete them. I never look through my archived tickets, so this isn’t so wasteful as it seems.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To Do&lt;/strong&gt;. This is basically an in folder, where everything goes. And I mean everything that doesn’t go into…&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Code, Physical To Do, Reading, Writing, Ideas, Blog Lists, Deferred Shopping Lists&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;Long Term&lt;/strong&gt;. Anything that goes in these lists - with the possible exception of coding - is swiftly forgotten about.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, this isn’t great. And I think I need to change it up. I have a list of projects in my To Do folder (along with a ton of PDFs I will never, ever read). I update it every few months. What I ought to be doing is mixing this in with my Trello list. Instead of segmenting things into ‘do now’, ‘do at some point’, and the ‘do never but nice idea’ categories, I should have cards for each project, and then have lists inside them with actionable items. At the start of each day, I should decide what projects to work on that day (of course, overwhelmingly, this will be my main job, building &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/BeagleLab/voyage&quot;&gt;Beagle&lt;/a&gt;). Then, I should decide what actionables for that day are possible, and move them out of the list using the ‘convert to card’ mechanism, and start taking them on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This loosely follows the &lt;a href=&quot;http://hamberg.no/gtd/&quot;&gt;Get Things Done&lt;/a&gt; philosophy, which I like. Hopefully, it’ll cut down on admin and job bloat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another thing I should start doing - well, that I have started doing since I started writing this post - is to organize my daily tasks better. I’ve just made a little node module called &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RichardLitt/practice&quot;&gt;Practice&lt;/a&gt;, which prints out the keys to an object if their values are false - that is, if I haven’t done a task yet, it lets me know. I’ve set  this up with GeekTool so that I can actually see the items on my desktop, where I’ll notice them. I hate having things on my desktop, so this will be pretty good motivation to do my daily tasks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img style=&quot;max-width:500px;padding: 30px 5px;&quot; src=&quot;http://i.imgur.com/MlXIwqu.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s to shaking up my to do lists.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>journall</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-09-21/22-50-journall"/>
   <updated>2014-09-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-09-21/22-50-journall</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Yesterday I published my first two NPM packages. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/natural-gutenberg&quot;&gt;natural-gutenberg&lt;/a&gt; is a collection of around 20 creative commons texts used in the NLTK python library, now available as node packages so that people using &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/NaturalNode/natural&quot;&gt;natural&lt;/a&gt; can use them too. The second one, which is more interesting, is &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RichardLitt/journall-public&quot;&gt;journall&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I take a lot of notes. I carry around four notebooks with me at all times, five if you count my laptop: one for my drawings (I used to have a webcomic for two years), one for long form writing, one for short form writing that is pocket size, and one that is the size of a passport that I plan to mail to an old friend of mine when I finally finish writing in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can imagine what my computer looks like. Tons of files, everywhere, scattered on the Desktop, in a folder called To Do, on Trello, in Documents, in a folder called Writings, and just randomly around. What I need is organization: a place I can quickly scribble things without thinking about where they end up. So, I made Journall, a small script that does that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Journall is a node script that uses an entries folder, and saves a file titled with the date - for instance, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;2014.09.16.md&lt;/code&gt;. It is a lot easier to save things in this format, as they are always alphabetized correctly. Journall won’t make a new file if today’s date is already taken. It also adds in a brief header.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The best thing about it is that it opens the file automatically, in my favorite editor, after being run. The idea is that typing journall automatically constructs the file for you, so you don’t have to build one yourself, and so you always have a markdown file you can write anything in that is persistently saved so you don’t end up with hundreds of random files in a folder called ‘journal’.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Natively, this package supports iA Writer, which is the best Markdown editor I’ve found for OS X. I highly suggest getting it - the full screen mode is absolutely beautiful, the focus mode is amazing, and distraction mode is double amazing. Basically, this program is the closest I have gotten to pretending I am on a typewriter while still having the power of techno-God at my fingertips.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To make everything easier, I added this to my .bash_profile:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;alias journall=&#39;node /path/to/dir/journall/index.js&#39;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This means that every time I want to write something down, now, I just open the terminal (which is almost always open already, and I have a hotkey for it, cmd+ctrl+t), and type &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;journall&lt;/code&gt;. And oi la! I am writing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get journall &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.npmjs.org/package/journall&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Random Coincidence Rates with Unsteady Sources</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-09-02/23-17-random-coincidence-rates-with-unsteady-sources"/>
   <updated>2014-09-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-09-02/23-17-random-coincidence-rates-with-unsteady-sources</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Random Coincidence Rates with Unsteady Sources&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Or: &lt;em&gt;A Collection of Published Paper Titles from Google Scholar by Authors Named R Littauer, Arranged by Relevance: A Poem&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The air war in Indochina&lt;br /&gt;
Charged Photomesons from Various Nuclei&lt;br /&gt;
High-Energy Photoproduction of π 0 Mesons from Hydrogen&lt;br /&gt;
Elastic Scattering of Photons by Protons. I&lt;br /&gt;
Scattering of Bev Electrons by Hydrogen and Deuterium&lt;br /&gt;
Betatron phase and coupling measurements at the Cornell Electron/Positron Storage Ring&lt;br /&gt;
Electron-Proton Scattering at High-Momentum Transfer&lt;br /&gt;
Structure of the Proton and Neutron&lt;br /&gt;
Instructional Implications of a Low-Cost Electronic Student Response System.&lt;br /&gt;
Pulse electronics&lt;br /&gt;
Multibunch operation of CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Wide-Angle Bremsstrahlung&lt;br /&gt;
ρ Production in Deep-Inelastic Electron Scattering&lt;br /&gt;
Beam diagnostic instrumentation at CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Beam instrumentation&lt;br /&gt;
An ion current integrator&lt;br /&gt;
Production of Photomesons&lt;br /&gt;
Inclusive Pion Distributions in Electroproduction&lt;br /&gt;
Pressure‐Fed Liquid Hydrogen Target&lt;br /&gt;
Pulse‐Height Analyzer for Neuro‐Physiological Applications&lt;br /&gt;
PRODUCTION OF PHOTO-MESONS FROM DEUTERIUM AND OTHER LIGHT ELEMENTS&lt;br /&gt;
“ Anomalous,” Nonlinearly Current-Dependent Damping in CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Photoproduction of π 0 Mesons from Hydrogen in the Region 900 to 1200 Mev&lt;br /&gt;
Accelerators: machines of nuclear physics&lt;br /&gt;
Photodisintegration of the Deuteron by 180-Mev and 260-Mev Gamma Rays&lt;br /&gt;
Production of photomesons in deuterium&lt;br /&gt;
The Unfreezing of Foreign Funds&lt;br /&gt;
Confiscation of the Property of Technical Enemies&lt;br /&gt;
STABILIZATION OF LASERS OR THE LIKE&lt;br /&gt;
Interaction of Pi-Mesons with Carbon and Aluminum Nuclei&lt;br /&gt;
CESR Status and Performance&lt;br /&gt;
Trends in use of scientific workflows: insights from a public repository and recommendations for best practice&lt;br /&gt;
Bunch length measurement using beam spectrum (CESR storage ring)&lt;br /&gt;
Double Pion Photoproduction&lt;br /&gt;
Inclusive Proton Distributions in Electroproduction&lt;br /&gt;
High Energy Photodisintegration of the Deuteron&lt;br /&gt;
Photomesonic Fission of Bismuth&lt;br /&gt;
The (n, γ) and (n, 2 n) Reactions in Iodine&lt;br /&gt;
CVIII. The radioactivity of F20.—II&lt;br /&gt;
Random Coincidence Rates with Unsteady Sources&lt;br /&gt;
An eight-dimensional pulse-height analyzer&lt;br /&gt;
Single bunch current dependent phenomena in CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Data management guide for public participation in scientific research&lt;br /&gt;
Do Walker,” Production of Photomesons from Deuterium and Other Light Elements,”&lt;br /&gt;
The luminosity performance of CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Interaction of CESR vacuum pumps with stored beam&lt;br /&gt;
The Angular Distribution of Gamma-Rays from 7Li (p, p’) 7Li*&lt;br /&gt;
Collisions of Resonantly Coupled Round Beams at the Cornell Electron-Positron Storage Ring (CESR)&lt;br /&gt;
Enemy Property in War&lt;br /&gt;
Elastic Scattering of Photons by Protons. II&lt;br /&gt;
Using wireless keypads in lecture classes&lt;br /&gt;
Investigation of chromaticity sharing at the Cornell Electron Storage Ring&lt;br /&gt;
Investigation of the Möbius accelerator at CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Beam-beam modes in Q-monitoring&lt;br /&gt;
Improvements to the CESR injector and injection process&lt;br /&gt;
THE INTERACTION OF PI-MESONS WITH NUCLEI&lt;br /&gt;
Visualising typological relationships: Plotting wals with heat maps&lt;br /&gt;
Beam Instrumentation, Physics of High Energy Particle Accelerators&lt;br /&gt;
Notes on Phase Oscillations&lt;br /&gt;
HF Schopper e RR Wilson&lt;br /&gt;
Building a Linked Open Data cloud of linguistic resources: Motivations and developments&lt;br /&gt;
Observation of the beam-beam limit in CESR&lt;br /&gt;
An External Beam from the Cornell 10 GeV Synchrotron&lt;br /&gt;
Performance of the Cornell High Intensity Linac Injector&lt;br /&gt;
From the Savannah to the Cloud. Blogging Evolutionary Linguistics Research&lt;br /&gt;
SLAC Accelerator School&lt;br /&gt;
PHOTOMESONS FROM HYDROGEN&lt;br /&gt;
Proposed Multibunch Operation Of Cesr&lt;br /&gt;
A Megawatt Soltd-State Inverter to Power the Cornell 10 GeV Electron Synchrotron&lt;br /&gt;
Measurement and simulation of beam-beam effects in the weak/strong regime&lt;br /&gt;
Multiplex Control and Monitoring of a Large Accelerator&lt;br /&gt;
Acceleratori di particelle: macchine della fisica nucleare&lt;br /&gt;
EXTERNAL BEAM FROM CORNELL TO GEV SYNCHROTRON&lt;br /&gt;
How far should you develop a formula?&lt;br /&gt;
MULTIPLFX CONTROL AID M3NITORING OF A IAFGE ACCELERATOR&lt;br /&gt;
THE RADIOACTIVITY OF F $ sup 20$. II&lt;br /&gt;
EP363/P360 course notes and laboratory manual&lt;br /&gt;
Linguistic Resources Enhanced with Geospatial Information&lt;br /&gt;
Beschleuniger: die kernphysikalischen Maschinen&lt;br /&gt;
PHYS-3360/AEP-3630 LABORATORY MANUAL 2014-2015&lt;br /&gt;
A Reanalysis of Anatomical Changes for Language: Re-Dating the Loss of Laryngeal Air Sacs in Homo sapiens&lt;br /&gt;
INFORMATION TRANSMISSION BY TIME PROGRAMMED MULTIPLEXING&lt;br /&gt;
Case law and systematic law: A descriptive comparison of american and German legal thinking&lt;br /&gt;
EXTERNAL BEAM FROM CORNELL 10 GEV SYNCHROTRON&lt;br /&gt;
PHOTOPRODUCTION OF $ pi $ $ sup 0$ MESONS FROM HYDROGEN IN THE REGION 900 to 1200 MEV&lt;br /&gt;
Replicating Oliphant’s Saussurean Simulations&lt;br /&gt;
Using Clojure in Linguistic Computing&lt;br /&gt;
THE EVOLUTION OF MORPHOLOGICAL AGREEMENT&lt;br /&gt;
PHOTODISINTEGRATION OF DEUTERIUM AT 180-MEV 260-MEV&lt;br /&gt;
CESR: the first year&lt;br /&gt;
The Open Linguistics Working Group.&lt;br /&gt;
HIGH-ENERGY PHOTOPRODUCTION OF $ pi $ $ sup 0$ MESONS FROM HYDROGEN&lt;br /&gt;
RE-DATING THE LOSS OF LARYNGEAL AIR SACS IN HOMO SAPIENS&lt;br /&gt;
CROWD SOURCING THE CLASSROOM: INTERACTIVE APPLICATIONS IN HIGHER LEARNING&lt;br /&gt;
Beam-Beam Effects at CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Academic research in the Blogosphere: Adapting to new opportunities and risks on the Internet&lt;br /&gt;
CERN Accelerating science&lt;br /&gt;
A Reanalysis of Oliphant’s Saussurean Simulations&lt;br /&gt;
The Multiplex Control System for the Cornell 10-GeV Synchrotron&lt;br /&gt;
RHO PRODUCTION IN DEEP INELASTIC ELECTRON SCATTERING&lt;br /&gt;
OPERATION OF THE CORNELL 10-GeV ELECTRON SYNCHROTRON.&lt;br /&gt;
MEASUREIvlENT AND SIMULATION OF BEAM-BEAM EFFECTS INTHE WEAK/STRONG REGIME&lt;br /&gt;
Electron-proton scattering at high momentum transfer&lt;br /&gt;
RR Wilson Prize Lecture: Pretzels&lt;br /&gt;
A Single Beam Multibunch Instability at CESR&lt;br /&gt;
EXPERIMENTAL TEST OF RADIATIVE CORRECTIONS IN HIGH ENERGY ELECTRON-PROTON SCATTERING&lt;br /&gt;
A Reanalysis of Anatomical Changes for Language&lt;br /&gt;
Monitoring system to permit accurate alignment of beams at collision in CESR&lt;br /&gt;
Using Demographic Data with Bayesian Phylogenies: A Japanese Case Study&lt;br /&gt;
The Angular Distribution of Gamma-Rays from/SOP 7/Li (p, p’) $ sup 7$ Li*&lt;br /&gt;
The CESR Control System&lt;br /&gt;
Accelerators&lt;br /&gt;
BEAM POSITION MONITORS FOR THE CORNELL ELECTRON&lt;br /&gt;
PHYS-360/AEP-363 LABORATORY MANUAL 2008-2009&lt;br /&gt;
LINAC INJECTION INTO THE CORNELL 1.3 BEV ELECTRON SYNCHROTRON&lt;br /&gt;
Schiedsgerichtsbarkeit und materielles Recht&lt;br /&gt;
Den tibetanske buddhismes normative etik&lt;br /&gt;
Aceleradores de particulas&lt;br /&gt;
Beschleuniger&lt;br /&gt;
Die private Volksversicherung und die Reformversuche auf gemeinnutziger Grundlage&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>@DeadGuys</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-09-01/10-30-deadguys"/>
   <updated>2014-09-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-09-01/10-30-deadguys</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;A few years ago, Simon and I had the idea of tweeting when musicians died. I’m not sure why - the origins are lost in history. We set up a twitter account, @DeadGuys. The name was based on a family joke of mine (now that I think about it, that’s pretty morbid), where we used the term Dead Guys to refer to old dead white Christian theologists my mother was obsessed with teaching about (CS Lewis, Martin Luther, John Calvin, etc, etc).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We tweeted 43 times in the past four or five years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today, I deleted this account. Here are some lessons I learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t make anything you wouldn’t feel comfortable telling anyone in your family about, because chances are you probably wouldn’t want to tell other people about it, either. If you’re closer to your friends, well, don’t make anything you wouldn’t tell your friends about.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;When you start a project on Twitter, generally, it’s good to retweet it or at least try to get the word out about it. People do not randomly search for things on Twitter nearly as often as you think they do.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t make a project that depends on you hearing news tangentially and decided to update it, posteriori. Chances are it won’t update nearly enough to have a life of it’s own.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t set up a separate gmail account for random accounts like this, because if you forget the password and have forwarding set up, it can get annoying.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t be disrespectful, of fans, family, or the dead. We didn’t get any flack about this account, but I was never proud of it, because I thought it belittled, in a sense, the work of great musicians. I’m not proud of that.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Don’t start projects without a purpose. Chances are, you won’t find one later.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Cabin Porn = SFW backgrounds?</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-08-10/16-24-cabin-porn-sfw-backgrounds"/>
   <updated>2014-08-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-08-10/16-24-cabin-porn--sfw-backgrounds</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I really like &lt;a href=&quot;http://cabinporn.com&quot;&gt;cabin porn&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like, a lot. It’s the only blog that I regularly look at, not counting a lot of comics. I find it relaxing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I wanted a way of saving the cabins to my desktop, automatically, so I wouldn’t have to actually go to the website to see the cabins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So I decided to refresh my python-scrape and osascript-foo and just build one. A few hours into a Saturday night later, and I’ve got it. &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RichardLitt/cabin-porn&quot;&gt;Here is the code.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I would suggest setting up a cronjob to actually make it check every few hours and see if Cabin Porn has posted a new sexy picture, but I don’t actually bother. I’ll just change it when I get tired of the current one. I use 6 desktops, so I’ll keep the other five as random pictures from my trove of thousands (here’s &lt;a href=&quot;https://imgur.com/a/L9Y1L&quot;&gt;some&lt;/a&gt;), but my default is now a cabin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hooray!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Losing it with the TSA</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-05-26/15-41-losing-it-with-the-tsa"/>
   <updated>2014-05-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-05-26/15-41-losing-it-with-the-tsa</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;This is a story about a social experiment. What happens if I decide to opt out of the full body screeners? How am I treated differently?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I arrive at the gate two hours early for my flight from San Francisco to San Diego, with a planned layover in Los Angeles. I’ve never flown south of here before, and I have a habit of always showing up two hours before a flight, even when I can feel the city leaving me as I take the Uber car to the airport. I sign in at the gate, have a last cigarette, and go to security.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve travelled a lot. I’ve racked up more miles by thumb (hitching) than almost anyone I know, and I’ve flown far more times than most of my friends. I’m a bit ashamed of that - I write long letters to a friend of mine in Wales, and she always says she’s going to have to come to the US someday but can’t with the world’s carbon levels being what they are. Her last letter had a drawing of a plane that was scribbled out with the word NO emblazoned over it. So, I feel guilty about being at the airport in the first place. I had planned to hitch down California 1 - the opposite direction of a trip I took two years ago to Vancouver - but I felt sick and I loved San Francisco so much I was toying on cancelling my flight and staying there regardless. So, I bought a cheap ticket, and showed up today to fly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just to let you know, I got through - I’m in the airport bar now, drinking Anchor Steam and listening to music. You can breathe. This isn’t a horror story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I’ve read a lot of horror stories about the TSA. And I’ve experienced some, myself; I was denied entry to the UK once, and kept in detention for a day before being flown back to Hungary. I’ve been held up at gunpoint at the Macedonian border, and I’ve shook hands with a friend who got deported (long story) from an Antiguan jail. I’ve illegally entered and left countries, several times. But I’ve never been at the brunt of the American border, never seen what it is really like to be unwanted or a security risk here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman in front of me was sitting next to the full body scanner - she had decided to ‘opt out’ of being put into a humiliating machine where they can look at a very realistic depiction of your body. I didn’t know you could opt out. I had two hours to kill. Sorry, spend - you can’t be too careful.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’ll opt out, please.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The TSA officer, a woman in her late twenties, didn’t blink an eye. She told me to sit down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;We have a male opt out, on Lane 4. Male opt out, Lane 4.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;She repeated this several times. After around two minutes of waiting, watching as people passed by me, a man in his sixties with thinning hair and probably weighing twice my weight came over. He was distantly friendly, and I followed him through the gate on the side, avoiding the Machine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He takes me through to where my bags are - two carryons and a collection of personal items - my camera, hat, iPhone, shoes, and belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Is this everything?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I pointed out that my computer was missing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My computer is my life. In the two minutes I had spent sitting and waiting, someone must have took it. I broke out in cold sweats almost immediately, wondering what I would do without it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This wasn’t funny anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We waited for a minute, and I got increasingly anxious. Eventually, he grabbed my bags and walked me over to the screening room, saying that the supervisor was busy. He called to another agent, a portly woman in her fifties, and she asked in a condescending manner to the other man if he had waited, if anything strange had happened, if I had put it on the belt. I think he was a TSA in training, and flustered he answered that he had done all of these things. He took me back across to the belt, and put down my things. We waited another minute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman TSA officer came over again and asked if I had been patted down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No, you told me to wait.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Well, pat him down.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In my mind, the bit of fear turned into a mountain. I wasn’t just dealing with the TSA - I was dealing with straight out incompetency. I started swearing internally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He took me over to the side, and put on new latex gloves. He then proceeded to explain where he would pat me, and how - using the outside of his hands, the inside of his hands, and so on. He began to pat me down, after asking the woman if she wanted to do it (no). While I’m there, she asks me if I had put my laptop with the other bags. I said yes. I ask if there were cameras - she nods, and said they will get to that. Meanwhile, the man finishes patting me down. It was far less invasive than I had figured, possibly because I have nothing to hide, although I did sit with these jeans on a porch where people were smoking weed last night (but this is California, and I don’t smoke marijuana), and because I really had nothing to fear. I had asked for this, after all.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the man is done, he bumbles over to the trays, and starts looking through all of them. I’m imagining someone holding my laptop like a child and getting onto the next flight to Kuala Lampur. I’m screwed. While I’m figuring out if I can write this off as a tax deductible insurance loss or something, I see him walk all the way to the front of the belts, and try the containers there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He takes a container, and puts it on the tray. It’s my laptop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;You forgot to put it on the belt. It happens most of the time in situations like these.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He hands it back to me, and walks away. I’m free to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The woman TSA agent comes over, and asks casually if I am flying for business. I explain I am, but that I haven’t travelled much domestically recently. She says I can get a precheck for $80 for five years, and avoid a lot of this. I nod, and explain I just wanted to see how it would go if I opt out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Oh, I don’t mind at all if you opt out. No one really cares. I tell my grandparents to - I’m from Jersey, they live in Florida, and they travel all the time. They’re 70. Just opt out, I tell them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I sheepishly put on my shoes, and think that two minutes ago I was worried the TSA had screwed me over by keeping me waiting while my laptop was stolen, and now I’m discussing grandparents. I say thanks, and walk away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, this isn’t a horror story. Nobody died. Nobody even got detained. I’ve had worse walking to my apartment in Brooklyn. But it is a story - I walked in, purposefully trying to see what would happen if I went beyond what was necessary with expectations of red tape, poor service, and structural violence. Instead, I ended up shooting myself in the foot by messing up the system in the first place, and found that really, the TSA isn’t the worst thing in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Still, though, this beer I’m drinking tastes pretty good right now, if only because I can drink it with my laptop in front of me.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sun Tzu and the art of Go</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-05-20/11-53-sun-tzu-and-the-art-of-go"/>
   <updated>2014-05-20T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-05-20/11-53-sun-tzu-and-the-art-of-go</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I read a pretty good article in Wired recently, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wired.com/2014/05/the-world-of-computer-go/&quot;&gt;The Mystery of Go, the Ancient Game that Computers Still Can’t Win&lt;/a&gt;. If you didn’t know, Go is an incredible chess-like game played mainly in Japan. In it, Remi Coulom’s computer program that he’s used to win some computer-vs-computer Go games is discussed, as is Remi’s interest in the game and a history of the game itself. I suggest you read it rather than having me summarize it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In particular, they talk about how the best programs that can play Go (Not Go programs - Go is a programming language, as well as an awesome game) use Monte Carlo Markov Chains. That makes sense, because you can cut down on the amount of time needed to search possible paths for the game to play. I used to use Markov chains for my undergraduate thesis, modeling how 8-month-old children learn word boundaries when they don’t know individual words.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My question here is; is this really the best way? To try and gamify the search space, so that you don’t have to do so many calculations?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think there’s possibly another way to do it. You view the board as a map. Then, you apply the old logic of Sun Tzu and the Art of War, and learn the territory. Stay updated. Take a birds eye view. Here’s what I’m thinking; instead of using the possible points on the board, model the board as topographical zones, or colors, or as water with boundaries. Then, fuzz the boundaries between the points; look at where the crucial choke points are, at the heat. Don’t use the computer to simply do the odds of calculations; try and teach the computer to view the board as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then do Markov chains. Then win.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Two new publications</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-04-05/15-40-two-new-publications"/>
   <updated>2014-04-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2014-04-05/15-40-two-new-publications</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve had two new publications published recently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Littauer, Sean G. Roberts, James Winters, Rachael Bailes, Michael Pleyer, Hannah Little (2014). &lt;em&gt;From the Savannah to the Cloud: Blogging Evolutionary Linguistics Research&lt;/em&gt;. In: L. McCrohon, B. Thompson, T. Verhoef, H. Yamauchi, eds., &lt;em&gt;The Past, Present and Future of Language Evolution Research: Student Volume of the 9th International Conference on the Evolution of Language&lt;/em&gt;, pp.121-132. Tokyo, Japan: Evolang 9 Organizing Committee. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burntfen.com/publications/bib/LittEvoC.bib&quot;&gt;bib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Littauer, Boris Villazon-Terrazas, Steven Moran (2013). &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.aclweb.org/anthology/W13-5508&quot;&gt;Linguistic Resources Enhanced with Geospatial Information&lt;/a&gt;. In: C. Chiarcos, P. Cimiano, T. Declerck, J. McCrae, eds., &lt;em&gt;Proceedings of the 2nd Workshop on Linked Data in Linguistics (LDL-2013): Representing and linking lexicons, terminologies and other language data&lt;/em&gt;, pp. 53-58. Pisa, Italy: Association for Computational Linguistics. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burntfen.com/publications/bib/LittLDL.bib&quot;&gt;bib&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m pretty proud of both of them. The first is a description of what we’re doing over at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.replicatedtypo.com&quot;&gt;Replicated Typo&lt;/a&gt;, and how we hope the field of linguistics and academic research can change. I haven’t posted much there recently, but it’s a good overview of academic blogging in general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second is a really cool test study of the power of linked data to map out GIS, and how we can use this in Linguistics.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Marshland</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-26/15-06-marshland"/>
   <updated>2013-12-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-26/15-06-marshland</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Alright.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The fabric of the world has snagged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The miasma bubbles up from the rotting vegetation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We float upon the tender grasses lifted by the marsh. Our sneakers grow wet with mud and pond water. We are collapsing in the runoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Beneath our feet, the frog eggs drape the front of our sunk canoe like a shroud. Soon, they too will bloom, like the lady slippers on the near bank.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An old woodpecker taps at the dead log, pointing up like an old man towards heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Snag. Snag. And snag again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“And is this not the essential function of the art, to add something if possible to the sum total of pleasure and form in a world where so much is subtracted by pain, confusion, and fear.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I return to romp the swamp again, and find my boots have stuck in years-old mud. Spears litter the littoral spread, like carrots on a trencher. Their gnawed tips grey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally published &lt;a href=&quot;https://medium.com/p/aa218f25ab8b&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Bushwhich</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-22/12-08-bushwhich"/>
   <updated>2013-12-22T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-22/12-08-bushwhich</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I can now finally release my newest project, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bushwhich.com&quot;&gt;Bushwhich&lt;/a&gt;, a Choose-Your-Own-Adventure set in Bushwick, my neighborhood in Brooklyn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On January 7th, I made a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/richard.littauer/posts/4382686000497&quot;&gt;post on Facebook&lt;/a&gt; offering to make five of my friends a special, unique, handmade gift, if they promised to pay it forward at some point. For my friend David Deacon, I made a set of cards that provide interesting fact for each family of squid. For Sarah Hunt, I wrote a poem. For my friends Alex and Joe, I wanted to make a game. Joe works as a sound designer, Alex as a sound masterer. I didn’t think I’d be able to make something worth their while audio-wise, but I know they both like video games. They kept asking me how living in NY is, and I decided to show them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After I bought a new camera, I had an idea. I borrowed my friend Sam for a day, and we rode all around Bushwick, going to my favourite spots, taking photos the whole time. By the end, I had around 350 photographs detailing most of the cool haunts I like. This was a pretty fun use of a day, and involved getting pretty drunk. Then the real work began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the past few months, I’ve been working in my spare time setting up the site. I didn’t want to make it too complicated - while I’m primarily a front-end developer, I thought that building a complex Javascript site that logged clicks and the like would quickly spiral into a massive project that wouldn’t be finished for years. So, I built the entire site in simple HTML and CSS. I used &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllbootstrap.com/&quot;&gt;Jekyll Bootstrap&lt;/a&gt;, a fantastic free static site blogging platform that runs on &lt;a href=&quot;http://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;. This site is built using the same software, as is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.mellowpageslibrary.com&quot;&gt;MellowPagesLibrary&lt;/a&gt;, another site I’ve built recently for my neighborhood library. I spent a few days building a custom theme, and trying to change the automation process (I wanted to publish folios, not posts, etc). After a while, I settled on a good way of doing it. So, I imported all of the photos, shrank them all to a decent size - good enough to be used as a decent desktop background in case someone like the picture, but small enough to not destroy a good internet connection. I used bash to build a fancy regex that automatically developed all of the posts needed to generate each page.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I spent hours and hours and days writing every page, planning out how the route would go. I didn’t draw a map to help, figuring it would be more fun if I got lost, too. Finally, last night, I finished every route. There may be a few bugs here and there - but on the whole, it should work. There’s a lot of options - going to the laundromat, to buy cigarettes, watching Harry Potter, eating at Bushwick Living Room, at Swallow, at Cain’s, at Alaska, going to Manhattan, dying in the subway on the way to Far Fockaway, getting sucked in by hipsters in McKibben Lofts, fixing your bike. It’s an adventure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope you all like it. Initial feedback from Alex and Joe indicate they’re happy. So, I am too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.bushwhick.com&quot;&gt;Go play!&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Things done</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-16/09-08-things-done"/>
   <updated>2013-12-16T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-16/09-08-things-done</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;As I was cleaning up my desktop this morning, waiting for some program to install work work, I ran across a document I made a couple of days after Thanksgiving, titled &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;things done&lt;/code&gt;. This was it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Updated UKLO website&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrote redacted about her article.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wrote David redacted&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Got some new albums&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i Wrote Pete about about page&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;i Wrote Gergo about video icon and deployment&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Emailed David again&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Archived Currents Against Us&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Talked to Aunt Theresa, went on a walk with Uncle Tom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Decided to make an Angular-Github-Pages repository that will run on Jekyll&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Took a long walk with Uncle Tom&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Said hi to Jordan&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Sat in a coffee house&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What a day that must have been, most notably for the two separate walks. Why am I posting this? Because this list shows a desire I have to chronicle my days, to make an account of them, to be able to check off things as I do them (even if they weren’t on a checklist before). This is one of the reasons I spent around 5 hours fighting databases to try and get &lt;a href=&quot;http://lean.burntfen.com/app/index.html#&quot;&gt;Lean&lt;/a&gt; working yesterday, which was ultimately a failure. That is more of a to do list program - and the past few months have taught me that my best days as far as productivity goes are days I use a pen and a paper, in an old fashioned list.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How do you keep a list of what you do each day? How do you organise your tasks having been done?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Poem: Copyright</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-14/11-47-copyright"/>
   <updated>2013-12-14T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-12-14/11-47-copyright</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I can never remember the alt key for the © symbol.&lt;br /&gt;
I looked it up.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s alt + g.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m gonna write that in a poem.&lt;br /&gt;
And by write it in a poem&lt;br /&gt;
I mean open up a text editor&lt;br /&gt;
And type that one line.&lt;br /&gt;
And this one, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I’m going to put this on my blog now. &lt;br /&gt;
And by put it on my blog,&lt;br /&gt;
I mean spend thirty minutes trying to get Ruby&lt;br /&gt;
To understand the copyright symbol in Markdown&lt;br /&gt;
I think it’s ampersand copy semicolon&lt;br /&gt;
But I can’t remember&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SadYoungMan.com</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-26/13-59-sadyoungmancom"/>
   <updated>2013-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-26/13-59-sadyoungmancom</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I recently bought &lt;a href=&quot;http://sadyoungman.com&quot;&gt;sadyoungman.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have no idea what to do with it. For a month it just redirected here. Now I have a picture up, at least.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I tried to make the back-end code as minimal as possible. https://github.com/RichardLitt/sad-young-man&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thoughts?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mellow Pages Secret Spy Library - An Email from peterbd99</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-26/09-19-mellow-pages-secret-spy-library-an-email-from-peterbd99"/>
   <updated>2013-11-26T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-26/09-19-mellow-pages-secret-spy-library---an-email-from-peterbd99</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;So, the same day I completed the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burntfen.com/projects/2013/11/25/16-17-mellow-pages-library/&quot;&gt;previous blog post&lt;/a&gt; about making the Mellow Pages Library site, I got an email from a mysterious email account I have never encountered before, called peterbd99. The title of the email was “richard littauer part I of III: the secret spy”.  It appears to be my post from yesterday… slightly edited. This was easily the most confusing email I have ever gotten. After some googling, it seems that peterbd99 is the Banksy of email art - he’s done this to a lot of people. I kind of feel, honored?, by having such a confusing experience bestowed upon me. The text is reproduced below.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;sometime in the past few weeks richard (richie rich for short) discovered that, across from his local morgan place l subway stop, the mellow pages library was actually a pretty cool place where he could get his secret spy on and whatnot. he’d been in it a few times before, mostly to see if anything was happening and also to check his secret spy email that only a true secret spy can access. nothing ever was happening when he walked in; he missed out on the fact that this was part of the allure. mellow pages is a free, collective library where secret spies can be themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;they do events at night, sometimes, and there’s free coffee and couches to hang out on, but the main thing to notice is the stacks and stacks of spy books. to become a secret spy member, you can drop off ten books to loan to the library, murder one of jacob and matt’s enemies or pay $20 for a yearly membership. then you can check out as much as you want after you’re done cleaning up your extra secretive spy mess. you can’t hang out as long as you want, and you technically need to be a member to even knock on the door. matt (blond haired chill bro) and jacob (long haired bro who needs to work on his chilling), the founders, a pair of gangly bearded hipsters who seem to spend their days beneath red eyes, illegal activity, and cigarette smoke, matt reading some sort of poetry book in the couch in the corner and jacob laughing at a youtube clip while telling a patron in the corner to shut the fuck up, are fixtures just as much as the artpiece above one of the shelves that shows a dilophosaurus head on an 18th century woman’s body or the plethora of secret spies who secretly check out secret spy books (in secret).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;anyhoo, they’re pretty chill guys, and one day, after a poetry reading that featured a constant stream of the internal monologue of a jewish new yorker, a performance piece by an ex member of the kgb, and also some poetry about I95 in connecticut, richard asked if he could help in any way. he’d noticed abc of anarchism on one of the shelves, and figured the kind of library that had that on display was probably the kind of library that could use his secret spry help (sidenote: secret spies are required to read abc of anarchism unless they will remain in level 15 of spy training instead of moving on to level 16. richard jumped ahead to level 18 because he read abc of anarchism in a day and wrote a 10 page book report on it). they said they needed a website that only secret spies could access. he told them to give him a week. during that week, he was working pretty hard on his normal job at the central intelligence agency, but mostly he fell prey to mercury poisoning for the first time since someone from the putin regime tried to poison him in 2011, which knocked him out for three or four days but he wasn’t sweating it cause real gs dgaf about something as trivial as mercury poisoning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;finally, on sunday, sitting like a pimp in the library, richie rich spent around 4 hours and made them what is currently up at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mellowpageslibrary.com&quot;&gt;mellowpageslibrary.com&lt;/a&gt;. he’s pretty proud of it - mostly the fact that the logo was reproduced in css, that he used bootstrap 3, and that he managed to make that work well with jekyll and github pages much faster than i had anticipated (that’s top secret coding spy lingo for those of you who are technologically illiterate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘practice makes perfect, i guess’  richard littauer once wisely said. so, that’s his newest project. he’ll probably tweak the website over the coming few months during his breaks from hacking into chinese intelligence or karate chopping someone evil james bond style - adding a calendar, that sort of thing. but it’s there, and it’s done, and he is going to be sitting off the side of the frame of the background picture for many days to come, coding away or reading poetry or watching as his secret spy bank account grows due to millions of secret spy money being deposited into his spy account or generally enjoying the place. it’s the kind of place where that’s easy to do. super spy richard littauer likes that.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mellow Pages Library</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-25/16-17-mellow-pages-library"/>
   <updated>2013-11-25T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-25/16-17-mellow-pages-library</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Sometime in the past few weeks I discovered that, across from my local Morgan Place L subway stop, the Mellow Pages Library was actually a pretty cool place. I’d been in it a few times before, mostly to see if anything was happening. Nothing ever was when I walked in; I missed out on the fact that this was part of the allure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mellow Pages is a free, collective library. They do events at night, sometimes, and there’s free coffee and couches to hang out on, but the main thing to notice is the stacks and stacks of books. To become a member, you can drop off ten books to loan to the library, or pay $20 for a yearly membership. Then you can check out as much as you want. You can also hang out as long as you want, but you don’t technically need to be a member to do that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Matt and Jacob, the founders, a pair of gangly bearded hipsters who seem to spend their days beneath red eyes and cigarette smoke, Matt reading some sort of poetry book in the couch in the corner and Jacob laughing at a Youtube clip while trying to write in the ther corner, are fixtures just as much as the artpiece above one of the shelves that shows a dilophosaurus head on an 18th century woman’s body. They’re pretty chill guys, and one day, after a poetry reading that featured a constant stream of the internal monologue of a Jewish New Yorker and also some poetry about I95 in Connecticut, I asked if I could help in any way. I’d noticed ABC of Anarchism on one of the shelves, and figured the kind of library that had that on display was probably the kind of library that could use help.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They said they needed a website. I said give me a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During that week, I was working pretty hard on my normal job at Ideapod, but mostly I fell prey to tonsillitis for the first time in two years, which knocked me out for three or four days. Finally, on Sunday, sitting in the library, I spent around 4 hours and made them what is currently up at &lt;a href=&quot;http://mellowpageslibrary.com&quot;&gt;Mellowpageslibrary.com&lt;/a&gt;. I’m pretty proud of it - mostly the fact that the logo was reproduced in CSS, that I used Bootstrap 3, and that I managed to make that work well with Jekyll and Github Pages much faster than I had anticipated. Practice makes perfect, I guess.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that’s my newest project. I’ll probably tweak the website over the coming few months - adding a calendar, that sort of thing. But it’s there, and it’s done, and I’m going to be sitting off the side of the frame of the background picture for many days to come, coding away or reading poetry or generally enjoying the place. It’s the kind of place where that’s easy to do. I like that.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>On Petition Emails</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-21/16-10-on-petition-emails"/>
   <updated>2013-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-11-21/16-10-on-petition-emails</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I sign a lot of petitions. It takes me around 5 seconds due to 1Password. I don’t mind doing it. What I don’t like is being sick for a couple of days and finding 100 emails in my inbox. I don’t like that. That is a thing I don’t like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the one hand, being a citizen in a democratic society means that I have to utilise my voice as much as possible, as no one will make me speak up, and any silence I have will mean complicit agreement. So, I try to remember to vote, to buy certain items, to call my senators. Petitions are a small way to have other people make sure my voice is heard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On days like today, though, I feel like their worth is meaningless. When I get emails to sign 25 in a day, what is the use of signing any of them? I want to sign petitions I care about, not just every petition sent to me from every petition site I’ve ever visited. But I don’t have the time to sort through them. Worse, I never feel like they’ve done anything with my name, because I get very little positive feedback, very few emails saying ‘we did it, thanks to you.’ In truth, I do get some emails that say that - but, more often than not, the rest of the email deals with the next big hurdle, or with pleas for donations, or requests to sign petitions saying ‘thank you’ to someone. And I’m tired of being asked for money from people and organisations because I happen to agree with them that veterans should be kept off the streets, that women should have the right to choose, that having a safety net of insurance isn’t such a bad idea. I don’t like being asked to share images on Facebook, or Twitter, because I don’t like preaching to my friends. I don’t like sharing my political views with them because I’ve found that politics kills friendships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I wish there was a way to delete all of the text from emails asking for money, but keep the link to sign a petition. I wish there was a way to keep all of the hyperbole out of any sort of email from an interest group, because I want a logical argument for once. I wish there was a decent feedback mechanism for voicing your political agency. I wish no one ever told me “You’re almost done! Now share this with your friends on Facebook,” because I am already done - I signed with my name.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Does anyone else wish that?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Another Monday</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-09-16/12-15-another-monday"/>
   <updated>2013-09-16T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-09-16/12-15-another-monday</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I sit down at my work station, open up my laptop with stickers on it from Dinosaur Comics, go downstairs and back again with a fresh free Bluebottle coffee, say hello to some of the coworkers in the office today, take off my new dinner jacket I wore today because I wanted to imagine that the side glances on the subway are for a good reason and not a bad one, call my senator briefly to complain about the NSA, open up the issues on Github related to Angular and the Ideapod front end, put on “Closer than This” on Spotify by St. Lucia, and think to myself; this is the life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;git add all_these_thoughts  
git commit -am &quot;25th Birthday Post, short and to the point&quot;  
git push origin master  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Laserspews</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-27/23-42-laserspews"/>
   <updated>2013-07-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-27/23-42-laserspews</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;In January, I was asked to describe the plot of a film. Instead, I used a transparent text editor, and wrote my thoughts about the film while I watched it on the same computer. I’ve done the same for every film I’ve watched alone, excepting 1, Men in Black, since. Since I didn’t want to release the scripts too early, as I’m trying to stick with projects longer, I waited until an arbitrary number were done - 27.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://laserspews.tumblr.com/&quot;&gt;http://laserspews.tumblr.com/&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of it like Mystery Science Theatre, but without having the movie at the same time, and literally whatever comes into my head. The most commented was The Notebook. The Hunter was my favourite. The title came from a thought I had in the middle of Footloose. Check out the &lt;a href=&quot;http://laserspews.tumblr.com/archive&quot;&gt;archive&lt;/a&gt; for more.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please feel free to share this, to suggest films, and to call me out for any weird comments. This is an experiment.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Devil's Beating His Wife... and a poem.</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-14/22-23-the-devils-beating-his-wife-and-a-poem"/>
   <updated>2013-07-14T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-14/22-23-the-devils-beating-his-wife-and-a-poem</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Here are some excerpts from a journal entry in New York.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Americana calls me in. She spits out cliches - “Regular food for regular people” - and makes me want her anyway. So, here I sit, 7:00 at night, waiting for a Daft Punk imitation gig, at a Diner in a city of endless coffee options. The coffee isn’t that bad; but I think of epithets for it. “Great for sharpening teeth,” or, “Cure for Athlete’s foot - apply liberally.” I cover my stale fries in mayo. The pouring rain applauds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An old man approaches the waitress. “Do me a favor - when the check comes, only me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A city is a million cities. The boundaries bleed into each other. We’ve given a name to an idea, an abstraction to maintain cohesiveness. There is no New York - legislative zones are protocols for the real thing, a multiplicity of conceptualizations. 8 million spirits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I wonder if the souls passing through the windows of the hospitals and sick beds to heaven get mangled in the AC unit,” I said, at three am.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Do you want to get married,” she asks, curious.&lt;br /&gt;
“A few times,” I reply. “I guess I’ve never valued the sanctity of marriage.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Outside, the devil’s beating his wife. Who was she, I wonder? What was she like? Did they meet one fine morning? What did his sweet-blooded lips promise here? Did he reek of bourbon, even then? Did she wear a white dress at the wedding? Did she, bare-assed, make eggs in the morning, the pan spitting drops of oil on his borrowed, Swedish sweater? Did she love him back for his cleverness? Did she once enjoy his company? Does she sit on the veranda on summer evenings and wait for him to come home? What was her name?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Morsi, go firmly to the window and listen! What God abandons me now? What crowds cheer for me? What invisible procession?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trying to find a path &lt;br /&gt;
through the forest of bloodshot trees&lt;br /&gt;
set against the cloudy sclerae of your eyes.&lt;br /&gt;
Your pupil is a lunar eclipse.&lt;br /&gt;
Behind that black disc&lt;br /&gt;
you’ve got stars in your eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just had breakfast with redacted. She woke me up at around 7 with incessant pleas.&lt;br /&gt;
“Everything is happening!”&lt;br /&gt;
“Not me.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Gittip</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-13/17-48-gittip"/>
   <updated>2013-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-13/17-48-gittip</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Today I learned about &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gittip.com/&quot;&gt;Gittip&lt;/a&gt; from my good pal &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gittip.com/simonv3&quot;&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a pretty sweet idea. You give people a set tip per week if you like there stuff - as small as 25¢ - and then they can get tipped from that. Very simple. Go check it out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s mine, if, you, you know, like my work. https://www.gittip.com/richlitt/&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LAGBSC: Moving On</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-13/17-29-lagbsc"/>
   <updated>2013-07-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-13/17-29-lagbsc</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Just now I sent my resignation email to the Linguistics Association of Great Britain Student Committee. I’ve been a member of the LAGBSC for something like three years, since I was a student in Edinburgh studying Linguistics, bright eyed and working on a thesis on evolutionary linguistics. I’ve come a long way since those conversations with the then president Penny, from talking to David Arnold over tea and coffee about what the LAGB could be to students, and what we could do for academia. One of the outcomes of these conversations was, of course, the Undergraduate Linguistics Association of Britain, an organisation me and David Arnold founded for students in Britain to present work of theirs and connect to other Linguistics undergrads. ULAB recently had it’s third annual conference, and seems to be going strong, for which I am immensely proud. Part of that was success came from help from the LAGBSC and the LAGB itself, who offered advice and occasionally conference funds. They helped fly me to Bristol to see the second conference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently, the LAGBSC for me meant simply signing off on emails. I’ve been living outside of Britain for two years now, and I am not necessarily continueing on in academia at the moment, as I am pursueing a career in web development. As such, I’ve felt increasingly like I was filling a position that someone else could fill better. I hope that someone does, and I look forward to seeing how the LAGB continues to thrive and how the LAGBSC continues to cater to student needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On that note, I’m trying to get more involved in the LSA COSIAC - Linguistics Society of America Committee on Student Issues and Concerns. So, it looks like I’m just finally accepting that I am, at last, American. Academia is very much a Hotel California, that way - you can check out any time you like, but you can never leave…&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>LCT Graduation Talk</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-12/00-28-lct-graduation-talk"/>
   <updated>2013-07-12T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-12/00-28-lct-graduation-talk</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I was one of the speakers at the recent Language and Communication Technologies Graduation ceremony at the University of Saarland, in which many of my good friends finally got their two year degrees. Here is the speech I gave, minus some adlibbed lines.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Hello everyone. It’s an honor for me, as the LCT student and alumni representative, to be able to stand here and talk to you - but as I’m fully aware of how hot it is in here, I’ll try to keep this brief. It was hard to format this speech - and we can tell that from the varying topics of the previous speeches. The uncanny valley, praises for Coli, and the four major challenges that face us. I’m going to try to focus on you guys and what I think CoLi is, but bear with me if it sounds a bit vague.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Going back through Nils Lenke’s talk this morning, there were several themes which I thought were worth mentioning here. One of them was the applicability of a Computational Linguistics degree - “I hired you not because of your Coli degree, but in spite of it!” I’m sure that everyone who has studied Computational Linguistics has had this crisis before when applying for a job or for a research position - am I a digital humanities scholar, or am I a computer scientist? It isn’t always clear.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;I think the main area where the vagueness of our degree comes into play is in daily conversations. How many of you have been asked, “So what does a computational linguist do?” To which the standard reply, or at least mine, is “Well, google, information extraction, voice stuff, Siri…” The trouble isn’t thinking of use cases, but rather thinking of an overarching theme to those cases. Saying ‘the interface between language and computers’ may be too broad - and, in any case, one could argue that the first linguist to invent writing (before computers) was, in some sense, a language technologist. For me, the one theme that defines a computational linguist is someone who intelligently tries to understand language, by whatever means necessary.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Often, this work is under-appreciated, because we work behind the scenes. You could sum up computational linguistics as a field by HTC’s motto - ‘quietly brilliant’. We work hard trying to make things work so that normal people - users - don’t have to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Ok, this is great speculation, but where am I going with this? What I want to draw attention to is that, first, and foremost, we’re thinkers, tinkerers, hackers, makers, and fixers - often of small pieces of code, of processes running behind the scenes.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;And it is this that will carry us forward - into academia, or into business, or into other fields. The degrees being handed out today are pieces of paper - what is important is that they show that the graduates have learned to be experts at finding solutions for language problems. And I hope that, going forth from today, they utilize all of the skills they learned in these two years.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;No one has ever fixed a novel problem by knowing the solution before hand - in each case, it takes ingenuity to solve problems. More, it takes education - learning how to learn, and how to solve. It takes humility to recognize that we are foolish approaching problems, but that “sucking at something is the first step towards being sort of good at something,” to quote the popular American Adventure Time. And what I want to impart here is what Steve Jobs tried to impart, in the now immortal phrase, “Stay hungry. Stay foolish.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But these thoughts are cumbersome, and, to quote Odysseus, “I am not an eloquent speaker.” So I guess that’s most of what I have to say. The last thing is this: Congratulations to the graduating class, and I wish you the best.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Thanks&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jen Kinney's new photography portfolio site...</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-09/15-33-jen-kinneys-new-photography-portfolio-site"/>
   <updated>2013-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-09/15-33-jen-kinneys-new-photography-portfolio-site</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I was in New York city on June 19th for an &lt;a href=&quot;www.ideapod.com&quot;&gt;Ideapod&lt;/a&gt; function, coding like a madman, pulling two 16 hour days back to back after getting off the plane from a weekend in Barcelona. I was more than a little stressed, but the presentation went by, and we got some compliments for it. Walking up the stairs towards the open bar after the applause, completely drained, this tall girl I had noticed in the crowd but didn’t know came up to me and asked, “Graham?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It took my around five seconds to remember that Graham was the name I went by in high school (I switched to my first name, Richard, seven years ago), and that I knew the girl. Her name was Jen Kinney, and we hadn’t talked since I graduated half a decade ago. She had known another one of the people who spoke, and had been completely surprised to see me there as a coder, or indeed, there at all. We swapped numbers and agreed to hang out.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The next day, we sat down in Tompkins Square Park in the East Village for an hour. She whipped out a microphone, so there’s a recording around there somewhere (which I’ll have to get from her, and edit accordingly), and we talked about where our lives had taken us. Jen had graduated from Kingswood-Oxford and gone on to do a Photography degree at NYU, doing a few fun projects along the way. One of these was about to happen again - she was leaving in two weeks for Alaska, to make a photo documentary book about a town called Whittier. Whittier is interesting because it is only accessible by a 2.5 mile long train tunnel, it was built and largely abandoned by the military, and 85% of the town lives in one tower block. Jen had spent the summer there once, and now had a grant to go back. I agreed that that was pretty cool. She dropped in the conversation, somewhere, that she needed a website for this, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two weeks later, a couple of short meetings at her place and at her goodbye party in Brooklyn, I’ve got her website up. I spent a bit too long trying to do a complicated jQuery thing that really wasn’t necessary, so that on the whole, it took around 10 hours to make. I still think it’s fun, if only because of her pictures. There’ll be more updates soon. Regarding the design, Jen actually had a whole .pdf of designs from Illustrator, so all I had to do was code up the site and figure out the architecture. Together, I think it works pretty well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Check out her amazing photography at &lt;a href=&quot;http://jakinney.com&quot;&gt;jakinney.com&lt;/a&gt;. I really suggest it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Publication: Language Documentation Review</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-09/15-25-new-publication-language-documentation-review"/>
   <updated>2013-07-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-07-09/15-25-new-publication-language-documentation-review</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;A new book review of mine was published the other week, in Linguist List. Here are the details:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Richard Littauer (2013). &lt;em&gt;Review of F. Seifart, G. Haig, N. Himmelmann, D. Jung, A. Margetts, &amp;amp; P. Trilsbeek, eds., Potentials of Language Documentation: Methods, Analyses, and Utilization. In: Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation Special Publication No. 3. Online: University of Hawai’i Press.&lt;/em&gt; In: &lt;em&gt;LINGUIST List&lt;/em&gt;, 24.2604. &lt;a href=&quot;http://linguistlist.org/pubs/reviews/get-review.cfm?SubID=12670360&quot;&gt;URL&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a fun book to read, and it is also free. I suggest browsing through the LDCJ if you are interested in low resource languages.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Publication: People's Web Meets NLP</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-30/08-11-new-publication-peoples-web-meets-nlp"/>
   <updated>2013-04-30T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-30/08-11-new-publication-peoples-web-meets-nlp</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve got a book somewhere in the world that has a chapter with my name as one of the authors. This is a new experience for me. It was fun to work on, mainly because I got to interact with the Open Linguistics people in the OKF. Most of the content of the book chapter is a bit over my head, which is why I’m last author - I basically helped where I could. Still, pretty nifty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the book announcement I recieved in my inbox yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;BOOK ANNOUNCEMENT&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The People’s Web Meets NLP: Collaboratively Constructed Language Resources&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Iryna Gurevych and Jungi Kim (Eds.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Series: Theory and Applications of Natural Language Processing, E. Hovy, M. Johnson and G. Hirst (eds.)
2013, XXIV, 378 p. 86 illus., 16 illus. in color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.springer.com/978-3-642-35084-9&quot;&gt;http://www.springer.com/978-3-642-35084-9&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Collaboratively Constructed Language Resources (CCLRs) such as Wikipedia, Wiktionary, Linked Open Data, and various resources developed using crowdsourcing techniques such as Games with a Purpose and Mechanical Turk have substantially contributed to the research in natural language processing (NLP). Various NLP tasks utilize such resources to substitute for or supplement conventional lexical semantic resources and linguistically annotated corpora. These resources also provide an extensive body of texts from which valuable knowledge is mined. There are an increasing number of community efforts to link and maintain multiple linguistic resources.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book offers comprehensive coverage of CCLR-related topics, including their construction, utilization in NLP tasks, and interlinkage and management. Various Bachelor/Master/Ph.D. programs in natural language processing, computational linguistics, and knowledge discovery can use this book both as either main textbook or supplementary reading. The book also provides a valuable reference guide for researchers and professionals for the above topics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keywords &amp;gt; Collaboratively Constructed Resource - Collective Intelligence / Human Computation - Computational Linguistics - Language Resource - Natural Language Processing&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Your online footprint is dirty.</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-19/09-25-your-online-footprint-is-dirty"/>
   <updated>2013-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-19/09-25-your-online-footprint-is-dirty</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I got an email this morning from &lt;a href=&quot;http://jobs.sciencecareers.org&quot;&gt;ScienceCareers&lt;/a&gt;. It said that I hadn’t signed onto my profile in 730 days, and that my profile was going to be deleted. I remember signing up, when I was leaving uni in Edinburgh and trying to figure out what I was doing. At the time, I was thinking about pursuing a career as a digital librarian, or a data scientists, and I was looking around all over the place for cool jobs that weren’t necessarily related to Linguistics but still allowed me to say that I did stuff “for science”, like XKCD. That’s how I signed onto ecolog, a mailing list with over 20k users, tons of emails a day, which I followed until around January this year. That’s how I got my internship with DataONE that I had my summer between uni and grad school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that isn’t necessarily me anymore. I’m still interested in Science, but I’m less likely to find a job on a website like Science Careers. I’m more likely to know the PI or prof I’m actually interested in working with. This is because I’ve invested lots of time and energy in research and networking over the past few years, and less in searching the annals of the internet for random jobs that might be cool, one day, maybe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What bothers me is that I get this sort of email all of the time. If you look at the links I’ve chosen to display for social networks on my &lt;a href=&quot;/about.html&quot;&gt;about&lt;/a&gt; page, it’s a bit ridiculous. There’s around 20 or 30, and that’s not even counting the links for organisations I have in the basically blue colored paragraph below that. Every day I get emails from some of them. I just got an email telling me I had a new follower on Twitter. I have around 700 followers on Twitter. I’ve received an email (or a joint email) for every one of them. My lists folder at the moment has around 2000 unread emails in it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why is this dirty? Because I’ve got to clean it up. The more websites I’ve signed up for, the more emails I get, the more my name is tossed around. The problem is that they don’t go away. 730 days is nothing on the internet. But the amount of time it took me to delete my account on Science Careers (ironically, after registering for a new password) - that’s something to me. When it’s added on to all of the other things I need to check my inbox for today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tl;dr don’t sign up for things and unsubscribe when you can.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EMLCT Masters Call for Students</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-17/15-16-emlct-masters-call"/>
   <updated>2013-04-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-17/15-16-emlct-masters-call</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The programme I am currently on is inviting applications for the coming year. If you know of anyone who might be interested, take a look! Alternatively, there are a load of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.em-a.eu/en/erasmus-mundus/erasmus-mundus-master-courses.html&quot;&gt;other Erasmus Mundus Masters&lt;/a&gt; available. From what I’ve heard, they’re all great. Mine is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;##To prospective Master students&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Erasmus Mundus Masters Program in Language and Communication Technologies (EMMLCT) &lt;a href=&quot;http://lct-master.org&quot;&gt;http://lct-master.org&lt;/a&gt; invites applications from both European and non-European students for start in fall 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key facts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;in-depth instruction in computational linguistics methods and technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;teaching as well as academic and administrative support in English&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;duration 2 years (120 ECTS credits)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;study one year each at two different partner universities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;double degree&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Deadline for applications is May 1, 2013.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Program fees: 4000 Euro for students from the EU; 8000 Euro for non-EU students (per academic year).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EMMLCT program is offered by the following consortium of Universities:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Saarland University in Saarbruecken, Germany (coordinator)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Trento, Trento, Italy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Malta, Malta&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;University of Lorraine, Nancy, France&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Charles University, Prague, Czech Republic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Rijksuniversiteit Groningen, The Netherlands&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Shanghai Jiao Tong University, China&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The University of Melbourne, Australia&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The University of the Basque Country, San Sebastian, Spain&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####The EMMLCT Program in Brief&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EMMLCT program is an international distributed Master of Science course. It provides students with profound knowledge and insight into the various disciplines that contribute to the methods of language and communication technologies (also known as computational linguistics or natural language processing) and it strengthens their ability to work according to scientific methods. Moreover, the students acquire practice-oriented knowledge by choosing appropriate combinations of modules in Language Technology, Computational and Theoretical Linguistics, and Computer Science. The course is designed to meet the demands of industry and research in a rapidly growing area and offers education and training opportunities for the next generations of leaders in research and innovation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program involves studying one year each at two different Universities of the consortium. After completing all study requirements the students obtain two already approved Master of Science/Arts degrees with legal value in the countries of issue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The course consists of compulsory core modules, as well as elective advanced modules in Language Technology and Computer Science, optionally complemented by a project, and completed by a Master Thesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The EMMLCT program is approved and supported by the Erasmus Mundus Program of the European Union. More information: &lt;a href=&quot;http://ec.europa.eu/education/external-relation-programmes/mundus_en.htm&quot;&gt;http://ec.europa.eu/education/external-relation-programmes/mundus_en.htm&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://eacea.ec.europa.eu/erasmus_mundus/&quot;&gt;http://eacea.ec.europa.eu/erasmus_mundus/&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;####Application requirements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All applicants must satisfy the following prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Degree: a Bachelor degree or equivalent in the area of (Computational) Linguistics, Language Technology, Cognitive Sciences, Computer Science, Mathematics, Artificial Intelligence, or other relevant disciplines. The degree must be completed before the course starts.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Language proficiency: Proof of proficiency in English is required for  applicants whose native language is other than English.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Application is made online. Further information and application instructions: &lt;a href=&quot;http://lct-master.org&quot;&gt;http://lct-master.org&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact email address for further inquiries: lct-info at coli.uni-sb.de&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Program coordination:&lt;br /&gt;
Prof. Hans Uszkoreit&lt;br /&gt;
Dr. Ing. Ivana Kruijff-Korbayova&lt;br /&gt;
Department of Computational Linguistics and Phonetics&lt;br /&gt;
Saarland University&lt;br /&gt;
Saarbruecken, Germany&lt;br /&gt;
http://lct-master.org&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Not an update, but an overhaul</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-13/14-10-not-an-update-but-an-overhaul"/>
   <updated>2013-04-13T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2013-04-13/14-10-not-an-update-but-an-overhaul</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Well, as you may have noticed, I completely reworked this site. A few reasons why - I’m a front end developer now, and I was kind of ashamed of the inherently bootstrappy feel of the last site. This should be a bit better. I’m also tired of updating this blog and then burntfen.com. So, I’ve integrated them together. This site will be moved over to that address (as well as rlittauer.com), as well, so this is a major consolidation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Also, I really didn’t feel like the old sites showed everything as well as they could. I kept a few things - for instance, the movable buttons beneath my profile, which is kind of a UX disaster, but I like the dynamic nature of it. I like the top bar off of this much more, and I like using Font Awesome to get the icons down. You can probably tell that this is based loosely (or not) on &lt;a href=&quot;zachholman.com&quot;&gt;Zach Holman’s site&lt;/a&gt;. I like it. I also like my little oval image at the top. Seems cool.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve also reorganised the way I was mentally viewing posts. Expect less pages, and more posts. I’m far too changeable to keep updated pages and pages of things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alright, with that done, I can start blogging again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Expect more.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Some more site updates</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-12-18/14-01-some-more-site-updates"/>
   <updated>2012-12-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-12-18/14-01-some-more-site-updates</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been working hard at some other projects the past two days (one of
which is re-reading all of &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/The_Wheel_of_Time&quot;&gt;the Wheel of
Time&lt;/a&gt; before &lt;em&gt;A Memory
of Light&lt;/em&gt;, the last book, comes out), but I have also managed to fill in
a few more pages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One is the &lt;a href=&quot;/projects.html&quot;&gt;Projects&lt;/a&gt; page, where I give a brief list of
projects I am currently involved with elsewhere on the web - most
notably, &lt;a href=&quot;http://unexus.org&quot;&gt;Unexus&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://wyrdin.com&quot;&gt;Wyrd In&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;http://ideaotter.com&quot;&gt;IdeaOtter&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve also filled out the &lt;a href=&quot;/language-resource-dev.html&quot;&gt;Language
Development&lt;/a&gt; Projects page, where I talk
about &lt;a href=&quot;http://de.clarin.eu&quot;&gt;CLARIN&lt;/a&gt;, and
&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RichardLitt/lrl/tree/master/Maltese&quot;&gt;Kelmu&lt;/a&gt; and my
Learn Na’vi projects, like &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RichardLitt/keypuk-ninavi&quot;&gt;translating
Facebook&lt;/a&gt; into a language
only a couple of dozen people can actually speak semi-fluently.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re interested in collaboration, because you want to go to Sofia,
too, let me know. I’m just a click or two away.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Reworking this site</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-12-17/02-39-reworking-this-site"/>
   <updated>2012-12-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-12-17/02-39-reworking-this-site</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I have discontinued use of my old blog, as I haven’t posted there in
months. However, there was a feature on that blog, and on my old
notebook system where I had a locally-installed Wordpress, which I
rather miss - namely, project pages. I haven’t had a page which keeps
track of all of my various projects and my various lines of research,
something which is necessary for me to keep track of all of my
activities. Yesterdy morning at 4, after trying to bang something out in
text to figure out how I was going to submit papers worth reading to
NAACL-HLT and ACL, I realised I needed to make a new site to keep track
of things again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I’ve revamped this one today, and it only took me around 10 hours or
so. I’ve redone the navigation bar, as you can see, and I’ve created
pages for each of the research areas I am interested in. In each page is
a list of the subtopics, within that area, that I would like to, have,
or am currently researching. For projects, I’ve listed projects I am
currently on, ones I do for fun, and those I do for language
development. I am going to fill these pages out, in time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are pages I wrote tonight:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richardlitt.github.com/about.html&quot;&gt;About&lt;/a&gt; this site and me&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richardlitt.github.com/art.html&quot;&gt;Art&lt;/a&gt; that I do&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://richardlitt.github.com/fun-stuff.html&quot;&gt;Fun projects&lt;/a&gt; I’ve
done or do currently.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I will work on filling the others out, and hopefully, this site will
function as a much more lively place for me to show research that I am
doing, on a daily basis. This may seem vain or self-important, in that I
am releasing all of this information into the public domain - for me, I
think that the benefits from other people seeing projects I am working
on and possible collaborations coming from that, as well as the benefit
of feeling connected to a community and being able to use web interfaces
and grab information I need whenever far outweigh any negative
reprecussions of having so much information online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking forward to seeing much more use of this site, now that this
step of completely moving over has occurred. I suspect that, when
January rolls around, I will move the &lt;a href=&quot;rlittauer.com&quot;&gt;Burnt Fen&lt;/a&gt; over
here, as well. Simplify, simplify.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Twitter Signal to Noise Application?</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-18/11-38-twitter-signal-to-noise-application"/>
   <updated>2012-11-18T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-18/11-38-twitter-signal-to-noise-application</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;An interesting post ran across my twitter feed this morning:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;cortesi: I want a tool that calculates the cost of following a Twitter user. Something like volume* signal/noise…&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I started thinking
that this is something you could do automatically. Cortesi seems to
already be working on a side project that would add a &lt;em&gt;like&lt;/em&gt; button to
tweets, so that he can manually manage which ones he likes and help the
program predict more. I think that this is a good way to go, but the
data deluge may get exhausting training wise, and it depends upon too
much of a conscious choice on the part of the tweeter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead, it might be worthwhile making a program that logs:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you follow a link on a tweet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you reply to a tweet&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you follow someone new&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;when you unfollow someone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;what percentage, of all of these, for each user.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combined, this should work fairly well to let the app know what sort of
information you like on your feed. It doesn’t work for self-contained
tweets which you enjoy, however - in that case, the manual system,
worked out by cortesi, would be best. But still, this would be a major
bootstrapper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m thinking about how I would do it. I would log links followed using a
browser add-on - I’m not sure if Twitter development code allows you to
log followed links (anyone know?) I would also do a simple reply
search to log that, again using the Twitter api. And then perhaps some
basic NLP on those posts to see what sort of thing I’m replying.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would you do it?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Richard Littauer, Poet.</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-17/17-57-richard-littauer-poet"/>
   <updated>2012-11-17T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-17/17-57-richard-littauer-poet</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I recieved a book in the mail today, called &lt;a href=&quot;http://code-poems.com/book.html&quot;&gt;Code {Poems}&lt;/a&gt;. 
It is the 54th copy out of 100 copies printed in the first edition. 
On page 18, the following is written:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;IMPORT SOUL  

# This script should save lives  

import soul  

for days in len(life):  
  print happiness  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the bottom of the page is my name, and beneath it, &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;// Python&lt;/code&gt;, 
the language the poem is written in This marks the first time that I’ve
seen my name in print in a book or a journal of poetry that wasn’t
connected to my educational establishment - in short, today is the first
day I am officially a published poet.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://24.media.tumblr.com/tumblr_mdn69mtFkQ1qeqp7go1_500.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Me and the book&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To learn more about the book, or to order a copy, go &lt;a href=&quot;http://code-poems.com/book.html&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Wroclaw Barcamp</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-10/12-04-wroclaw-barcamp"/>
   <updated>2012-11-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-10/12-04-wroclaw-barcamp</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Last weekend I had the opportunity to go to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://barcampwroclaw.org/&quot;&gt;Barcamp in Wroclaw&lt;/a&gt;.
A barcamp is an &lt;em&gt;un&lt;/em&gt;-conference event, made more for audience
participation than for scheduled talks. This Barcamp was organised by
the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.unexus.org/team&quot;&gt;Unexus Team&lt;/a&gt;, which means that I had
the chance to hang out out with Justin Brown and Mark Bakacs, the two founders of Unexus, 
and also  with&lt;a href=&quot;http://johan.janssens.me/&quot;&gt;Johan Johanssens&lt;/a&gt;, cofounder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.joomla.org&quot;&gt;Joomla&lt;/a&gt;,
as well as the current founder of &lt;a href=&quot;http://nooku.org/&quot;&gt;Nooku&lt;/a&gt;. Justin and
Mark were the ones who enabled me to come; I am now on board as the new
front-end developer for Unexus, which means I will be helping to develop
the user experience for a social network website with a lot of
potential. I’ll most likely be blogging more about that in the coming
months. I wasn’t able to meet Mark’s brother Pete, our designer, but I
am going to be working closely with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Barcamp itself lasted a day; there were around 30 people there, and
there were some pretty interesting talks. Most interesting, for me, was
Johan’s talk about FOSS, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Free_and_open-source_software&quot;&gt;Free and Open Source Software&lt;/a&gt;.
He started out with the tagline that &lt;em&gt;Open Source is
not like free beer&lt;/em&gt; - rather, &lt;em&gt;It’s free as in Freedom.&lt;/em&gt;
Another good talk for me was Kamil Rudniki’s presentation of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.timecamp.com/&quot;&gt;TimeCamp&lt;/a&gt;,
a time-tracking productivity software that started in the past few years
and already has a good client base. I’m going to be working with Kamil
to integrate my own &lt;a href=&quot;http://wyrdin.com&quot;&gt;Wired/Wyrd In&lt;/a&gt; startup with his.
Mine is more focused on task organisation and planning, while his is
much more about screen-tracking, like RescueTime, and time-tracking.
Together, along with tools like &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.trello.com&quot;&gt;Trello&lt;/a&gt;, we
should end up with a pretty solid product. Kamil gave me a ton of good
links to follow up, namely:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;www.timecamp.com/auth/register&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;www.visikid.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;www.timeandtracking.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;www.jerela.com&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://todotxt.com/&quot;&gt;Todo.txt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://letsfreckle.com/&quot;&gt;LetsFreckle&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johan also gave some good discussion of licensing models, something I’ve
been struggling with researching recently. Importantly, it seems that the
license of a software only becomes applicable when you distribute
the software. That only happens when the software goes from a copyright
holder to a non-copyright holder. In essence, Github is distribution. I
am going to have to move Wyrd In off of Github, soon, then - I’ll
probably set up a git repo on my own server to deal with it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And that was the weekend, in a nutshell. When I got back, I had a ton of
fresh ideas, a good perspective on what I am doing with Unexus, and a
cold. That’s alright though; it was worth it.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Appril</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-07/19-10-appril"/>
   <updated>2012-11-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-07/19-10-appril</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;My friend &lt;a href=&quot;http://piranhabay.co.uk/&quot;&gt;Simon&lt;/a&gt;, the coder and designer
who is the main guy behind &lt;a href=&quot;http://ideaotter.com/&quot;&gt;IdeaOtter&lt;/a&gt;, a project
we’ve been working on together, has had another pretty awesome idea:
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appril.org&quot;&gt;Appril&lt;/a&gt;.
Again, I helped out a tiny bit, but Simon works far too fast for me, so
the credit goes entirely to him. I’m looking forward to helping out in the coming
months prepare the site and the event. What am I talking about? Here’s
the blurb from his website.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appril.org&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://raw.github.com/RichardLitt/richardlitt.github.com/master/images/appril.png&quot; title=&quot;www.appril.org&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;About a week before Github launched their build-a-game competition, I was talking to a couple of friends about an idea I had. Github’s competition got our asses into gear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ve all attended hackathons, and while I like what they represent - what they achieve is often not much more than a concept roughly initiated. Really, to do something right you need more time. How much more time? That varies on what you’re doing. But I’m willing to bet that for most things it’s somewhere around a month. That’s enough to plan out your idea (find one if you haven’t already), get a team of people that you like together (if you want), learn your tools (if you want to learn new tools), and build that thing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So we want to initiate the first ever &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appril.org&quot;&gt;Appril&lt;/a&gt;. Come April, we’re going to get together in teams, and push ourselves to build the apps we’ve been meaning to build. Alongside whatever else we’re planning on doing that month.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know April is 5 months away, but man, wouldn’t it be great if a heck of a lot of people knew about this and participated. It’d be a 30 day hackathon taking place all over the world, and at the end of it, there’d be completed, fully functional, well thought out, applications.  And all the developers would be well rested at the end of it. That would be neat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, we’d love any help spreading the word.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Matthew 5:42</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-06/11-07-matthew-542"/>
   <updated>2012-11-06T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-11-06/11-07-matthew-542</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;For years, I have wanted to understand what christianity really is, so
that I can more accurately see why the community I grew up in fell so
short of the ideal they professed to believe in. This morning, I
realised that I had a few deep-seated issues which needed to be
addressed before I could actually read the bible again (the most
prominent of which was a strong feeling that my mother would burst out
of the closet and start crying that I was coming back into the fold,
and I would have to then awkwardly and vehemently disabuse her of that
notion). I decided, this morning is as good as any to get over these.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, I started reading Matthew. Most of the book passed by with just a
very raised eyebrow, until I got to this verse, and I had an idea:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The Book of Matthew, Chapter 5:38-42&lt;br /&gt;
38 “You have heard that it was said, ‘Eye for eye, and tooth for tooth.’&lt;br /&gt;
39 But I tell you, do not resist an evil person. If anyone slaps you on the right cheek, turn to them the other cheek also.&lt;br /&gt;
40 And if anyone wants to sue you and take your shirt, hand over your coat as well.&lt;br /&gt;
41 If anyone forces you to go one mile, go with them two miles.&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;b&gt;42 Give to the one who asks you, and do not turn away from the one who wants to borrow from you.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Needless to say, this is too good an opportunity to miss. So, I dug
up my paypal donate button from my old site. I then found out that you
need to be a registered charity to use that, and the chargebacks can be
annoying, and my ‘Shave-the-whales’ campaign probably isn’t a worthy
cause.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, my paypal name is also my email, richard dot littauer on gmail.&lt;br /&gt;
Please, if you’re a &lt;i&gt;true&lt;/i&gt; Christian, &lt;u&gt;examine your heart&lt;/u&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;give
generously&lt;/b&gt;. Consider this a formal proposition to all Christians for
monetary donations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you’re an atheist, agnostic, or follower of Shiva, bring some beer
when you come over and we can all have a good sacrilegious laugh later.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Computational Linguistics Examination Revision</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-25/23-21-computational-linguistics-examination-revision"/>
   <updated>2012-10-25T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-25/23-21-computational-linguistics-examination-revision</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;#Computational Linguistics&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are examination preparation notes from the slides for a course I took at the University of Saarland in Saarbrücken in the summer of 2012. The majority of the information here came from the slides for that course, which are available online, but not under any copyright. To save embarassment in case I mistype or misunderstood, I won’t cite the lecturers here. Much of this information can be found in better quality in Dan Jurafsky or Chris Mannings books, cited below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;../files/exam-revision&quot;&gt;That is all, I think.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Getting Mou to run in the terminal</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-24/13-12-getting-mou-to-run-in-the-terminal"/>
   <updated>2012-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-24/13-12-getting-mou-to-run-in-the-terminal</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I just tried to get Mou to run in the terminal. &lt;a href=&quot;http://mouapp.com/&quot;&gt;Mou&lt;/a&gt; is actually a pretty
lovely program that allows you to see what a document with Markdown
syntax looks like as you type it, something like an instant TeX
compiler. I use Markdown on this blog, and on Github Wikis, so it’s
proven useful. It’s the main reason I upgraded to Mountain Lion - I wish
I hadn’t, as they killed spaces, which in turn killed my entire
productivity flow. I look forward to more updates, as I can’t do other
things anymore, such as have a transparent vim workspace.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I just tried this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;sudo ln -s /Applications/Mou.app/Contents/MacOS/mou /usr/bin/mou
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This should have worked. Instead, I got this error:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;No Info.plist file in application bundle or no NSPrincipalClass in the Info.plist file, exiting
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I then tried using ‘echo test &amp;gt; test’ ‘open App…/mou test’. No dice,
as it instead opened test in mvim, and Mou opened nothing. So,
basically, I can’t open things from Mou in the terminal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, then I googled it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;open -a Mou test.md
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And we have it. For future reference, Richard, Google stuff first, you
knob.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Morphological induction</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-24/12-57-morphological-induction"/>
   <updated>2012-10-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-24/12-57-morphological-induction</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Thoughts while reading: S. Keshava &amp;amp; E. Pitler (2005). &lt;em&gt;A Simpler,
Intuitive Approach to Morpheme Induction&lt;/em&gt;. Proceedings of
Morphochallenge 2005, pp. 28-32.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Goldsmith 2001 seems to be used often to sum up morphological
induction - what’s the new must-read article for the past decade?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This paper was released around the same time as Morfessor 1.0. How do
they compare?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This isn’t good for Arabic or semitic languages (Maltese). How does
it compare to Poon et al, 2009, NAACL, &lt;em&gt;Unsupervised Morphological Segmentation with Log-Linear Models&lt;/em&gt;?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Paper idea&lt;/strong&gt;: using orthographically cleaned data, could one use historical knowledge of a language, perhaps by using Bayesian analysis of similar languages to find cognates, to bootstrap better morphological induction? Pitfalls, possibilities?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“The forward and backward trees allow us to calculate conditional probabilities in O(1) time…” What does this mean exactly?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What influence do multiword expressions or complicated NPs have on morphological analysis? Does &lt;em&gt;The Mayor of Boston’s Hat&lt;/em&gt; actually do anything?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;I’m sorry, but I think that using the argument that “19+1 is not arbitrary, as x / x+y = .05” is not a valid argument. .05 is also arbitrary. If you want to go for non-arbitrary, use human-evaluated morpheme to lexeme percentages.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What exactly do the other 20%, after 80%~ Recall and precision, look like? Are there regularities to the exceptions? Perhaps etymological / PoS / orthographical? Throwing out the baby with the bathwater.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;This paper was also run on Finnish. Morfessor was too. Going to have to read both.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;What about differences between derivational and inflectional morphemes?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Good example: &lt;em&gt;widen&lt;/em&gt; is &lt;em&gt;wid&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;en&lt;/em&gt;, which is missed by the script. Ideally, one should be able to know that long vowels shortened when there is a following syllabic morpheme (have I written/read this aright?). That should be testable given statistical regularities in Germanic roots or Bayesian inference of likely source language, followed by likely age, followed by intelligent morpheme induction that would treat &lt;em&gt;widen&lt;/em&gt; as both &lt;em&gt;wide&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;en&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;wid&lt;/em&gt; + &lt;em&gt;en&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;passionflowers&lt;/em&gt; is arguably on the cusp of being non-compositional. Morpheme induction for this is useful how, exactly?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Another Saffran quoting paper! &lt;strong&gt;I need to get that paper of mine out&lt;/strong&gt;. &lt;strong&gt;Now&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Read Yang 2004 in response to Saffran 1996.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Regarding &lt;em&gt;Future Work&lt;/em&gt;: What follow-ups have they had? Why didn’t they utilise Saffran &amp;amp; Aslin earlier, if they knew about it? What sort of phonological information would help them? Why don’t they use collocations? How would batch learning actually change the program recognition (opaque)?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;“While we do not claim that humans use our algorithm to segment words, we believe that further research along this line has potential to reveal insight into human language processing.” What sort of insight? What other algorithms would humans use? What about subconscious vs. conscious induction? What about linguistically-informed induction vs. first language acquisition? Isn’t it an error to lump all of these together?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Hafer and Weiss, 1974. &lt;em&gt;Word segmentation by Letter Successor Varities&lt;/em&gt;. Information Storage and Retrieval, 10:371-385. - might be worth reading.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As always, reader, if anything is interesting, don’t hesitate to get into contact.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Some Regex Fun</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-02/18-38-some-regex-fun"/>
   <updated>2012-10-02T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-10-02/18-38-some-regex-fun</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Recently I’ve been trying to do lists the long way instead of the longer
way. That is to say, if I have a chunk of text that I need to copy
somewhere, and it’s not in a good format, I take the time to figure out
the regex for it so that I get faster at using regex, rather than just
doing it manually. In some cases, this is far shorter - I recently
converted a very long dictionary easily after around thirty minutes
figuring out a regex for it. Just now, I did something similar, but I
could have just deleted some segments a lot faster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;:%s/\s\([A-Z][a-z]*\)\s\S*\s\S*\s\S*\s\S*/\1\r/gc
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This basically took a proper noun - in this case, a Japanese town - with
for words after it, and removed them, and put it on a new line. As you
can tell, I’m using vim. Favourite thing I learned here? \S - anything
but \s. I also love () and \1, but that’s just a given, innit?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>New Paper on Interactive Classroom participation</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-17/20-34-new-paper-on-interactive-classroom-participation"/>
   <updated>2012-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-17/20-34-new-paper-on-interactive-classroom-participation</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;My coauthors, Antonia Scheidel, Marc Schulder, and Sibel Ciddi, and I
all have a new paper out recently in the 4th International Conference on Education and New Learning Technologies in Barcelona. It’s called &lt;strong&gt;Crowd sourcing the classroom: Interactive applications in higher learning&lt;/strong&gt;, and it is available for download &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burntfen.net/publications/LittEdulearn.pdf&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;, with the appropriate &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.burntfen.net/publications/bib/LittEdulearn.bib&quot;&gt;bib file&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;abstract&quot;&gt;Abstract&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The traditional university classroom paradigm frequently leads to fragmented knowledge dispersal; each student creates, collates, and curates their own notes individually. Here, we present a more holistic approach to student participation, based on experience from a student-initiated experiment using interactive applications in higher education. We explore several methods to help university students work collaboratively: Simultaneous note-taking using an online, interactive notepad; centralised information storage using a dedicated wiki; student-run centralised storage in the cloud; and communication management using a dedicated email list. In this paper, we elaborate on these points, and draw upon relevant previous literature, as well as our experience with implementing this system in several classes with diverse subjects in a graduate level Computational Linguistics degree. We also suggest future avenues to explore, such as slide-and-note integration.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our basic goal for this paper was to tell a story. At the beginning of
the fall semester at the Saarland University, in 2011, all of the
students were thrown together in a Masters program foundation course for computational
linguistics. We quickly realised that some of us, who took notes by
computers, could make our work more efficient by working together. Over
the course of the semester, a spontaneous, organic, and collaborative
way of taking notes, organising files, and managing our studies formed.
At heart, there were four main devices we used for this: &lt;strong&gt;simultaneous online notepads, central storage on Dropbox, private class-based wikis, and email lists&lt;/strong&gt;. None of these are necessarily new - but we felt that it was a story worth telling, and what we try to do in this paper is to present how we worked together, where we failed, and what we would suggest to teachers and students in the future. This paper is relevant, then, for not only classroom planners and education theorists, but also to students and teachers who can apply the methods used here to their own classrooms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;note-taking&quot;&gt;Note-Taking&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We first discuss some details about the courses we attended, and how
they were different, and each had different needs; tutorials, seminars,
projects, and so on. In general, to take notes in these, we used
Etherpads, based on either the Etherpad site, Riseup, Mozilla, or
DataONE (which I had used the previous summer to work with, during an
internship.) An Etherpad is a collaborative online notepad that allows multiple users to edit a document simultaneously, and has a chat bar, basic formatting functionality, and stores data for 30 days from the last edit. We basically used one Etherpad to store all of the links to the others, and every day we would check into that, open a new one, paste the link, and start taking notes. Other students in on it would start taking notes at the same time, and our work was cut in half. As well, this gave us the opportunity to see what was important to others, what questions we might have, to share personal notes about the course or anything else, and also the opportunity to ask a question, and listen, instead of scrambling to take notes simultaneously. It worked very well. We go over a lot of the gritty details, as well as show a textual analysis of the type of notes - links, personal comments, slide transcriptions, and so on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;wiki&quot;&gt;Wiki&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of our courses had a dedicated MediaWiki that we used to share
information about the course itself, a reading list, slides from our
presentations, information about the topic, as well as links to
notebooks. It wasn’t the largest wiki - 18 pages in the end - but it did
work very well as a reference which we could edit, rather than a closed
site that only a secretary somewhere can edit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;dropbox-and-email-lists&quot;&gt;Dropbox and Email Lists&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For each course in the program, there was a centralised email list that could be used to talk among other students. Usage patterns differed - for some courses, the lists were barely used. For others, there were often emails several times a week. The topics of conversation varied widely: administration details, homework assignments and questions, requests for papers that were held behind paywalls, questions about specific lectures, mentions of relevant books or research outside of the syllabus, and so on. For the entire program, there was also a centralised list that was used for larger concerns, such as examination procedures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As well, in response to early inefficient practices of repeatedly forwarding multiple copies of papers and homework assignments, a centralised Dropbox was set up to gather all of the information in one place. By the time we published, the Dropbox held 814 files, and was 1.07 GB in size. That’s a lot. There were dozens of relevant articles, answer sheets, past examinations, and notes. Dropbox was chosen because it was free, easy to use, easily synced to the master storage unit in the cloud, easy to moderate (both to allow members and to ensure quality), and because it had version control (for instance, when someone accidentally deleted a file, it could be recalled.) The majority of the students in the department had access to the Dropbox, except a few who had minor security issues, or did not wish to share files with others. We also, for some assignments, used a Github.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We then go on to discuss, in more detail, each of the topics, before
moving on to give our final recommendations. Here’s that section, verbatim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;recommendations&quot;&gt;Recommendations&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, from our experiences, we have several overarching recommendations for future students and
teachers regarding how to maximise the use of the four methods described above:&lt;br /&gt;
1. Spend time after lectures, or during lulls in conversation, to make the notes readable and
more structured. This leads to a better understanding of the material both during the lecture
and for later reference.&lt;br /&gt;
2. Communicate with lecturers about the use of slides being uploaded before a class. We found
that does help significantly with following along. It also helps with note-taking, exporting to
different documents and formats, and provides an impetus to prepare for lectures so that extra
information can be garnished from the instructor instead of merely following the slides at the
front of a class. Page numbers, sign-posting, and overview slides are especially helpful.&lt;br /&gt;
3. Short breaks between sections during a class can be incredibly helpful, even if they seem
redundant and counter-productive. They allow students to mull over new thoughts, and to
structure their notes and their understanding.&lt;br /&gt;
4. Make sure that someone archives and collates the notes together in a central repository, so
that collaborative work is not lost (for instance, due to the 30-day use limit to the Etherpads).
crowdsourcing quality assurance and checking the repository is also much easier than having
one individual doing this alone.&lt;br /&gt;
5. Keep systems simple and straightforward to encourage people to contribute regularly.
Complicated processes and interfaces inhibit students, by causing them to spend the extra
effort in an already intense study environment. The more seamlessly collaboration can be
integrated into daily routine, the better.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We hope that these recommendations help with future classes. Another aspect, not mentioned so far
in this paper, that makes collaborative work suitable for classrooms is that it is very engaging, and in
some cases, &lt;em&gt;fun&lt;/em&gt; - more so than following a single lecturer without interacting with fellow students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, that was basically our paper. None of us could attend the conference
for logistical reasons, but we hope that it got our there, and that some
people take the time to look at the paper, and perhaps implement
Classroom 2.0 technologies in their universities or high schools. Would
be fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to email me or comment here for questions.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The world's languages in crisis: A 20 year update</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-03/23-04-the-worlds-languages-in-crisis-a-20-year-update"/>
   <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-03/23-04-the-worlds-languages-in-crisis-a-20-year-update</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note: These are not so much reviews as notes I took after reading. In
some cases, they may even be notes merely to myself.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a very interesting paper that tackles the new Ethnologue coming
out in 2013, but more importantly, EGIDS, the Expanded Graded
Intergenerational Disruption Scale, a new way of classifying language
vitality. I was looking for this last week, and then I finally read the
paper, and now I can’t wait to see this used in the literature and to
help funding grants, and so on. EGIDS already came out in Lewis and
Simons 2010 (and is an extention of the Fishman scale, and UNESCO’s), but this based on the new Ethnologue - with some new figures. The most shocking of these is that Kraus 1992 may have been too dire! Most languages are not dying - only around 19% aren’t being passed on. This is of course, not good at all, but it is an improvement.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some line item notes:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Statistics on language viability are very hard to come by’ (Krauss
1992:4)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Fishman 1991 seems like a good book. Anyone read it? I need to get my
hands on it. Same with the UNESCO Experts Meeting on Safeguarding
Endangered Languages, Brenzinger et al. 2003. For that matter, also
Fishman 2001.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Ethnicity is not necessarily always equated with a language
community, as the marking of EGIDS level 7 seems to imply.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;It is unclear what they did about Latin. Or, for that matter,
Volapük.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Actually, what is the Na’vi one? I know we got our SIL code rejected
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;lack of a literature - but sure, I can do that? &lt;strong&gt;Anyone want to work on making a corpus from a forum?&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Six official languages of the UN: Arabic, Chinese, English, French,
Russian, Spanish. What about German and Portuguese?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Countries are not good determiners of language areas! I need to write
a paper on this. Anyone interested, &lt;strong&gt;let me know.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘We have lost 15% of the linguistic stocks (the largest subgroups of
related languages that are reconstructable) that had at least one
living member in 1950.’ pg. 11&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Alarmingly, 2,150 (29%) living languages all around the world are
currently at some stage in the process of language loss (EGIDS 6b-9).
That is more than the number of languages (1,863, 25%) that have
experienced enough language development (EGIDS 0-5) to rise about the
default stage of vigorous oral use (EGIDS 67a).’ p.11&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘Our findings show that Krauss’s estimate in 1992 that 50% of
languages were doomed or dying was too dire.’&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Who is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.google.com/url?sa=t&amp;amp;rct=j&amp;amp;q=&amp;amp;esrc=s&amp;amp;source=web&amp;amp;cd=1&amp;amp;ved=0CE0QFjAA&amp;amp;url=http%3A%2F%2Fhumanities.uchicago.edu%2Ffaculty%2Fmufwene%2Fvl4n2COLONIZATION-GLOBALIZATION.pdf&amp;amp;ei=ymLzT8WbNIbSsgb24NS7BQ&amp;amp;usg=AFQjCNG4RfMQQscKTYw_XWQ8ZqUePLK9Hw&quot;&gt;Mufwene 2002&lt;/a&gt;? Oh.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Dari language colonisation was very different from the Russian
one. Using diglossia to compare them fails. Just a thought.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we define language, anyway? (Is this a moot comment?)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;‘A correlation analysis of the colonization patterns that were
typical of particular regions or countries with the profile of
current EGIDS estimates for the languages in each context could be done
to develop concrete evidence that support Mufwene’s hypothesis.’ Yes,
that could be done. &lt;strong&gt;and it should be.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sunset poem</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-03/21-53-sunset-poem"/>
   <updated>2012-07-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-03/21-53-sunset-poem</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I decided that&lt;br /&gt;
now was the&lt;br /&gt;
time&lt;br /&gt;
to write&lt;br /&gt;
that&lt;br /&gt;
poem.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But&lt;br /&gt;
the tea &lt;br /&gt;
needed&lt;br /&gt;
to be brewed.&lt;br /&gt;
my bladder&lt;br /&gt;
wouldn’t empty itself.&lt;br /&gt;
the sunset&lt;br /&gt;
was drooping.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And it was&lt;br /&gt;
then&lt;br /&gt;
that I found&lt;br /&gt;
my little poem,&lt;br /&gt;
about the way&lt;br /&gt;
the hills looked,&lt;br /&gt;
like Japan,&lt;br /&gt;
detailed,&lt;br /&gt;
and full of&lt;br /&gt;
their own&lt;br /&gt;
molded earth,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;my&lt;br /&gt;
little&lt;br /&gt;
poem,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;was…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;of what was I&lt;br /&gt;
thinking &lt;br /&gt;
again?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;and why is my&lt;br /&gt;
tea&lt;br /&gt;
cold?&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Tolkien was a slacker.</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-01/17-09-tolkien-was-a-slacker"/>
   <updated>2012-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-01/17-09-tolkien-was-a-slacker</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I am rereading Lord of the Rings for the 13th time. I keep running
across new things - for instance, evidence so strong that I once would
have taken it for proof that the Entwives are in the Old Forest. As I
was reading along, I came upon this passage with new eyes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘There is one of my people yonder across the stream,’ he said, ‘though you may not see him.’ He gave a call like the low whistle of a bird, and out of a thicket of young trees an Elf stepped, clad in grey, but with his hood thrown back; his hair glinted like gold in the morning sun. Haldir skilfully cast over the stream a coil of grey rope, and he caught it and bound the end about a tree near the bank.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘Celebrant is already a strong stream here, as you see,’ said Haldir, ‘and it runs both swift and deep, and is very cold. We do not set foot in it so far north, unless we must. But in these days of watchfulness we do not make bridges. This is how we cross! Follow me!’ He made his end of the rope fast about another tree, and then ran lightly along it, over the river and back again, as if he were on a road.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;‘I can walk this path,’ said Legolas; ‘but the others have not this skill. Must they swim?’&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;‘No!’ said Haldir. ‘We have two more ropes. We will fasten them above the other, one shoulder-high, and another half-high, and holding these the strangers should be able to cross with care.’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When this slender bridge had been made, the Company passed over, some cautiously and slowly, others more easily. Of the hobbits Pippin proved the best for he was sure-footed, and he walked over quickly, holding only with one hand; but he kept his eyes on the bank ahead and did not look down. Sam shuffled along, clutching hard, and looking down into the pale eddying water as if it was a chasm in the mountains.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He breathed with relief when he was safely across. ‘Live and learn! as my gaffer used to say. Though he was thinking of gardening, not of roosting like a bird, nor of trying to walk like a spider. Not even my uncle Andy ever did a trick like that!’&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;When at length all the Company was gathered on the east bank of the Silverlode, the Elves untied the ropes and coiled two of them. Rumil, who had remained on the other side, drew back the last one, slung it on his shoulder, and with a wave of his hand went away, back to Nimrodel to keep watch.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Slacklining has been traditionally taken to have been invented in 1983.
Tolkien published Lord of the Rings in 1954.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And, of course, The Fellowship crossed the Celebrant on January 17th, 3019 of the Shire Reckoning. Take that, Californians.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Anonymous Twitterings</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-01/16-34-anonymous-twitterings"/>
   <updated>2012-07-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-07-01/16-34-anonymous-twitterings</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Over a year ago (but not much over), a friend and I were sitting in one
of my favourite cafés at the time, Black Medicine, in Bruntsfield,
Edinburgh. We were talking about Twitter, and about what sort of posts
were allowed – and what sort weren’t. We began to wonder: what if we
had private twitter accounts, and no followers? What would the posts
be like?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A pact began to form. We both set up new accounts, and didn’t tell the
other their names. We promised to never follow anyone; to never tweet at
anyone; to never retweet each other or anyone who might be able to
identify us; to not talk about it, except in generalities; to tweet when
we wanted, but never because we felt obligated to. At the end of the
year, we’d see who had more followers, and what the tweets looked like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A year passed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My friend, @simonv3 (his public account), won the contest, with four
followers. We have no idea why any of them followed him. I had no
followers - and frankly, I’m not surprised.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No, I’m not going to give you the name of my account. This is largely because around 95% of my private tweets were swear words. Around 20% of them aren’t fit for public consumption, and around 10% of them are midly socially incriminating. But in between the drunken rants and swears, there’s a few very tender moments. Posts about how much I miss people; or home; or a girl. Posts that really show what exactly I was feeling at the time, and some that show how quickly a mood can change. Posts that speak of the heights and lows of last year (one of the most dynamic in my life, I suppose.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While I’m not going to post the twitter handle here; if you’re a good
friend, and are brave enough to risk being told &lt;em&gt;Sorry, No&lt;/em&gt; to (I’m not giving it
out to everyone), feel free to ask for it. If you’re curious as to what
&lt;em&gt;you&lt;/em&gt; might do - well, I suggest setting up your own account. I’ve
learned a lot - mainly, I’ve learned what social networks really mean,
and how the old adage of ‘I tweet about my breakfast’ only holds up when
you know others are listening.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the record: there were no tweets about breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Mark Liberman on Automating Phonetic Measurements</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-29/17-12-libermans-talk-provisional"/>
   <updated>2012-06-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-29/17-12-libermans-talk-provisional</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Over the weekend, I attended a workshop on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.martijnwieling.nl/workshop&quot;&gt;Quantitative Linguistics and
Dialectology&lt;/a&gt; in Groningen, in
Holland. This was my first time in Groningen - I had friends there from
my Erasmus Mundus program in Language and Communication Technologies,
and it was great to meet up with them and to stay with another friend of
mine, Jelke, an honorary EMLCT member. The workshop was centred around topics relevant to Martijn Wieling PhD defense, which occured the day before. Several of the speakers were invited for this, and the workshop was supplementary to their appearance. This was certainly the case for Mark Liberman, of UPenn, LDC, and LanguageLog fame. His talk ended the workshop.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here are the notes I took (as good as they could be), along with the transcriptions of the question and answer session. I hope I didn’t annoy too many by typing loudly and too fast. There were most likely many transcription errors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;mark-liberman---automating-phonetic-measurements&quot;&gt;Mark Liberman - Automating Phonetic Measurements&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Talk at the Quantitative Linguistics and Dialectology Workshop&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a talk about automating phonetic segmentation and manipulation, and why we’re not using the tools available, and how that may change in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;For most well-defined phonetic detection, classification, and measurement tasks, judicious choice of acoustic features and application of modern machine-learning techniques will produce and automatated annotation system that works about as well as a human annotator.&lt;/strong&gt; (This slide was referred to several times.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Two papers that aren’t really known by many linguists:&lt;br /&gt;
 * Saul Sternberg et al. 1978. The Latency and Duration of Rapid Movement Sequences: Comparisons of Speech and Typewriting.&lt;br /&gt;
 * Saul Sternberg et al. 1980. Motor Programs in Rapid Speech: Additional Evidence. In Cole, Ed., &lt;em&gt;Perception and Production&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why did they use these? Motivations:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Accuracy, as human annotators aren’t the best.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Freedom from experiment bias.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Efficiency. (Praat did not exist.)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Forward 32 years: &lt;em&gt;Journal of Phonetics&lt;/em&gt;: 45 articles, 4 issues this year.&lt;br /&gt;
Use of automated measures? Either 0, or 1, papers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Mooshammer et al, 2012, ‘Bridging…’: This is a good paper, and I suggest it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Schuppler et al, 2012. Used some forced alignment, but eventually returned to Praat for detailed analysis.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Why does this matter? Well, human judgement means wasted time and effort, slower research, problems with confirmation and experimenter bias. There’s also a lost opportunity for very-large scale research, especially on ‘Found data’. Also on large-scale laboratory speech collections. Well, is there an alternative?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, an example: VOT measurement for voiceless stops. The concept is to use forced alignment to find the approximate region for a measurement. And then use machine-learning methods to classify the region, and to detect relevant events and measure durations, frequencies, amplitudes, etc., as appropriate. This is work in progress by Neville Ryant at Penn, supported by an NSF grant.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Architecture: at each identified stop region (as localised by forced alignment):&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;We create a time series of acoustic feature vectors, extracted every ms.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The decision function of a max-margin stop-burst detector is computed for ever frame.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The decision function of a max-margin stop-burst detector is computed for every frame following a burst.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If either the burst onset or voice onset detector fails to find a non-negative peak, VOT measurement fails for this region. Otherwise, it is recorded.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We measured five acoustic features: locally-normalised total energy, low- and high- frequency energy, and spectral entropy and centroid. The details do not matter - what matters is that this is all standard machine-learning guff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, we get good results from these, compared to human annotators. For instance, 1.5ms mean absolute difference between two human phonetician annotators, while 1.89ms between the algorithm and a human annotator.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, the statement (&lt;em&gt;in bold&lt;/em&gt;) above fits.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions:&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;To what extent are you thinking about firing all of the human annotators?&lt;/strong&gt; I mean, well, I don’t know, the way that it stands now, you certainly wouldn’t want to apply this sort of thing without a significant check. We need to do random spot checks of the rest of the data to make sure that nothing weird has happened, and similar kinds of problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I have such and such a corpora…&lt;/strong&gt; (&lt;em&gt;missed&lt;/em&gt;). There’s a version which is easy: Say, there’s a tape with a digital recording, and you know what the word list spoken was, and you want to associate the word list with the region of the tape where it is said, that’s easy. &lt;strong&gt;Also for two and half hours?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, we’ve done two (&lt;em&gt;laughs in the room&lt;/em&gt;). Just how crappy this was, forgive my wording, &lt;em&gt;can be shown by how we did it the application of it&lt;/em&gt; in Swedish. I contacted all of my Swedish phonetician friends, and I came up empty with regards to sound rules or a Swedish pronouncing dictionary. They pointed to everyone else around in the circle; ‘mine was mislaid in the wash’, etc. We didn’t have anything. So, without knowing anything about Swedish, I made a guess for each letter of the English alphabet what English phoneme it was most like, not even using digraphs, and used models trained on the Supreme Court arguments, 2001, and we were able to properly align it. I think we can deal with your corpora.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;I wonder how many class labels this can deal with&lt;/strong&gt; Well, the more classes, the harder the problem. There’s no technical problem, it’s just that as the classes increase, the accuracy decreases. Of course, the same tends to be true for human annotators in most classes. We can talk about your problem. You know we’re … the claim is of course a bit overstated. But I think there’s no reason in principle that whatever task can’t be taken care of. Coming back to the previous question: what would be harder, is what the Nijmegen Schuppler et al paper used forced alignment for, which is not only getting words in the right place, but to figure out what configuration is used in each particular case, which isn’t fairly perfect, but should work well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about public approachability for this? Like a wiki?&lt;/strong&gt; Well, we’ve already done that for the forced alignment. That’s open source, you can download it. There’s also a web-based trial. The languages for which we have models, we now have five or six languages, in addition to English: Portuguese, Vietnamese, Chinese… I forget. For these, you can upload audio and transcript, and after a while, you get emailed a link to a Praat file giving you the alignment. For certain, I would expect, we’re not there yet, but in the next few years for a number of standard phonetic measurements like VOT - we ought to be able to offer some analogous service, although I would hope that people could learn to do it themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;What about automating this… Often, when you look at the output, you see different patterns between human and computer errors.&lt;/strong&gt; If the automated analysis is unbiased relative to the analysis of interest for you, you’ll still be better off. I’m less concerned about whether there are bizarre errors, which there might be - of course, human’s do this too, with finger slips and the like - I’m more concerned as to whether the mistakes there are are biased with respect to the object of interest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Maybe I could ask about sociolinguistic variation. Some tasks that we regularly have: checking transcription quality and vowel quality.&lt;/strong&gt; Let me take the second first. Starting in 2009, we are working with Bill Labov’s students, in particular with Kielen Melanini (sp?) We took a Bayesian approach to formant tracking, using a transcript, forced alignment with a sociolinguistic interview, we then select from a transcript the words containing the vowels you want to analyse, perhaps all of the vowels, and then, because you know the environment that you want to get, you know something about where you expect the formants to be. There’s a prior. Then you take LPC poles, for each set of poles in the appropriate frequency range, you do a joint optimization of the things you need, based on the bandwidth and so on, multiplied by the prior. That eliminates a large percentage of formatting errors. I can show you scatter plots, it’s been done for a few languages now. Keelin convinced Bill by doing this for the Atlas of North American English. He was able to say quite precise things about what conclusions you’d come to from using the machine generated numbers, versus the hand stuff. Bill and their students now do all of their measurements using this technique.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Checking transcripts is a very interesting and difficult problem. One of the
dirty little secrets of speech recognition is that confidence measurements are
surprisingly poor. One of the major projects at Limsee is making error analysis
of confidence better. It’s true that for transcripts you can find analyses that
have been way off, but transcript errors are harder to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Applause.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A Linguistic Assessment of the Munji Language in Afghanistan</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-27/19-33-notes-a-linguistic-assessment-of-the-munji-language-in-afghanistan"/>
   <updated>2012-06-27T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-27/19-33-notes-a-linguistic-assessment-of-the-munji-language-in-afghanistan</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Some notes from:
  * Beyer and Beck (2011). &lt;em&gt;A Linguistic Assessment of the
Munji Language in Afghanistan.&lt;/em&gt; Language Documentation &amp;amp; Conservation,
6; pp. 38-103. http://nflrc.hawaii.edu/ldc/&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a generally fascinating paper, and very fun to read alongside
with ‘A Walk in the Hindu Kush’, about travels in the area fifty years
before. Here are some sections I highlighted in my reading:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;2.3 LINGUISTIC SITUATION. The national languages of Afghanistan are
Dari and Pashto. Both are Indo-European languages, Dari belonging to
the West Iranian group of languages and Pashto to the East Iranian
group. The Ethnologue (Gordon 2005) lists 46 languages for
Afghanistan. Many of these are also spoken in neighboring countries,
as borders were drawn without taking into account the locations and
boundaries of ethnolinguistic groups. Accoding to the new
Constitution of Afghanisatan (in place since 2005), Article 16, the
government supports the development and strengthening of minority
languages. Even the status of a third national language is ascribed to
some languages, in places where the majority speaks them. For example,
Pamiri is mentioned as one of them. &lt;strong&gt;Little research has been conducted
on the minority languages of Afghanistan, and hardly any information
about them is available.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The splitting up of Afghanistan is a fascinating topic, particularly the &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Durand_Line&quot;&gt;Durand Line&lt;/a&gt;. The great game was a ridiculous affair, where European interests basically ignored the locals and carved up the region. This can still be seen today. In the most sobering part of the paper, Medical Situation, there is this quote:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;As we were walking through the villages, people often asked us for
medicine and said, “Please send us a doctor and an eye doctor. We
don’t have a doctor in the valley, and the people just die.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I suggest reading the paper - it is a very good assessment of the
language, and predicts that Munji is not in danger of going extinct
soon, thanks to lots of youth learning the language and the people being
proud of it. Let’s hope this continues.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Finding</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-26/23-36-the-finding"/>
   <updated>2012-06-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-26/23-36-the-finding</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I woke, attended classes. When they were finished, and I had finished
messing around with my own code during them, I enjoyed the sunshine.
Bringing my slackline back with me from home, I set it up, and for
twenty-odd minutes in the afternoon sun I walked next to the building
where my colleagues and professors studied. The line hung black like a
long snake I caught another afternoon, years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A final class; and then home. I watched a movie, ate dinner, did some
work. As the sun set, I realised how much I depended on my sunset
cigarette. Now I had no reason to stand on my balcony. So I went out,
visited a friend, and finished my final work for the day. Coming back, I
hear music from the empty lot behind my house, in the industrial
abandon where I once hopped around a fence and saw artwork, trees, and
what looked like a commune. No one was there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“Ah! You’re Brazilian. Have you ever drunk maté? I love that stuff, but I don’t have a gourd.”&lt;br /&gt;
“I have one. I bring them with me to give, because there is always someone who wants some.”&lt;br /&gt;
“No shit!”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tonight, I knew there would be people there; Bonobo was drifting through
a football field of air to prove that. I filled my maté gourd, and
headed out beneath the last blueing of the sky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were lights on in the abandoned garages, but I couldn’t tell if
anyone was there, or if, perhaps, this was a residence and I had not
noted. I peered through a fence, and finally, wandered around and past
it. I sip cautiously, and return. WHEEEEET - a sharp whistle. My keys
rattle as a back off, hoping it’s not for a dog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Twenty metres away, I turn. There’s a man there, staring at me. I slowly
walk towards him; and his hand extends. I shake it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He was an Italian, Guilliame. The other, in the large shed, filled to
the brim with a spotlight, was Leonard (I think.) They’re making the
stage for a burlesque show, for players from Paris.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“So what are you doing in life?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Well, a masters.”&lt;br /&gt;
“In what?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Computational linguistics…But I’m only here another month, and then I’m off to Malta.”&lt;br /&gt;
“Malta?”&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes. I’ve bought a boat, and that’s what I’m doing in life.”&lt;br /&gt;
“How long is it?”&lt;br /&gt;
“25 feet. Sorry, och metres.”&lt;br /&gt;
“What about chicks?”&lt;br /&gt;
“There’s room enough for one.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
…&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;“Where is Kentuky, again?”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I help them saw some boards. I think to myself, &lt;em&gt;my years in the stage taught me when to exit.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;“I’m off. When are you here?”&lt;br /&gt;
“For the next few weeks. Come on the 13th. You can be our guest.”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My hands smelling of sawdust, my lips wet from a shared joint, my maté empty. I’ll try and follow the music from now on.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Hopcroft and Brzozowski</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-18/09-45-hopcroft-and-brzozowski"/>
   <updated>2012-06-18T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-18/09-45-hopcroft-and-brzozowski</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Most coders of automata go through this process: The Hopcroft is a bit longer to code up, so let’s just go with Brzozowski’s algorithm, the deterministic reverse deterministic reverse algorithm. In practice, that works well - until one fine morning when they go to minimise something, go get coffee, come back, and it’s still going on. That’s when they go with Hopcroft. It turns out that when you’re really doing serious work with finite state machines, then minimising frequently after a few steps in some machines is better.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Martin Kay (in class)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Seasons</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-17/22-13-seasons"/>
   <updated>2012-06-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-17/22-13-seasons</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Standing on my balcony&lt;br /&gt;
I begin to wring a poem&lt;br /&gt;
From the sunset.&lt;br /&gt;
‘Each year, I swallow summer whole&lt;br /&gt;
Gulp it down&lt;br /&gt;
And each autumn, I begin to choke’&lt;br /&gt;
No, that’s no good, I say&lt;br /&gt;
It’s not perfect&lt;br /&gt;
‘I swallow summer whole&lt;br /&gt;
And let it swill there,&lt;br /&gt;
Filling me in the winter
And each spring,&lt;br /&gt;
I find I am hungry again’&lt;br /&gt;
No, not perfect.&lt;br /&gt;
While smoke wraps around my fingers&lt;br /&gt;
Like the suns last caresses&lt;br /&gt;
Six swallows fly overhead&lt;br /&gt;
And I begin to laugh.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Pinched</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-17/21-10-pinched"/>
   <updated>2012-06-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-17/21-10-pinched</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;On the Metro in Paris,&lt;br /&gt;
I imagine her thoughts&lt;br /&gt;
and her destination.&lt;br /&gt;
Then, I see her&lt;br /&gt;
fingers&lt;br /&gt;
drumming lightly&lt;br /&gt;
on the metal pole;&lt;br /&gt;
And the wide gulf&lt;br /&gt;
between synapses and nerves&lt;br /&gt;
opens before me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If that hand&lt;br /&gt;
held this hand,&lt;br /&gt;
this ocean would be&lt;br /&gt;
just lightly pinched.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Family (poem)</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-09/16-24-my-family-poem"/>
   <updated>2012-06-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-09/16-24-my-family-poem</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;My family &lt;br /&gt;
has a bad &lt;br /&gt;
habit of &lt;br /&gt;
killing &lt;br /&gt;
ourselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My mother&lt;br /&gt;
Slammed a smile onto her face&lt;br /&gt;
For so many years that it locked itself&lt;br /&gt;
I heard her say, once&lt;br /&gt;
“I need to laugh that way&lt;br /&gt;
at least once a year.”&lt;br /&gt;
She moved home, south&lt;br /&gt;
where it’s warm beneath the pine trees&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My sister&lt;br /&gt;
broke down when she was cut off&lt;br /&gt;
At a stop sign in a parking lot&lt;br /&gt;
She tried so hard to shelve her childhood&lt;br /&gt;
That she forgot it was still there&lt;br /&gt;
dusting up and rusting away&lt;br /&gt;
She has a child now&lt;br /&gt;
And may dust those shelves in time&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My brother&lt;br /&gt;
Drove the principal’s car into a lake&lt;br /&gt;
And got sent to juvenile&lt;br /&gt;
For two long years&lt;br /&gt;
He came back five inches taller&lt;br /&gt;
With some white stubble&lt;br /&gt;
And free entrance to the low security&lt;br /&gt;
mental institution in the local hospital&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My father&lt;br /&gt;
Drank and drank and drank&lt;br /&gt;
All of the stars into his bones&lt;br /&gt;
until they filled his marrow &lt;br /&gt;
until he could walk on his reflection&lt;br /&gt;
in the night ocean&lt;br /&gt;
feet-bottoms touching&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And me&lt;br /&gt;
I’ve written these stories&lt;br /&gt;
Until the horizon squalls over&lt;br /&gt;
And I remember&lt;br /&gt;
And my father can’t walk on water&lt;br /&gt;
And my mother loved her dogs&lt;br /&gt;
And my sister&lt;br /&gt;
is bringing something useful into the world&lt;br /&gt;
And I never had a brother&lt;br /&gt;
But it sure kills me to pretend.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Father poem</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-05/00-34-father-poem"/>
   <updated>2012-06-05T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-05/00-34-father-poem</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Untitled&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;em&gt;May 28th&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 2012&lt;br /&gt;
My father put on weight.&lt;br /&gt;
“I’m 210!” He said,&lt;br /&gt;
sniffing like a seal,&lt;br /&gt;
mouth set in a clam outline.&lt;br /&gt;
He was always skinny,&lt;br /&gt;
A crazed, starved prophet.&lt;br /&gt;
(Arent’t all prophets false?)&lt;br /&gt;
But now, an incipient week away,&lt;br /&gt;
He ate and swallowed and grew,&lt;br /&gt;
Until even his pants drew tight.&lt;br /&gt;
An old tree,&lt;br /&gt;
Growing through a white fence.&lt;br /&gt;
Eating and growing&lt;br /&gt;
“Yes. I’m 210 now. Yep.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Beyond _n_-grams</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-04/14-01-beyond-n-grams"/>
   <updated>2012-06-04T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-04/14-01-beyond-n-grams</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been reading through some of the papers on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.stanford.edu/~mjkay/&quot;&gt;Martin Kay’s website&lt;/a&gt;, as he is teaching Basic Algorithms for Computational Linguistics here. He has a paper about &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;-grams and the upper limit, and ways of getting past it. In it, he talks about language models, and the current way of using &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;-grams to generate natural language. He ends with this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;But could it be that the standard statistic is not only difficult to
use, but also not the best one for the job? A very different one,
which may be easier to use is the probability of the substring, given
the bag of words that make it up. In other words, it is the number of
instances of the substring in the training data, divided by the number
of sentences that contain all of the words in it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Consider a string S that contains substrings s1,s2…sk, all of
which are also substrings of the training corpus, that are maximal
with respect to S. Might the figure of merit of the substrings f1,
f2…fk, be assinging in such a way that the fom of S would be f1
+ f2…+fk, or something comparably simple?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think this is the right reasoning, but I also think it may not go far
enough. One of the interesting things about the &lt;em&gt;n&lt;/em&gt;-gram model is that
it is generally used for words, but not necessarily for substrings that
are composed of other substrings - as far as I am aware. If this is the
case, then it might be possible to train an algorithm that would not
only give the best fit strings from the bag of words, but also rank the
substrings that are collated as being more probable together. You would
need a massive amount of corpora for this to be the case, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But a way of getting around this block might be to use annotated
substrings that have some sort of intelligent understand of the
collocations within them, possible using semantic or syntactic
annotation. If this were to be done, coreference and anaphoric
resolution would be a bootstrapper to predicting the correct choice of
substrings, and the current best-first model would be surpassed in favor
of a more cohesive output. By taking the the substring with the
probability of the words within coming from within the previous bag of
words, and then checking this substring against the surrounding
substrings &lt;em&gt;against the possibility of these collocations existing in
the training data&lt;/em&gt; (and possibly even the already given strings), it
should be possible to have more probably generation.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Ballistic Seeds</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-03/16-40-ballistic-seed"/>
   <updated>2012-06-03T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-03/16-40-ballistic-seed</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;There is a pretty cool video &lt;a href=&quot;http://jecologyblog.wordpress.com/2012/05/28/ballistic-seed-dispersal/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; on ballistic seed dispersal. If you don’t know what this is, go check it out - basically, some plants propgate by exploding their seed sacs so that the seeds jump as far from the base as possible. It’s pretty fun to watch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I once read an Arthur C. Clarke story about an astronaut who had died on
the moon. Some people went to find out where he had gone, and found that
his helmet had been broken in. They couldn’t figure out why - but they
were astounded to notice that he had been in a garden, on the moon,
&lt;em&gt;in the open.&lt;/em&gt; The garden was full of cacti. He had found a way to make
a plant that would make oxygen, and live in the sterile environment of
the moon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Just as they figure this out, one of the cacti explodes - and seeds go
everywhere. Not caught by the gravity field, they have the same force as
bullets, and the mysterious death is explained. Pretty awesome story, I
think.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Café Montmarte</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-01/14-20-caf-montmarte"/>
   <updated>2012-06-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-06-01/14-20-caf-montmarte</id>
   <content type="html">
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Headline Bias</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-29/09-35-headline-bias"/>
   <updated>2012-05-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-29/09-35-headline-bias</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I ran across this email from Reuters in my inbox today. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.reuters.com/article/2012/05/24/us-usa-campaign-idUSBRE84H13020120524?feedType=RSS&amp;amp;feedName=domesticNews&quot;&gt;Romney opens new front vs Obama: schools are failing&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What shall I think of this? My first thought was &lt;em&gt;Good, I’m glad that is
being talked about.&lt;/em&gt; This was followed almost immediately by &lt;em&gt;Romney
must be an OK guy to bring this up, as it is important. Maybe I should
reconsider calling him an asshole before I actually look at his issues,
just based on his party and what I remember of his assinine comments in
the primaries.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of course, I then realised that this, too, is wrong. There are two
biases playing out here: one being a cognitive bias, and the other being
the bias of the news team. To understand, consider these questions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How do we know that Romney actually cares?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Are failing schools in any way connected to Romney?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Has Obama not being doing enough for schools?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;If he has been doing stuff, then why is this a new front?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Why is Romney seemingly on the offensive here? Even the language
suggests it.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;How, on earth, is this a &lt;em&gt;new&lt;/em&gt; front? Surely schools have been
failing America for decades?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basic point: Be very careful what you think after reading a headline.
You’re probably wrong, at first.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Globe</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-28/20-37-globe"/>
   <updated>2012-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-28/20-37-globe</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;After the Marathon, we came to the Globe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Globe. is awesome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a really nice selection of books in the bookstore. There are
lots of pamphlets and cool things to look at. Myself, I bought &lt;em&gt;what
matters most is how well you walk through the fire&lt;/em&gt; by Bukowski.
Depressing, but good reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The back bit has a really nice menu, complete with Spinach burgers and
Nachos, both of which I tried. I had becherovka, a Czech drink, which,
as my friend put it, has ‘the taste of Christmas and gasoline.’ You
know, he wasn’t wrong. The Mexican coffee, with Kahlua, is also
fantastic. At Czech prices, we’ve been here all day. I spent most of
that reading a paper on the &lt;a href=&quot;http://scholarspace.manoa.hawaii.edu/bitstream/handle/10125/4506/beyer_beck.pdf?sequence=1&quot;&gt;Munji language in Afghanistan&lt;/a&gt; (very fun), and a lot of
[Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality] (hpmor.com) (more fun). Smoking is cool inside, and
the music ain’t half bad. Before - James Bond themes. Now - Fatboy Slim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Wireless is excellent. 
Plugs are good. 
Chairs are comfortable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And once again I sacrifice seeing another city for happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Marathon Cafe, Prague</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-28/14-07-marathon-cafe"/>
   <updated>2012-05-28T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-28/14-07-marathon-cafe</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;With Andreas and Lemar in the Marathon Café in Prague. I’ve continually
wanted to start a blog talking about all of the different cafés I’ve
been to, but I haven’t gotten around to it yet. As this blog as so easy
to push, this post is going here, although it may eventually go on a new
blog, or maybe even on my old &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.edinburghcafes.blogspot.com&quot;&gt;Edinburgh
Cafes&lt;/a&gt; blog, which is really only for
cafes in Edinburgh.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, here’s the run down:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Two cute girls in the corner&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;In a confusing building - might be a uni?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Wireless good. Also, access to Eduroam as a backup.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Latte alright, a bit too frothy.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Very lovely music, computer near the door for selection. Conducive to
sitting and thining. Think lounge music, but not so ungood.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Chairs, nice. Lights, nice. General atmosphere: chic.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Food - not sure, haven’t had it. Going to another place now.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Many outlets for computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rating: 4 out of 5.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Stack Overfloweth</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-21/09-25-my-stack-overfloweth"/>
   <updated>2012-05-21T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-21/09-25-my-stack-overfloweth</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;h2 id=&quot;from-psalm-23&quot;&gt;From Psalm 23.&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;By me and Jolene.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Lord is my sysadmin, I shall not grep.&lt;br /&gt;
He makes me use languages with many libraries,&lt;br /&gt;
he allows me to apt-get many packages,&lt;br /&gt;
he clears my cache. &lt;br /&gt;
He echoes my global path,&lt;br /&gt;
for his user names klout.&lt;br /&gt;
Even though I tech-support other people’s code,&lt;br /&gt;
I will fear no project manager,&lt;br /&gt;
for you are with me;&lt;br /&gt;
your root access and your admin powers,&lt;br /&gt;
they comfort me.&lt;br /&gt;
You oai-pmh my repository,&lt;br /&gt;
in the presence of my 4chan trolls.&lt;br /&gt;
You chmod my files as 777,&lt;br /&gt;
my stack overfloweth.&lt;br /&gt;
Surely your goodness and wireless network will follow me&lt;br /&gt;
all the days of my life,&lt;br /&gt;
I will subscribe to your mailing list&lt;br /&gt;
for(int days = 0; days &amp;lt;= eternity; days++);&lt;br /&gt;
I will be in your usergroup.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Right to Offend</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-10/10-53-the-right-to-offend"/>
   <updated>2012-05-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-10/10-53-the-right-to-offend</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;There’s a relatively good song by Momus called Rhetoric, and in the
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=mf4LLPMtSkU&quot;&gt;Youtube video&lt;/a&gt; there’s this
lovely segment of an interview where he explains that art is great
because no one has to do it. It is so unnecessary. Sometimes, writing
these blogs feels that way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Take this one. I opened it yesterday after having a back and forth of
around twenty twitter messages with a friend of mine in Edinburgh. She
had been castigated the police, calling them all bastards, and so on. I
tried to get across to her that the police - even the UK police, who are
about as close to V for Vendetta as possible while not letting people
catch on too much - do have some useful functions, that they are really
actually helpful in some cases, and that they’re composed of human
beings who we should embrace as brothers and not alienate. Sure, I hate
the state and the popo, too. But that doesn’t mean I am going to go
around calling all Police scum - they aren’t, although their office
might be. I say this even though I’ve seen friends arrested, maligned,
marginilised, taken away in taxis, and submitted to almost every kind of
disgrace. But I still hold that we shouldn’t demand for their
excommunication from life, or from any sort of new world order.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At one point, my friend, who probably didn’t get my messages intent as
much as I had hoped, partially due to Twitter, told me I didn’t have the
right to tell her what to think or say. I responded with the sentiment
from one of my favourite quotes on the freedom of speech. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=HQ3VcbAfd4w&quot;&gt;Philip Pullman&lt;/a&gt;
states that “No one has the right to live without being schocked. No one
has the right to live without being offended.” I do have the right to
suggest alternative ways of speaking, of telling her I don’t think her
attitude towards our fellow-men-in-black is right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I still think that’s pretty awesome.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Sterling Hayden</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-06/11-06-sterling-hayden"/>
   <updated>2012-05-06T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-06/11-06-sterling-hayden</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve seen this quote on the web a few places, but it often has errors. I went back to the book and fixed them, and added the paragraph on money and sex that is often not included.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To be truly challenging, a voyage, like a life, must rest on a firm foundation of financial unrest. Otherwise you are doomed to a routine traverse, the kind known to yachtsmen, who play with their boats at sea - “cruising,” it is called. Voyaging belongs to seamen, and to the wanderers of the world who cannot, or will not, fit in. If you are contemplating a voyage and you have the means, abandon the venture until your fortunes change. Only then will you know what the sea is all about.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Little has been said or written about the ways a man may blast himself free. Why? I don’t know, unless the answer lies in our diseased values. A man seldom hesitates to describe his work; he gladly divulges the privacies of alleged sexual conquests. But ask him how much he has in the bank and he recoils into a shocked and stubborn silence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;“I’ve always wanted to sail to the south seas, but I can’t afford it.” What these men can’t afford is &lt;em&gt;not&lt;/em&gt; to go. They are enmeshed in the cancerous discipline of “security.” And in the worship of security we fling our lives beneath the wheels of routine - and before we know it our lives are gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;What does a man need - really need? A few pounds of food each day, heat and shelter, six feet to lie down in - and some form of working activity that will yield a sense of accomplishment. That’s all - in the material sense. And we know it. But we are brainwashed by our economic system until we end up in a tomb beneath a pyramid of time payments, mortgages, preposterous gadgetry, playthings that divert our attention from the sheer idiocy of the charade.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;The years thunder by, The dreams of youth grow dim where they lie caked in dust on the shelves of patience. Before we know it, the tomb is sealed.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Where, then, lies the answer? In choice. Which shall it be: bankruptcy of purse or bankruptcy of life?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;– Sterling Hayden, &lt;em&gt;Wanderer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This quote is often on my background, and it is one of the main reasons I embarked recently on a major attempt to save myself from leaping out of windows. More on that later. Obviously, I think you should all read his book, &lt;em&gt;Wanderer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>A bit of slack...</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-01/23-08-a-bit-of-slack"/>
   <updated>2012-05-01T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-05-01/23-08-a-bit-of-slack</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’ve been incredibly homesick the past few days. I think that is a
legitimate use of the word ‘homesick’, although I don’t refer back to a
single place, least of all to Connecticut, where I grew up and lived for
some 14 years, nor to Edinburgh, which was my base of sorts for five
years during my undergraduate, and lastly not to Saarbrücken, where I
currently am, anyway. No, I’ve been homesick in another way - the
topography of my mind doesn’t match the longitude and latitude of the
physical world. Home is where my friends, beauty, and adventure
collide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Back within the valley.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Down from the divide.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;No more flaming clouds about,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;O! the soft hillside.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the starry night,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And my cottage light.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Wallace Stevens&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My homesickness manifests itself in several ways. For one, I have an
inability to focus on anything. I’ve never been good at focusing in the
first place, but when I’m low, it’s much worse. If I am focusing, it’s
on a friend, or a lock of hair, or a journey, or a tumblr. The cycle
continues. I even had a party last night which should have broken the
monotony. Alas, it didn’t.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At 5:00pm today I realised I wasn’t going to get better, so I watched
Game of Thrones while eating dinner, and headed out with my new
slackline from REI to the river. It’s 120 feet - I managed to build a
slackline that was around 70 or 80 feet, and walked around half of it. I
put it at 5 feet off of the ground, so it was a bit high up, but it
still had a bit too much slack in it. Not really a problem, just makes
it harder to focus in the middle, when you’re dropping down another four
feet. Some German kids tried it out, and a man helped me tighten it and
let out a great laugh when I fell with my legs on either side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But then I am back to the computer. I’ve been trying to get a Github to
work, checking out and updating social networks (I actually updated my
Tumblr, for once), and that sort of thing. Mostly, though, I’ve been
contemplating this mental map I have. The porch in Portland is tied in
with the beach at Truro, the Swiss alps, the midges along the West
Highland Way, and all of these other places I’ve been to and savoured.
Distance doesn’t hold any barrier to reminiscing. But this world is
peopled, with friends. There are around 10 of them, and I’d give a lot
to have any of them in Saarbrücken, or to be elsewhere. Since that isn’t
the case, I must be content with blogging half-assedly, trying to map
out the topography of my desire, listening to the same songs on repeat,
hoping to bring into my night that little bit of wideness that comes
from good friends - that feeling that the world is gilded, that
opportunities are real, that we’ll always have enough money for another
coffee, that all wrongness is fleeting, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I had a friend here, what would I be doing different? I assume little. 
Slacklining, surfing the net. Staring at sunsets and smoking my lungs away. 
Well, I guess I’d settle for that. For now, I have to settle for work.
Let’s hope this semi-rant will break the endless beat.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>EACL Thoughts</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-24/16-10-eacl-thoughts"/>
   <updated>2012-04-24T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-24/16-10-eacl-thoughts</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;How about a tool that looks at language change holistically,
combining typological, lexical, morphological, and syntactic
databases that have been used to show evolutionary processes?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;“All we are doing is putting numbers on things.” Is there a bias
towards dealing with percentages and understanding what it really
means? Can humans actually compute differences from a gold standard, or
fully comprehend what a gold standard actually is?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Stray thoughts</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-19/16-55-stray-thoughts"/>
   <updated>2012-04-19T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-19/16-55-stray-thoughts</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;I’m studying for my Foundations exam. I had some stray thoughts that
might be worth sharing, and that’ll help me remember things.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;missed&lt;/em&gt; is a homophone to &lt;em&gt;mist&lt;/em&gt;. I should write a poem about that.
Why? Because mist is one of my favourite things, and staring into
it, a lot of things are arbitrarily called to the mind. Cf. TS Eliot’s
poem ‘Marina’ for what I mean.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I still think that morphology ought to be more important in language
evolution. I wonder what lines of thinking would lead to if you
followed down the route that starts with the thought that morphology
sits at the interface of lexicon, phonology, and syntax - does that make
it a fossil itself? What is the nature of theoretical detritus - is it
more likely to be isolated or joined onto existing patterns?&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;I should use regular expressions more in NLP for Wired. For
instance, in t = ‘two minutes and five seconds’, I should use
minutes and then split(‘ ‘) and then use t[x-1] to identify,
instead of currently saving slots 1 and 4 for retrieval. Just saying.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Becoming Awesome.</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-10/11-01-becoming-awesome"/>
   <updated>2012-04-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-10/11-01-becoming-awesome</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Through rationality we shall become awesome, and invent and test systematic methods for making people awesome, and plot to optimize everything in sight, and the more fun we have the more people will want to join us.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This morning I have been wrestling with myself, with help from Professor Quirrel. Meaning, with help from &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikiquote.org/wiki/Eliezer_Yudkowsky&quot;&gt;Eliezer Yudkowsky&lt;/a&gt;. Why? Because I wish to become awesome (cf, above). All of his quotes are good - they are rational, and so it is easier to be awesome because they are probably right. I’ll just focus on a couple that struck me hard just now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To confess your fallibility and then do nothing about it is not humble; it is boasting of your modesty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do this all of the time. I am endeavoring to change it. If you notice
me boasting about my flaws, please point it out to me and tell me to
shut up. If I get annoyed by that, use the code word ‘Hufflepuff’ and
I’ll understand and fix that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Do not flinch from experiences that might destroy your beliefs. The thought you cannot think controls you more than thoughts you speak aloud. Submit yourself to ordeals and test yourself in fire. Relinquish the emotion which rests upon a mistaken belief, and seek to feel fully that emotion which fits the facts. If the iron approaches your face, and you believe it is hot, and it is cool, the Way opposes your fear. If the iron approaches your face, and you believe it is cool, and it is hot, the Way opposes your calm. Evaluate your beliefs first and then arrive at your emotions. Let yourself say: “If the iron is hot, I desire to believe it is hot, and if it is cool, I desire to believe it is cool.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My cross to bear is laziness. So:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If I am lazy, I desire to believe that I am lazy. If I am not lazy, I desire to belive that I am not lazy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When I am lazy, I desire to believe that I am lazy. When I am not lazy, I desire to belive that I am not lazy.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Simulating Language Codes</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-10/02-09-simulating-language-codes"/>
   <updated>2012-04-10T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-10/02-09-simulating-language-codes</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Today, I added all of the codes that were given to me in the Simulating
Language course at the University of Edinburgh to my &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/RichardLitt/CoLitt/tree/master/Simulating%20Language&quot;&gt;CoLitt
Github&lt;/a&gt;.
I took this course between January and March 2010, and it is still being
offered at Edinburgh - I talked for 45 minutes last night with a friend
of mine who is taking it. There are some modifications to the course -
more with neural networks, some stuff about priors that I don’t
remember, but it is essentially the same. In essence, the teachers hand
out lots of code, tell you to fiddle around with it, and that’s how you
learn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not sure I approve of this technique, which is one of the reasons I
loaded the code up. The main reason, of course, is that I am for opening
up notes wherever possible (I loaded my notes in, too). I think that the
more access you have, the more likely you’ll use that access, the more
you’ll learn. Back to the technique - this teaches you how to manipulate
code, but it doesn’t teach you how to code per se. Today I was asked a
question that a CS child could answer (I’d rather not embarass myself by
admitting what it was.) But because of the fact that I learned
haphazardly, I couldn’t answer. Had I taken a CS course at any point, I
would have been able to. I’ve still got a long way to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m not saying I disliked the course - I loved it, I recieved my highest
mark in it, I’m publishing my essay from it in a journal (admittedly, a
journal for undergrads), and because of that course I went on to do my
dissertation in that field, which lead me to go to Kyoto and to Germany.
But, I wish I had had access to the code more, that I had been taught
how to program and not how to ‘break something then fix it’. In any
event, I hope this is useful to someone out there.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Jazzy Bill</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-09/16-55-jazzy-bill"/>
   <updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-09/16-55-jazzy-bill</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;The past few days I’ve been massively hating on my old friend David Leon for introducing me to Harry Potter and the Methods of Rationality in the middle of a very stressful month. Now that I’ve read all 83 current chapters, I feel much more thankful to David for having done so - he also introduced me, incidentally, to Mark Knopfler, Gene Wolf, and The Rise and Rise of Michael Rimmer, so he can’t be all bad.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Get to the point: I’m reading more and more of &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesswrong.com&quot;&gt;Less Wrong&lt;/a&gt;. It’s a community blog devoted to refining the art of human rationality. If you didn’t know, I am horrified by my own ability to judge what to do correctly, and suspect that I actually turn away from my better judgement the majority of the time in case I have to change a course of action. In simpler terms, I am not only lazy, I am stupid, when it comes to mental processes. This is the sole reason I have not learned German while living in Germany, and it’s something this blog is supposed to help me work around, eventually (&lt;em&gt;now&lt;/em&gt;, my brain is screaming.) So, I very much like Less Wrong, because it’s all about fixing those inner voices and &lt;em&gt;getting things done&lt;/em&gt;. For instance, right now I should be writing an essay. That I’m writing this shows that I’m rationalising long term mental improvement over immediate necessity. This is a common excuse I use, and I’m looking forward to finding literature on the bias behind it. (&lt;em&gt;This&lt;/em&gt;, right there, is why I am glad I was up until 5am setting this blog up and populating it enough to use. I hadn’t been approaching that thought directly - writing is a very powerful means, for me, of realising what I actually think.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, onto Jazzy bill. I was reading &lt;a href=&quot;http://lesswrong.com/lw/31/what_do_we_mean_by_rationality/&quot;&gt;What do we mean by ‘Rationality’&lt;/a&gt;, and ran across this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Sometimes experimental psychologists uncover human reasoning that seems very strange - for example, someone rates the probability “Bill plays jazz” as less than the probability “Bill is an accountant who plays jazz”.  This seems like an odd judgment, since any particular jazz-playing accountant is obviously a jazz player.  But to what higher vantage point do we appeal in saying that the judgment is wrong?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Experimental psychologists use two gold standards: probability theory, and decision theory.  Since it is a universal law of probability theory that P(A) ≥ P(A &amp;amp; B), the judgment P(“Bill plays jazz”) &amp;lt; P(“Bill plays jazz” &amp;amp; “Bill is accountant”) is labeled incorrect.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;To keep it technical, you would say that this probability judgment is non-Bayesian.  Beliefs that conform to a coherent probability distribution, and decisions that maximize the probabilistic expectation of a coherent utility function, are called “Bayesian”.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I think that there might be a simple explanation for people saying this,
and it doesn’t have to do with probability or decision theory overmuch. It has to do with the semantic domain of the sentence, or the Grician implicature. I don’t know the actual words to use here, so I’m making them up as I go. That’s ok, this is a formulation blog, and this post is already too long.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Bill plays jazz” is pretty unambiguous, we can all agree. There’s an
entity, &lt;em&gt;Bill&lt;/em&gt;, such that he plays &lt;em&gt;jazz&lt;/em&gt;. (If you want, you can imagine
Clinton on his saxophone here - I am, and it’s rather amusing.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What &lt;em&gt;is&lt;/em&gt; ambiguous is “Bill is an accountant who plays jazz.” Not
because of the referent of &lt;em&gt;who&lt;/em&gt;, but because of the inability for the
written word to put the stress in the right place. Compare:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Bill&lt;/em&gt; is an accountant who plays jazz.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill is an &lt;em&gt;accountant&lt;/em&gt; who plays jazz.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Bill is an accountant, &lt;em&gt;who plays jazz.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“who plays &lt;em&gt;jazz&lt;/em&gt;” would also be acceptable in 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Logically, rationally, if you were to formulate each of these down into
a formula (as above) they would all come out as less probable than “Bill
plays jazz.” However, given the different readings, the mind can
construct worlds in which it is more plausible for 2 or 3 to occur
than 0 (or 1, which is pretty unambiguous too.) I don’t mean creating
a specific scenario where all accountants play jazz and Bill is normally
associated with reggae-only assassins, not accountants. I mean, rather,
that (bear with me) with the statement that Bill is an accountant, with a
relative clause attached about jazz appended on, one is less likely to
view the relative clause as implausible. I think that this might occur
because the mind is more likely to accept a fictional world as truth
when more information is supplied, and that the more information, the
less people suspect that the other objects may in themselves be less
plausible. I suspect there is some truth in this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’d be interested in feedback on this one.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>microbogging it down</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-09/02-00-microbogging-it-down"/>
   <updated>2012-04-09T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-09/02-00-microbogging-it-down</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;Decided I am not going to try to push wired stuff to this directly, at the moment. For one, I don’t know how to properly sequence os.system() in Python. For instance, what I would like is to do this:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;&lt;pre class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;code&gt;if (sys.argv[1] == &quot;bog&quot;):  
    import os  
    title = raw_input(&#39; title? &#39;)  
    os.system(&#39;cd ../richardlitt.github.com&#39;)  
    os.system(&#39;rake post title=&quot;&#39;+title+&#39;&quot;&#39;)  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;Sadly, that doesn’t actually work (wait - would a symbolic link work?). Neither does using a&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;. I’m really not sure why, but it is pretty annoying, because there are a lot of things I could do if that did work. Right now I am trying to figure out how to automate calls to a local installation of WordNet, so if you have any ideas, let me know.&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, instead of trying to fiddle with that for ages and pushing things here, and then becoming reliant on this site instead of just using the .csv database I am using at the moment (why .csv? Because I didn’t want to learn .sql when I started. That goes to show you how bad at planning us humans are.) Instead, I am going to use this as a microblogging site. More and more recently I realise I have these little burts of writing inspiration, scientific or not, that go nowhere, and I wish I had an easy way of just putting them down and publishing them without consigning them to the ‘Writings’ section of my HD, from which nothing ever returns. So, let’s try this.&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
=======
   <title>Settling in...</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/site/2012/04/08/test"/>
   <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/site/2012/04/08/test</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;Well, I think I might be getting some of the hang of it. I&amp;#8217;m not sure how to remove the tagline yet, but I&amp;#8217;ll get there eventually. I do like the way that YAML works, and using Markdown files instead of anything else. I do tend to the Spartan, though - I could use the Wordpress wysiwyg much easier than .md, but I approach .md with a better sense of mind because I feel like I should be able to do more with it. That&amp;#8217;s probably not actually the case. I suspect I prefer it for some prestige reason.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In any event, I&amp;#8217;m going to see if I can push to this directly. So, next up, set up a symbolic link, and a small python program - a shell program? - to allow me to edit the markdown file as soon as I rake it, and then to commit and push it as soon as that is over. Hypothetically, that&amp;#8217;ll mean a lot easier quick blogging than what I have at the moment, which is nothing. Wordpress is very heavy, twitter doesn&amp;#8217;t do enough, Faebook is the wrong audience, I don&amp;#8217;t use G+ for some reason (distractions? Wide margins? The multiplicity of colours?). But this should do nicely, if only I can manage it, retain my sanity, and always have the internet on me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That&amp;#8217;s all for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
>>>>>>> New
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Starting with Clojure</title>
<<<<<<< ab5e6c99ebf65ed6cd1cf3f50b0789a835f1269f
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-08/starting-with-clojure"/>
   <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/2012-04-08/starting-with-clojure</id>
   <content type="html">
&lt;p&gt;
Ok, so, once again, I&#39;m new to Clojure. Not only that, I am new to
computational linguistics, and to coding in general. I have some background
messing around with Python - I&#39;ve implemented a lot of programs, some of them
non-trivial (meaning thousands of lines of poor code long). My undergraduate
was in Linguistics, where when I once asked a professor if I should apply to a
degree in computational linguistics, I found the shocked and almost appaled
answer &quot;I didn&#39;t know you leant that way.&quot; But, half a year, lots of Python and
even some attempts at Java, Ruby, Javascript, Luna, and who knows what else
later, here I am.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you haven&#39;t read them yet, Paul Graham&#39;s essays on what it means to use
Lisp are excellent. Lisp is arguably the most powerful language. It is based on
math, and math, as we all know, doesn&#39;t age. (What this means, I have yet to
really understand, but this is a learning process over here, so help me out.)
Clojure is a new dialect of Lisp. Ok, I can get all that. So, what&#39;s different
about clojure besides the pretty rainbow brackets, and an annoyingly long
process of setting it up (Clojure, clojars, leiningen, VimClojure with SLIME -
you name it, I&#39;ve fought it, all the way down to things like Mercurial.)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well, right off of the bat, the syntax is pretty nifty. Take &lt;code&gt;(+ 3 5
5)&lt;/code&gt; -
that&#39;s multiple arguments, going fine. The syntax, of course, doesn&#39;t matter so
much, but it&#39;s easy to appreciate how much easier this is than python&#39;s
&lt;code&gt;3 + 5 + 5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some more thoughts that should be sorted:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something about brackets being useful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anonymous functions is nice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running on the JVM - what does this really mean? Library support? Isn&#39;t
    making a library set then kind of perpendicular to the point of using Clojure?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
=======
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/languages/2012/04/08/starting-with-clojure"/>
   <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/languages/2012/04/08/starting-with-clojure</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;
Ok, so, once again, I'm new to Clojure. Not only that, I am new to
computational linguistics, and to coding in general. I have some background
messing around with Python - I've implemented a lot of programs, some of them
non-trivial (meaning thousands of lines of poor code long). My undergraduate
was in Linguistics, where when I once asked a professor if I should apply to a
degree in computational linguistics, I found the shocked and almost appaled
answer &quot;I didn't know you leant that way.&quot; But, half a year, lots of Python and
even some attempts at Java, Ruby, Javascript, Luna, and who knows what else
later, here I am.
&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you haven't read them yet, Paul Graham's essays on what it means to use
Lisp are excellent. Lisp is arguably the most powerful language. It is based on
math, and math, as we all know, doesn't age. (What this means, I have yet to
really understand, but this is a learning process over here, so help me out.)
Clojure is a new dialect of Lisp. Ok, I can get all that. So, what's different
about clojure besides the pretty rainbow brackets, and an annoyingly long
process of setting it up (Clojure, clojars, leiningen, VimClojure with SLIME -
you name it, I've fought it, all the way down to things like Mercurial.)&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Well, right off of the bat, the syntax is pretty nifty. Take &lt;code&gt;(+ 3 5
5)&lt;/code&gt; -
that's multiple arguments, going fine. The syntax, of course, doesn't matter so
much, but it's easy to appreciate how much easier this is than python's
&lt;code&gt;3 + 5 + 5&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some more thoughts that should be sorted:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Something about brackets being useful&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Anonymous functions is nice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Running on the JVM - what does this really mean? Library support? Isn't
    making a library set then kind of perpendicular to the point of using Clojure?&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>installed jb</title>
   <link href="http://richardlitt.github.com/site/2012/04/08/hello-world"/>
   <updated>2012-04-08T00:00:00+02:00</updated>
   <id>http://richardlitt.github.com/site/2012/04/08/hello-world</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;#8217;ve installed it now. Now I just need to figure out how to automatically add things to the post section, and I&amp;#8217;ll be one step closer to automatic blogging.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
 </entry>
 
 
</feed>
>>>>>>> New
